<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>online on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/online/</link>
    <description>Recent content in online on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Asteroids</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/active-asteroids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/active-asteroids/</guid>
      <description>Active Asteroids View the project here.
Overview Active Asteroids &amp;ndash; asteroids with comet-like activity such as tails &amp;ndash; are poorly understood in part because so few of these objects have been found. At the time of this project launch, fewer than 30 active asteroids have been found since 1949. Finding more active asteroids will enable scientists to study these enigmatic objects as a population. The implications for science and engineering are far-reaching, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Health</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</guid>
      <description>Addressing Health View the project here.
Overview Why did the UK&amp;rsquo;s Post Office employees in the nineteenth century retire from work? Some reached retirement age but many had to end their careers early because of ill health. Be a part of this Wellcome-funded project to find out what Post Office workers&#39; lives tell us about the history of health and wellbeing in the Victorian period. Transcribe the records of their career histories from images of documents held at the Postal Museum, London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents of Enslavement</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/agents-of-enslavement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/agents-of-enslavement/</guid>
      <description>Agents of Enslavement View the project here.
Overview Agents of Enslavement? is a research project, which seeks to explore the ways in which colonial newspapers in the Caribbean facilitated and challenged the practice of slavery.
It also seeks to identify the networks and voices of enslaved people hidden within these newspapers.
These crowdsourcing tasks are integral to both these aims as your help will create new datasets for analysis.
One of the goals of this project is to create a database of enslaved people identified within these newspapers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI4Mars</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ai4mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ai4mars/</guid>
      <description>AI4Mars View the project here.
Overview We need YOUR help to make future Mars rovers safer!
By participating in this project, you will help improve the rovers’ ability to identify different, sometimes dangerous terrain - an essential skill for autonomous exploration!
You’ll be using your superior cognitive and artistic abilities to label images from the Curiosity Rover, collectively creating the first open-source navigation-classification dataset of the Red Planet. It will be used - like the cityscapes dataset - by teams to train rovers to understand Martian environments, laying the way for future missions to unlock the secrets of our nearest neighbor!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancestry® World Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ancestry-world-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ancestry-world-archives/</guid>
      <description>Ancestry® World Archives View the project here.
Overview The Ancestry® World Archives Project is volunteers from around the world creating searchable record indexes from digitized records. We gather historical records and scan them into our system. You look at the records and type out what you see (so that the facts in the records become searchable). The index you create is added to Ancestry’s free collections and is accessible to anyone who wants to search it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurorasaurus</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</guid>
      <description>Aurorasaurus View the project here.
Overview Aurorasaurus is the first and only citizen science initiative that tracks auroras around the world via reports on our website and social media. All aurora-related tweets and reports are placed on the Aurorasaurus.org map. We then ask people to log in and verify the tweets or reports. Each verified report serves as a valuable data point for scientists to analyze and incorporate into space weather models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</guid>
      <description>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count View the project here.
Overview Every year, thousands of seals and sea lions haul out on Año Nuevo Island to give birth, molt, and rest. The secluded shores of the island make a perfect spot for northern elephant seal and California sea lion mothers to give birth and nurse their pups. Researchers at the University of California, Santa Cruz are interested in tracking the number of animals that haul out onto the island&amp;rsquo;s beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents View the project here.
Overview Help turn our collection of 17th-19th century handwritten documents relating to Maine&amp;rsquo;s land history into text that may be more easily read, keyword searchable, and accessed by students, teachers, and historians.
Maine Historical Society received a grant in the summer of 2020 from the National Endowment for the Humanities to fully digitized three significant land collections covering 1625-1893. In addition to digitization, Maine Historical is making an effort to transcribe these collections for easier access to their historic content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bursts from Space</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/bursts-from-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/bursts-from-space/</guid>
      <description>Bursts from Space View the project here.
Overview Fast Radio Bursts are massive bursts of energy we see from across half the universe. We call them Fast Radio Bursts because that&amp;rsquo;s what we see - a brief millisecond &amp;lsquo;burst&amp;rsquo; of energy in radio waves.
What are they? We don&amp;rsquo;t know! But every burst we find tells us a little more about what&amp;rsquo;s happening. We need to find these bursts!
Sounds easy right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buzzy Bee - African Canopy Pollinators</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/buzzy-bee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/buzzy-bee/</guid>
      <description>Buzzy Bee - African Canopy Pollinators View the project here.
Overview Help us identify insect pollinators of large African timber trees!
In order to define sustainable exploitation practices, it is necessary to understand regeneration cycles of timber tree species. The purpose of this research is to describe the relationship between pollen dispersal distances, floral traits, and pollinators of several timber species, as well as document the size and composition of pollinators communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</guid>
      <description>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field View the project here.
Overview The British Library wildlife and environmental sounds archive was established in 1969 by the ornithologist Patrick Seller and the BBC radio producer Jeffrey Boswell, with the endeavour to create a national collection that can document, preserve and share the sounds of nature for future generations to study and enjoy. Since then we have amassed over 6.5 million recordings and are now one of the most comprehensive collections in the world, used by scientists and amateur naturalists alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimp and See</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</guid>
      <description>Chimp and See View the project here.
Overview Studies of human evolution often focus on the fossils and artifacts left by our early ancestors. However, we can also make inferences about human origins by studying our closest living relatives: chimpanzees, the great apes that live across equatorial Africa. Because humans and chimps are so closely related, patterns in chimpanzee behavior may tell us quite a bit about how the earliest hominids lived and evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Endo</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Endo View the project here.
Overview In order to study a disease, we need to know what it looks like. When it comes to endometriosis, there are many different ways in which the disease can present itself in patients. There is a disconnect between how doctors think about the disease and what patients experience on a daily basis. Bridging this gap is critical to further research on endometriosis. Citizen Endo will use a series of studies to better understand the disease from the perspective of patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corresponding with Quakers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/corresponding-with-quakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/corresponding-with-quakers/</guid>
      <description>Corresponding with Quakers View the project here.
Overview The Quakers of Ballitore, Ireland, were a small group, but they have fascinating links to many major political issues of the period: abolitionism, women&amp;rsquo;s rights, religious tensions, global migration, and the American and French Revolutions.
Corresponding with Quakers is an ongoing, collaborative research project investigating the Ballitore Collection held at UCSB Library’s Special Research Collections. The Ballitore Collection features more than 2,500 documents related to the Irish Quaker community of Ballitore, Ireland, including letters, journals, notebooks, and dream accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Muon Images</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmic-muon-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmic-muon-images/</guid>
      <description>Cosmic Muon Images View the project here.
Overview We place muon detectors all around the globe and we study the inner structure of massive objects from volcanoes to ancient tombs and from underground tunnels to blast furnaces.
Using muon tomography we can probe the internal structure of massive objects, like volcanoes, with particles from stars and galaxies far, far away. Help us identify these particles inside our detectors!
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological jellyfish</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmological-jellyfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmological-jellyfish/</guid>
      <description>Cosmological jellyfish View the project here.
Overview We are a group of researchers at the Max Planck Institute of Astronomy using simulations of the Universe to study the various ways in which galaxies in the Universe evolve, both through their own internal processes, and under the influence of their environment.
Galaxies in the Universe can come in many forms and shapes.
Some of them can show very asymmetric distributions, with long tails of material that depart from their main body made of stars and cosmic gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Energy Explorers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dark-energy-explorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dark-energy-explorers/</guid>
      <description>Dark Energy Explorers View the project here.
Overview The Hobby-Eberly Dark Energy Experiment (HETDEX) is designed to find over one million galaxies that are 9 billion to 11 billion light-years away, yielding the largest map of the universe ever produced. The map will allow HETDEX astronomers to measure how fast the universe was expanding at different times in its history. Changes in the expansion rate will reveal the role of dark energy at different epochs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davy Notebooks Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>Davy Notebooks Project View the project here.
Overview Help us to transcribe the manuscript notebooks of Sir Humphry Davy – one of the most significant and famous figures in the scientific and literary culture of early nineteenth-century Britain, Europe, and America.
Davy’s scientific accomplishments include: conducting pioneering research into the physiological effects of nitrous oxide (often called ‘laughing gas’); isolating seven chemical elements (magnesium, calcium, potassium, sodium, strontium, barium, and boron) and establishing the elemental status of chlorine and iodine; inventing a miners’ safety lamp; developing the electrochemical protection of the copper sheeting of Royal Navy vessels; conserving the Herculaneum papyri; and writing an influential text on agricultural chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental Disease Detection</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dental-disease-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dental-disease-detection/</guid>
      <description>Dental Disease Detection View the project here.
Overview Dental radiography is an essential tool for diagnostics of dental diseases. Analysis of radiographs is time-consuming and often error-prone due to a high variety of dental structures, positioning/orientation errors, and the substantial amount of radiographs that need to be analysed. An automatic solution for flagging abnormalities in dental radiographs is needed to improve detection accuracy and to reduce the cost of misdiagnosis. This project aims to use AI to bridge this gap to find and validate such a solution, by building a software prototype enabling computers to recognise normal anatomical structures and differentiate from subtle abnormalities in radiographs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disk Detective</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/disk-detective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/disk-detective/</guid>
      <description>Disk Detective View the project here.
Overview NASA&amp;rsquo;s WISE mission is surveying the whole sky at infrared wavelengths. Here at Disk Detective, you&amp;rsquo;ll examine data from WISE and other surveys to search for dusty debris disks similar to our asteroid belt, and gas-rich primordial disks, the birthplaces of planets.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY History</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</guid>
      <description>DIY History View the project here.
Overview DIY History lets you do it yourself to help make historic artifacts easier to use. Our digital library holds hundreds of thousands of items—much more than library staff could ever catalog alone, so we&amp;rsquo;re appealing to the public to help out by attaching text in the form of transcriptions, tags, and comments. Through &amp;ldquo;crowdsourcing,&amp;rdquo; or engaging volunteers to contribute effort toward large-scale goals, these mass quantities of digitized artifacts become searchable, allowing researchers to quickly seek out specific information, and general users to browse and enjoy the materials more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drones for Ducks</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/drones-for-ducks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/drones-for-ducks/</guid>
      <description>Drones for Ducks View the project here.
Overview Migrating birds like ducks, geese, and cranes are important parts of many ecosystems along their seasonal travel routes. To ensure there are enough resources to go around, managers of public lands in the Southwestern United States conduct waterfowl surveys to know how many birds to expect over winter. Traditional methods of counting birds out in the field present a lot of challenges and may not be very precise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etch A Cell - ER</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/etch-a-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/etch-a-cell/</guid>
      <description>Etch A Cell - ER View the project here.
Overview Help us study one of the biggest structures found in your cells - the Endoplasmic Reticulum.
In Etch A Cell - ER we need you to help us study the Endoplasmic Reticulum (ER) of a cell. The ER is often one of the biggest structures (organelles) in the cell, and is involved in lots of important cellular processes including the production and transport of new proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eterna</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eterna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eterna/</guid>
      <description>Eterna View the project here.
Overview Design molecular medicines by solving puzzles!
Eterna is a game that allows players to design RNAs by solving puzzles. Each puzzle represents a target RNA shape or a set of design requirements. Players design the pattern of bases they think will best meet the requirements. Scientists then create the molecules the players have designed and test them in the lab. The lab results are returned to the players, who can use them to improve their designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Name Counts</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/every-name-counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/every-name-counts/</guid>
      <description>Every Name Counts View the project here.
Overview With the initiative #everynamecounts, the Arolsen Archives aim to establish a digital memorial to the people persecuted by the Nazis. Future generations should be able to remember the names and identities of the victims and put faces to history.
Thousands of volunteers are contributing to this first major digital memorial, which will enable people all over the world to access and search the data themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyewire</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</guid>
      <description>Eyewire View the project here.
Overview Eyewire is a game to map the brain. Anyone can play and you need no scientific background. Hundreds of thousands of people from around the world already do. Together we are mapping the 3D structure of neurons and advancing our quest to understand ourselves.
By joining Eyewire, you can help map the connectome, starting with connections between retinal neurons. Eyewire gameplay advances neuroscience by helping researchers discover how neurons connect and network to process information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix It&#43; Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</guid>
      <description>Fix It+ Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting View the project here.
Overview Help the American Archive of Public Broadcasting fix computer-generated transcripts from thousands of historic public broadcasting programs from across the country.
We need you to help ensure that public media remains accessible—not just today&amp;rsquo;s broadcasts, but the archive all the way back to the beginning.
FIX IT+ users can correct transcripts for any of the historic programs available in the AAPB&amp;rsquo;s Online Reading Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating Forests</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/floating-forests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/floating-forests/</guid>
      <description>Floating Forests View the project here.
Overview Welcome to Floating Forests, where you can help us uncover the history of Giant Kelp forests around the globe. Most life on the seafloor can only be sampled by SCUBA divers or dredging up samples from the deep. This kind of data requires a ton of (really fun) effort to collect, but it means we’re limited to places we can get to! Given the worldwide distribution of kelp, we need your help to track it across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folding@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Install our software to become a citizen scientist and contribute your compute power to help fight global health threats like COVID19, Alzheimer’s Disease, and cancer!
Folding@Home began in October 2000 in the lab of Dr. Vijay Pande at Stanford University. Since 2019, the project has been in the hands of Dr. Gregory Bowman, a former Pande Lab graduate student. In addition to the numerous scientists who have worked on the project over the years, F@h has been supported by thousands of dedicated volunteers who have enabled outstanding scientific research and computational achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foldit</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/foldit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/foldit/</guid>
      <description>Foldit View the project here.
Overview Foldit is a revolutionary crowdsourcing computer game enabling you to contribute to important scientific research.
Knowing the structure of a protein is key to understanding how it works and to targeting it with drugs. A small protein can consist of 100 amino acids, while some human proteins can be huge (1000 amino acids). The number of different ways even a small protein can fold is astronomical because there are so many degrees of freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom on the Move</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview We need your help to turn our collection of handwritten correspondence between anti-slavery activists in the 19th century into texts that can be more easily read and researched by students, teachers, historians, and big data applications.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frog Find</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frog-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frog-find/</guid>
      <description>Frog Find View the project here.
Overview Help us find threatened frogs in NSW National Parks. Understanding where they live helps us improve their chance of survival in the future.
Frogs need your help! Following bushfires, floods and a host of other threats including water pollution and disease, our frogs really have their back against the wall.
Frog Find uses frog sounds recorded from streams, ponds and wetlands to work out who is calling where.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FrogSong</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frogsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frogsong/</guid>
      <description>FrogSong View the project here.
Overview With your help, researchers at James Cook University and Monash University aim to develop automated techniques to identify frog calls in very long audio recordings. This will allow us to understand the environmental drivers of frog chorusing, detect changes in frog communities through time, determine how species partition the acoustic space, and much more!
This project contains audio recordings collected by the Australian Acoustic Observatory at sites around Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GWitchHunters</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/gwitchhunters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/gwitchhunters/</guid>
      <description>GWitchHunters View the project here.
Overview GWITCHHUNTERS aims at improving the performance of current Gravitational Wave detectors in the experimental study of the Universe. Such instruments have reached extraordinary sensitivities to accomplish this task, but they are also very delicate and prone to spurious disturbances of non-astrophysical origin. Our goal is to better understand their disturbances and find new solutions to them.
We are a team of researchers devoted to this very challenging task, involving state of the art technologies and analysis methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iberian Camera Trap Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/iberian-camera-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/iberian-camera-trap/</guid>
      <description>Iberian Camera Trap Project View the project here.
Overview Wildlife monitoring is often based on outdated protocols. However, advances in technology have paved the way for optimizing data collection and profusing cutting-edge analytical methods. Our cameras are placed in one of the most important protected areas in Europe, the Parque Nacional de Doñana (South Spain). Your classifications will serve to train an artificial intelligence algorithm to do the same with an exorbitant amount of images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Wild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</guid>
      <description>Instant Wild View the project here.
Overview ZSL’s Instant Wild empowers you to take part in vital conservation work, bringing you LIVE images and videos from amazing locations all around the world. By identifying the animals in each image, you are contributing to conservation and making a positive impact on the future for wildlife.
Available both as a smartphone app and online at instantwild.zsl.org, Instant Wild mobilises people power to scale up important animal monitoring work, which helps scientists to protect wildlife and secure a richer biodiversity for all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iWitness Pollution Map</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/iwitness-pollution-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/iwitness-pollution-map/</guid>
      <description>iWitness Pollution Map View the project here.
Overview The iWitness Pollution map is a tool that communities can use to document pollution in their neighborhoods. By calling or texting to (504) 272 – 7645 (27 27 OIL), residents can crowdsource pollution and tell the world about the bad smells, flares and noise from the neighboring petrochemical plant.
We first deployed the map in 2010 in the days after the BP Disaster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LabintheWild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</guid>
      <description>LabintheWild View the project here.
Overview LabintheWild tests your abilities and preferences. At the end of each experiment, you will see a page with your personalized feedback, which lets you compare yourself and your performance to other people around the world.
By participating, you contribute to research on people&amp;rsquo;s similarities and differences and help improve users&#39; experience when interacting with technology. We believe that research should be done in collaboration with people—people like you from all over the world who are interested in learning about themselves and helping research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library of Congress: By the People</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</guid>
      <description>Library of Congress: By the People View the project here.
Overview Help transcribe Library of Congress documents. Volunteers create and review transcriptions to improve search, access, and discovery of these pages from history.
By the People invites you to transcribe, review, and tag digitized pages from the Library’s collections. Everyone is welcome to take part! Volunteer-created transcriptions improve search, readability, and access to handwritten and typed documents for everyone, including people who are not fully sighted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macdonald Dictionary</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/macdonald-dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/macdonald-dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Macdonald Dictionary View the project here.
Overview George Ranald Macdonald (1891 - 1967) was a farmer and local historian in Canterbury, New Zealand. After retiring he began volunteering at Canterbury Museum. When Museum visitors mentioned there was a need for a biographical dictionary of colonial personalities to help with research, Macdonald volunteered for the project.
Compiled by Macdonald between 1952 and 1964, and comprised of over 12000 index cards with biographical information on over 22000 people, the dictionary took about 12 years to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAPPPD (Penguins!)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/mapping-penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/mapping-penguins/</guid>
      <description>Mapping Application for Penguin Populations and Projected Dynamics (MAPPPD) View the project here.
Overview Help us locate new colonies by exploring high resolution Google earth imagery. Over the last several years, penguin biologists have been working hard to find all the penguin colonies in Antarctica using satellite imagery. However, the massive expanse of the continent and the challenges of finding each last penguin colony leave many likely undiscovered. This is where you can help!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the ANZACs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/measuring-anzacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/measuring-anzacs/</guid>
      <description>Measuring the ANZACs View the project here.
Overview The Measuring the ANZACs project brings together an international team of researchers, community connections around New Zealand’s military history from the Auckland War Memorial Museum, and the power of the Zooniverse community to explore, analyze, and digitize original World War I personnel files from Archives New Zealand.
Data gathered from Measuring the ANZACs will be used for three main purposes:
 To create a complete and rich index of persons who served in the New Zealand military in World War I and the South African War (also called the Second Boer War).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/m-a-e-terrae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/m-a-e-terrae/</guid>
      <description>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae View the project here.
Overview Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae (MET - Meteorology of the End of the World) aims to recover weather and oceanic data record in Argentina since at least the beginning of the XIXth Century. The first currently known records date back to 1801. Other than the Oficina Meteorológica Argentina, later Servicio Meteorológico Nacional, many public and private organizations have registered weather data. Argentine Navy ships, lighthouses, railway stations, &amp;ldquo;estancias&amp;rdquo; are among many data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nest Quest Go: Mourning Doves</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nqg-mourning-doves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nqg-mourning-doves/</guid>
      <description>Nest Quest Go: Mourning Doves View the project here.
Overview Join the Cornell Lab of Ornithology&amp;rsquo;s Citizen-Science Project, NestWatch, in understanding the historical nesting patterns of Mourning Doves. In North America, Mourning Doves are the most abundant and widespread game bird.
While they are hunted in North America, these nest-record cards demonstrate a different kind of hunting: the quest for data!
These nest record cards are a subset of a larger collection of more than 300,000 nest records that NestWatch is working on digitizing and transcribing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nest Quest Go: Sparrows</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nest-quest-go-sparrows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nest-quest-go-sparrows/</guid>
      <description>Nest Quest Go: Sparrows View the project here.
Overview Join the Cornell Lab of Ornithology&amp;rsquo;s Citizen-Science Project, NestWatch in understanding the historical nesting patterns of various sparrows, including Black-throated Sparrow, Vesper Sparrow, Savannah Sparrow, Chipping Sparrow, Song Sparrow, Field Sparrow, Lark Sparrow, Eastern Towhee and many more! Generally, for most types of sparrows, the female searches for a nest location and builds her nest with little to no help from the male, who often guards the nesting territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Particle Search at CERN</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/new-particle-search-cern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/new-particle-search-cern/</guid>
      <description>New Particle Search at CERN View the project here.
Overview You have the opportunity to contribute to the search for undiscovered particles, which are produced from the collisions of high-energy protons at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), the world’s most powerful particle accelerator.
While the Higgs boson was discovered in 2012, after about 40 years of intense experimental and theoretical research, and was the last missing component of our present model of particle physics, there are still many unanswered questions and even more theories that try to answer them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Public Library: What&#39;s on the menu?</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</guid>
      <description>New York Public Library: What&amp;rsquo;s on the menu? View the project here.
Overview Help The New York Public Library improve a unique collection!
We’re transcribing our historical restaurant menus, dish by dish, so that they can be searched by what people were eating back in the day. It’s a big job so we need your help!
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</guid>
      <description>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes View the project here.
Overview We are running ‘Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes’ to analyse images of lymph nodes from breast cancer patients. This project will generate data that will be used to help improve our AI model performance. We are trying to find the germinal centres, the light pink circles in lymph nodes. When the immune system spot something foreign, new immune cells were produced in germinal centres of lymph nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - CalBug</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-calbug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-calbug/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - CalBug View the project here.
Overview Natural history collections house over a billion insect specimens worldwide collected over several centuries. Specimen labels encode data denoting species, location, and date captured and are used to study biogeographic patterns, spread of invasive species, and responses to land use, climate, and other environmental changes. However, access to data is impractical for most of the research community.
Because of enormous collection sizes, entomology has lagged behind other disciplines in digitizing collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&#39;s Flowers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&amp;rsquo;s Flowers View the project here.
Overview The California Phenology Network was originally an NSF-funded collaboration of 22 California herbaria that aimed to image 904,200 herbarium specimens by 2022. In July 2020, this network was expanded by a partner-to-existing-network grant to include six additional institutions and over 148,000 more specimens, for a total of over one million specimens. We will also georeference and transcribe over 320,000 specimens, making their data publicly available on our data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Flora of Texas and Oklahoma</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-tx-and-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-tx-and-ok/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Flora of Texas and Oklahoma View the project here.
Overview Naturalists and Scientists have been exploring Nature for centuries, collecting a massive amount of specimens over the course of many lifetimes. While this meticulous work has resulted in more than 3 million botanical specimens being housed in herbaria across Texas and Oklahoma, only a small fraction of this treasure is digitally accessible for observation, or for inclusion in scientific studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - Herbarium</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-herbarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-herbarium/</guid>
      <description>Notes From Nature - Herbarium View the project here.
Overview Welcome to the Herbarium Project on Notes from Nature. We will be hosting lots of great expeditions related to plants on this Project from a variety of institutions.
For the time being these will be mostly specimens related to the from the NitFix project.
The NitFix project received funding from the U.S. Department of Energy to develop mechanisms to engineer bioenergy crops so that these plants can fix nitrogen via root nodule symbioses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity View the project here.
Overview Digitizing data of southeast United States species allows comparisons of geographic distributions and niche specificity between endemic vascular plant species and non-endemics – essential to characterize and manage a significant component of this nation’s biodiversity imperiled by the effects of climate change, the loss of native habitat to anthropogenic uses, and biotic invasions.
Researchers can utilize herbarium specimen data to model current and future distributions of rare and endemic species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Terrestrial Parasite Tracker</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-terrestrial-parasite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-terrestrial-parasite/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Terrestrial Parasite Tracker View the project here.
Overview Parasitic arthropods inflict an enormous burden on human society; they afflict human health and the animals on which we depend. The negative effects of parasitic arthropods are exacerbated by current climate and ecosystem change. Fleas that vectored the pathogen causing bubonic plague wreaked havoc on historic human populations. Mosquitos continue to vector pathogens responsible for malaria and dengue, and ticks vector the bacteria responsible for Lyme disease; these arthropod borne pathogens infect and kill millions of people each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants View the project here.
Overview WeDigFLPlants is a collaboration between professional research botanists, amateur naturalists, gardeners, educators, and citizen scientists to build the most complete picture possible of plant distribution and diversity in Florida over the past 200 years. The data for this historical baseline come from archived plant specimens curated by the world&amp;rsquo;s 3,000 herbaria. Each of these specimens includes a label that answers the who, what, when, and where of the collecting event that produced it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OceanEYEs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/oceaneyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/oceaneyes/</guid>
      <description>OceanEYEs View the project here.
Overview NOAA scientists need your help to count fish and improve data used in management of the Hawaiʻi “Deep 7” bottomfish fishery! NOAA&amp;rsquo;s Pacific Islands Fisheries Science Center deploys stereo-camera systems on the seafloor to help monitor populations of deep-water snappers and groupers. The local commercial fishery in Hawaiʻi targets these fish primarily. Each camera can record tens of thousands of images! Human observers annotate the images to count and measure each species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offal Wildlife Watching</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/offal-ww/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/offal-ww/</guid>
      <description>Offal Wildlife Watching View the project here.
Overview Who Eats your Guts? Help us better understand scavenging of deer gut piles provided by hunters across Minnesota. IMPORTANT: IMAGES SHOW ANIMALS FEEDING ON THE REMAINS OF DEER
The purpose of this research is to better understand what and when species use deer gut piles provided by hunters across Minnesota. Minnesota offers a unique opportunity to look at this across four different biomes and a major metropolitan area, different hunting methods (rifle, archery, and shotgun), and different scavenger assemblages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - Naval Rendezvous</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-naval-rendezvous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-naval-rendezvous/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - Naval Rendezvous View the project here.
Overview This project seeks volunteers to help transcribe sea ice and weather observations from the logbooks of military vessels that sailed Arctic seas in the 19th and 20th century. This information is used to improve climate and sea ice data sets used by scientists every day.
To learn how to participate in this project, visit the Old Weather forum here.
In this project we use customized LibreOffice spreadsheets to guide the collection and organization of information extracted from the logbooks posted online, as in the example below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - Shipping Office</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-shipping-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-shipping-office/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - Shipping Office View the project here.
Overview This project seeks volunteers to help transcribe sea ice and weather observations from the logbooks of whaling ships that sailed Arctic seas from 1849 to 1912. This information is used to improve climate and sea ice data sets used by scientists every day.
To learn how to participate in this project, visit the Old Weather forum here.
In this project we use Microsoft Excel to guide the collection and organization of information extracted from the logbooks posted online, as in the example below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - WW2</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - WW2 View the project here.
Overview Help recover hidden weather data collected by the U.S. Navy during World War II!
The purpose of this project is to recover hidden marine weather data recorded in U.S. Navy ships&#39; logbooks during World War II. Like all Old Weather projects, these data will be used to drive sophisticated computer models that help us understand weather and climate in extraordinary detail. But there is another goal that is just as vital - to uncover the source of a mysterious distortion in the Navy temperature data collected during the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers of the War Department</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</guid>
      <description>Papers of the War Department View the project here.
Overview The War Department office was established in 1790. It burned in 1800.
For decades historians believed that its files, and the window they provide into the early federal government, had been lost forever. This collection unites copies of the lost files in a digital archive that reconstitutes this invaluable historical resource. Our community of transcribers are working to create full text transcriptions of every possible document in the collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Hunters NGTS</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-ngts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-ngts/</guid>
      <description>Planet Hunters NGTS View the project here.
Overview The Next-Generation Transit Survey have been searching for transiting exoplanets around the brightest stars in the sky. We need your help sifting through the observations flagged by the computers to search for hidden worlds that might have been missed in the NGTS team&amp;rsquo;s review. Most of the planets in the dataset have likely been found already, but you just might be the first to find a new exoplanet not known before!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Hunters TESS</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-tess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-tess/</guid>
      <description>Planet Hunters TESS View the project here.
Overview The recently launched Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) is providing us with a huge amount of data that lets us look for planets outside of our own Solar System, including planets that could support life. With your help, we are going to find planets that will help us understand how these extrasolar systems form and evolve over time. The results may even bring us closer to answering the question that we all want to answer: Are we alone in the Universe?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Patrol</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-patrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-patrol/</guid>
      <description>Planet Patrol View the project here.
Overview NASA’s Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission will take pictures of more than a million stars to search for planets orbiting them, called &amp;ldquo;transiting exoplanets&amp;rdquo;. We expect this mission will see thousands of these transiting exoplanets when they pass in front of nearby stars and periodically block some of the starlight.
But sometimes when a star dims like that, it&amp;rsquo;s not because of a planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Origins</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</guid>
      <description>Plastic Origins View the project here.
Overview Plastic Origins is a project initiated by the not-for-profit Surfrider Foundation Europe in search of solutions to address the source of ocean pollution. Supported by citizens, associations, scientists, and socially responsible companies, the Plastic Origins project aims to map plastic pollution in European rivers by applying participatory science and Artificial Intelligence technology. This mapping data helps to identify areas of high impact, gain a deeper understanding of the problem on the field, and measure the evolution of pollution over time as well as to raise awareness among political decision-makers on the local, national, and European levels and urge them to act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prickly Pear Project Kenya</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/prickly-pear-project-kenya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/prickly-pear-project-kenya/</guid>
      <description>Prickly Pear Project Kenya View the project here.
Overview Prickly pear cacti (Opuntia sp.) are one of the worst invasive plants in East Africa. We are a team of researchers from Durham University (UK) and Mpala Research Centre (Kenya) using camera traps to understand how Opuntia affects the habitat use of medium to large mammal species. This research has important implications for human-wildlife conflict and the future spread of the cactus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Four</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</guid>
      <description>Project Four View the project here.
Overview Welcome to Planet Four, a citizen science project designed to help planetary scientists identify and measure features on the surface of Mars&amp;hellip; the likes of which don’t exist on Earth. All of the images on this site depict the south polar region, where dark seasonal fans and blotches appear during the Spring. By mapping these features in images from the HiRISE camera, the highest resolution camera ever sent to a planet, we can explore the Martian climate and how it changes over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Unlock the past! Transcribe letters and diaries to help with historical research.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/galaxy-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/galaxy-zoo/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here (for desktop users) and its mobile version (for Android and iPhone) here.
Overview To understand how galaxies formed we need your help to classify them according to their shapes. If you&amp;rsquo;re quick, you may even be the first person to see the galaxies you&amp;rsquo;re asked to classify.
Welcome to Galaxy Zoo&amp;rsquo;s latest incarnation. For more than a decade, we&amp;rsquo;ve asked volunteers to help us explore galaxies near and far, sampling a fraction of the roughly one hundred billion that are scattered throughout the observable Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project RattleCam</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rattlecam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rattlecam/</guid>
      <description>Project RattleCam View the project here.
Overview This project was conceived in 2020 when Dr. Scott Boback of Dickinson College and Dr. Emily Taylor of the California Polytechnic State University decided to design a Zooniverse project for help analyzing game camera images they&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting from prairie rattlesnake rookeries in a remote area of Colorado. Rattlesnake rookeries are areas where females come together to give birth and care for their young.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Research on the Net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</guid>
      <description>Psychological Research on the Net View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
On this website you will find links to known experiments on the internet that are psychologically related. They are organized by general topic area with the topic areas listed chronologically with the most recently added at the top.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Flu</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</guid>
      <description>Quantified Flu View the project here.
Overview The question we want to answer is: Can the various physiological parameters tracked by our wearables help to predict when we’re getting sick? With the COVID-19 pandemic influencing all of our lives right now, this question seems more timely than ever. But it&amp;rsquo;s not only the pandemic, this question equally applies to the flu and the common cold!
There is some preliminary data which shows that the data from wearables (like resting heart rate and sleep quality) might be predictive of coming down with a cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio Galaxy Zoo: LOFAR</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-galaxy-zoo-lofar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-galaxy-zoo-lofar/</guid>
      <description>Radio Galaxy Zoo: LOFAR View the project here.
Overview Help astronomers locate and identify supermassive black holes and starforming galaxies!
The LOFAR project offers us an unprecedented view of what our skies look like at radio wavelengths. Never before have we been able to map such a large part of the radio sky at such high sensitivity. This allows scientists all over the world to answer many questions on the evolution of galaxies and the supermassive black holes that they harbour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio JOVE</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-jove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-jove/</guid>
      <description>Radio JOVE View the project here.
Overview Radio JOVE students and amateur scientists from around the world observe and analyze natural radio emissions of Jupiter, the Sun, and our galaxy building their own radio telescope from an easy to build kit or using remote radio telescopes through the Internet.
 Build and use your own Decametric Radio Telescope Share your observations with other project members Teachers, See Our Lesson Ideas and other Educational Materials  There is much more to astronomy than what can be learned by peering at the skies through an optical telescope!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan White Letters</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</guid>
      <description>Ryan White Letters View the project here.
Overview The Ryan White Letters Collection consists of almost 6000 letters and cards written to Ryan White and his family during the last years of his life. After being diagnosed with HIV/AIDS at the age of 13, Ryan’s legal fight to attend school despite his disease brought him to the forefront of public discussion about AIDS and its victims in the late 1980s. Thousands of letters came to Ryan from all over the world, many of them from children and teens who had seen his story in the media and wanted Ryan to know he was loved and supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scarlets and Blues</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</guid>
      <description>Scarlets and Blues View the project here.
Overview Travel back in time and take a behind-the-scenes look at the stories, lives and interactions of WWI-era staff and soldiers at the Royal Hospital Chelsea, one of London’s most iconic and longstanding institutions.
Named for the colours of the coats worn by England’s famous Chelsea Pensioners, the Scarlets and Blues project takes a behind-the-scenes look at the Royal Hospital Chelsea using records from The National Archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed Sleuth</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/seed-sleuth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/seed-sleuth/</guid>
      <description>Seed Sleuth View the project here.
Overview Arabidopsis thaliana (Arabidopsis) was the first plant to have its genome completely sequenced (circa 2000). Although technically a weed, this small plant has been transformed into an important model system for plant research.
This project aims to provide ABRC with new information about these seed lines by asking citizen scientists to quantify the number of mutant phenotypes and dead seeds in different seed samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small world of words</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/small-world-of-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/small-world-of-words/</guid>
      <description>small world of words View the project here.
Overview The small world of words project is a large-scale scientific study that aims to build a mental dictionary or lexicon in the major languages of the world and make this information widely available.
In contrast to a thesaurus or dictionary, we use word associations to learn about what words mean and which ones are central in the human mind. This enables psychologists, linguists, neuro-scientists and others to test new theories about how we represent and process language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smithsonian National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</guid>
      <description>Smithsonian National Archives View the project here.
Overview Become a Smithsonian Digital Volunteer and help us make historical documents and biodiversity data more accessible.
Join 55,775 &amp;ldquo;volunpeers&amp;rdquo; to add more to the total 912,645 pages of field notes, diaries, ledgers, logbooks, currency proof sheets, photo albums, manuscripts, biodiversity specimens labels, and historic audio recordings, that have been collaboratively transcribed and reviewed since June 2013.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoke Sense Study</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/smoke-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/smoke-sense/</guid>
      <description>Smoke Sense Study View the project here.
Overview Smoke Sense is a crowdsourcing, citizen science research project developed by EPA researchers focused on increasing public awareness and engagement related to wildfire smoke health risks. Specifically, EPA wants to understand the extent that exposure to wildland fire smoke affects health and productivity, discover what steps people are willing to take to reduce their exposure, and develop health risk communication strategies that improve public health when there is wildfire smoke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Psychology Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</guid>
      <description>Social Psychology Network View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
This page contains links to 259 web-based experiments, surveys, and other social psychology studies.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Jet Hunter</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/solar-jet-hunter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/solar-jet-hunter/</guid>
      <description>Solar Jet Hunter View the project here.
Overview Join the hunt for solar jets—enigmatic bursts of energy from our own star, the Sun!
Studying solar jets, which are small and narrow ejections of solar material, may help us address some of the Sun&amp;rsquo;s mysteries. For example, solar jets could be linked to energetic particles and perturbations in the solar wind. In this project, we focus on features that are found at various sizes and locations on the Sun, which can be observed clearly in extreme ultraviolet images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spyfish Aotearoa</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/spyfish-aotearoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/spyfish-aotearoa/</guid>
      <description>Spyfish Aotearoa View the project here.
Overview Our team deploys baited underwater cameras in marine reserves all over Aotearoa New Zealand to monitor the abundance and diversity of marine life. Help us identify and count the species of fish recorded by the cameras. Your classifications will be used to determine the effectiveness of the reserves, inform marine management, and protect our taonga (treasured) species.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford University Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</guid>
      <description>Stanford University Archives View the project here.
Overview The Stanford University Archives is the official repository for records of Stanford University and serves as its institutional memory. The Archives collects, preserves, administers, and promotes access to materials in any format that document the history of Stanford, including its founders, administration, faculty, students, and alumni/ae. Our holdings include more than 30,000 linear feet of material and 20+ TB of electronic records within 2,200+ collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Notes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</guid>
      <description>Star Notes View the project here.
Overview Help us transcribe the groundbreaking work of early women astronomers!
We have digitized the notebooks of the Harvard Computers and early Harvard astronomers including Williamina Fleming, Annie Jump Cannon, Henrietta Swan Leavitt, and many others. The goal of Star Notes is to link these notebooks back to their original source material: 500,000 glass plate photographs representing the first ever picture of the visible universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardust@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/stardust-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/stardust-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Stardust@home View the project here.
Overview On January 15, 2006, the Stardust spacecraft’s sample return capsule parachuted gently onto the Utah desert. Nestled within the capsule were precious particles collected during Stardust’s dramatic encounter with comet Wild 2 in January of 2004; and something else, even rarer and no less precious: tiny particles of interstellar dust that originated in distant stars, light-years away. They are the first such contemporary interstellar dust particles ever collected in space and returned to Earth for study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of St James&#39;s Burial Ground</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</guid>
      <description>Stories of St James&amp;rsquo;s Burial Ground View the project here.
Overview High-Speed Rail 2 (HS2) is a major infrastructure project connecting cities across the UK with faster train lines and services. In London, contractors Costain Skanska Joint Venture (CSJV) are managing work near Euston Station where construction is taking place on the site of St James’s Burial Ground, a major 18th-19th century cemetery site. Ahead of this work over 100 archaeologists and specialists from MOLA Headland Infrastructure were brought in to excavate and record over 40,000 burials, the largest archaeological excavation of its kind ever undertaken in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swipes for Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/swipes-for-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/swipes-for-science/</guid>
      <description>Swipes for Science View the project here.
Overview The problem
 Big data in biomedical research needs individual inspection, but this doesn’t scale for large datasets. For example, some researchers analyze MRI images to study the brain. But before they start the analysis, they have to visually inspect each image to make sure it is good quality. And at various stages in data processing, researchers have to check images to make sure the analysis is correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag Along with Adler</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/tag-with-adler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/tag-with-adler/</guid>
      <description>Tag Along with Adler View the project here.
Overview Help the Adler Planetarium tag our collections to expand how we catalogue our objects, and how our users can find them!
As museums add collections online, the language that describes the objects - known as metadata - affects how people find and search for these objects. Cataloguers and museum staff create metadata based on standards and rules. This means access is often limited to only those who understand the style used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestMyBrain</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</guid>
      <description>TestMyBrain View the project here.
Overview TestMyBrain is a not-for-profit initiative dedicated to collaborating with citizen scientists throughout the world by providing measurement tools that allow people to engage in science and learn about themselves.
At TestMyBrain, we have the same goal that you do - to understand more about your brain. All of our experiments are designed to provide personalized feedback that is specific to you and will help you learn more about your own mind and brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</guid>
      <description>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project View the project here.
Overview The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project belongs to all of us who live in Berkeley. We invite you to participate by making a contribution, e-mailing us current or historical photos that will add to this website, or writing and sending us your own e-Plaque texts with photos.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greater Bilby Sanctuary</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/greater-bilby-sanctuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/greater-bilby-sanctuary/</guid>
      <description>The Greater Bilby Sanctuary View the project here.
Overview With climate change, drought conditions are becoming more frequent and severe in Australia. Greater bilbies (Macrotis lagotis), like many other species, are sensitive to drought. To combat this conservation challenge, we need to think of creative solutions to support threatened species, such as the bilby, during drought.
In 2019, research collaborators at the University of New South Wales and the Taronga Conservation Society Australia released bilbies into a 110-ha semi-wild sanctuary at Taronga Western Plains Zoo, in Dubbo, NSW, for conservation breeding and release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Indy Wildlife Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/indy-wildlife-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/indy-wildlife-watch/</guid>
      <description>The Indy Wildlife Watch: An Initiative of the CUES View the project here.
Overview Join the Center for Urban Ecology and Sustainability (CUES) at Butler University and the Indianapolis Zoo by tagging animals in our photos!
Urbanization describes a human population shift from rural areas to cities, which usually results in the physical growth of urban areas.
As the global population of humans continues to grow, so will the rate of urbanization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Koster seafloor observatory</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/koster-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/koster-observatory/</guid>
      <description>The Koster seafloor observatory View the project here.
Overview At the Koster seafloor observatory we want to know how climate change and human activities influence Sweden&amp;rsquo;s marine ecosystems.
For the last 20 years, we have used Remotely Operated Vehicles and cameras to monitor the Kosterhavets National Park. A highly-diverse and unique marine reserve in the south of Sweden. Now, we need your help identifying the habitat, species, and presence of litter recorded in over 3,000 hours of underwater videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Map Corps</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</guid>
      <description>The National Map Corps View the project here.
Overview By updating and verifying structures data, volunteers are making significant contributions to USGS National Structures Database, The National Map, and ultimately U.S. Topo Maps!
TNMCorps is an online crowdsourcing mapping project with volunteers successfully editing structures in all 50 States, Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands.
Anyone with an interest in contributing can volunteer. It is easy to sign up and get started!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RBGE Herbarium: Exploring Gesneriaceae, the African violet family</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/rbge-herbarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/rbge-herbarium/</guid>
      <description>The RBGE Herbarium: Exploring Gesneriaceae, the African violet family View the project here.
Overview Open up global biodiversity research possibilities by releasing the data held in 300 years of plant specimens!
The Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh&amp;rsquo;s extensive Herbarium collection is estimated to hold three million specimens representing half to two thirds of the worlds flora. Herbarium specimen data helps inform and target conservation and climate change mitigation efforts protecting plant species for future generations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web Experiment List</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
The Web Experiment List NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
An interactive Web-based hotspot and archive for Internet-based experiments and surveys.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</guid>
      <description>Transcribe View the project here.
Overview Transcribe is the Library of Virginia’s collaborative online workspace where the public can participate in enhancing access to many of our amazing collections documenting over 400 years of Virginia history, people, and culture. This is the perfect opportunity for participants to dig deep into our collections and transcribe historical materials from five to ten active projects at a time. From peace to wartime, court records to letters home, and conspiracies to political statements, there will be something for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translate TED Talks</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/ted-translate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/ted-translate/</guid>
      <description>Translate TED Talks View the project here.
Overview TED Translators are a global community of volunteers who subtitle TED Talks, and enable the inspiring ideas in them to crisscross languages and borders.
Help make TED accessible to your language! Join our global community of volunteers.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</guid>
      <description>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration View the project here.
Overview Questions about how people make sense of and engage with their personal omic information including their personal genomics and microbiome data, and how comfortable they feel about sharing such information in order to advance scientific and biomedical research, are not only of paramount importance for society and policy makers, but also a pressing issue for HCI researchers. Funded by the National Science Foundation, and in collaboration with Open Humans, we investigate how to design effective interaction techniques to empower nonexpert users to engage with and make sense of their personal omic information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Tides</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/uk-tides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/uk-tides/</guid>
      <description>UK Tides View the project here.
Overview About 28% of the people live near the coast, and with global sea level rising, we need long records to be able to investigate how local tides and sea level are changing. One way this can be done is by recovering data from old documents. In this project, we are trying to convert data from old tide gauge ledgers from the North West of England into data usable by scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</guid>
      <description>United States National Archives View the project here.
Overview Welcome to our Citizen Archivist program. You can contribute to the National Archives Catalog by tagging, transcribing and adding comments to our records, making them more accessible and searchable. Join us! Every contribution you make helps unlock history.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices Through Time: The Story of Care</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/voices-through-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/voices-through-time/</guid>
      <description>Voices Through Time: The Story of Care View the project here.
Overview Help us transcribe the records of Coram, the UK’s first children’s charity, to tell the story of care from where it began.
Our archive contains thousands of handwritten records, going back to the 1700s, which contain the stories of children who were cared for at the Foundling Hospital.
With your help transcribing these records, we can make them available online for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Rescue At Sea</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/weather-rescue-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/weather-rescue-at-sea/</guid>
      <description>Weather Rescue At Sea View the project here.
Overview The aim of the Weather Rescue At Sea project is to construct and extended the global surface temperature record back to the 1780s, based on the air temperature observations recorded across the planet.
This will be achieved by crowd-sourcing the recovery (or data rescue) of the weather observations from historical ship logbooks, station records, weather journals and other sources, to produce a longer, and more consistent dataset of global surface temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</guid>
      <description>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch View the project here.
Overview Want an exclusive view of the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S? Take a closer look at urban wildlife activity through this camera trap project by joining our citizen science team and helping us tag pictures and contribute to urban ecology theory!
Wesselman Woods is home to the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S with over 200 acres of land, making this camera trap project like none other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale Chat</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whale-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whale-chat/</guid>
      <description>Whale Chat View the project here.
Overview The current development of deep learning and artificial intelligence allows a new approach to trying to understand the whale song. Deep learning models could help with identification of humpback sounds and unsupervised learning models could help to classify the song “units” in perhaps different ways. This project aims to investigate humpback songs from different years and regions, to identify humpback whale sounds in recordings, to classify these calls or units, and eventually to see if we can find individually distinct calls or units (the same way we do in Manatee Chat).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whooping Cranes!</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whooping-cranes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whooping-cranes/</guid>
      <description>Whooping Cranes! View the project here.
Overview Help us look for large white birds (Whooping Cranes) in Northern Canada so we can monitor the population of this endangered species!
Whooping Cranes (Grus americana) are one of North America’s rarest birds. The only remaining wild and self-sustaining population of Whooping Cranes breeds in northern Canada and winters on the Texas Gulf Coast. Canada has monitored the population by aerial surveys since the 1960s but the population is now growing quickly and expanding into new breeding areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Mont-Blanc</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wild-mont-blanc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wild-mont-blanc/</guid>
      <description>Wild Mont-Blanc View the project here.
Overview Help us explore the secret life of the Mont-Blanc massif! Our cameras track the distribution, behavior and seasonal rhythm of animals year after year.
Forty camera traps installed across France’s Mont-Blanc massif are giving us a powerful new window into the dynamics of alpine wildlife species. The Research Center for Alpine Ecosystems (CREA Mont-Blanc) needs your help to identify all the different animals caught in hundreds of thousands of camera trap images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</guid>
      <description>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl View the project here.
Overview The western burrowing owl needs our help. Unusual among owl species, this pint-sized raptor lives in elaborate underground burrows. These owls cannot dig their own burrows, and instead “reuse” excavated dens dug by ground squirrels and other fossorial (burrowing) animals. With its penchant for open, native grasslands, the burrowing owl has been on a collision course with humans throughout much of Southern California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woodpecker Cavity Cam</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/woodpecker-cavity-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/woodpecker-cavity-cam/</guid>
      <description>Woodpecker Cavity Cam View the project here.
Overview Help researchers explore the world of woodpecker cavities and the animals that use them!
The Woodpecker Cavity Cam project began in 2019 to augment ongoing research and fill additional knowledge gaps about red-headed woodpeckers. We are working to learn more about their nesting ecology and behavior and the many other animals that use and compete for the cavities these woodpeckers create. Researchers at the Cedar Creek Ecosystem Science Reserve, the University of Minnesota, and volunteers with the Red-headed Woodpecker Recovery Project and Audubon Chapter of Minneapolis have collaborated to place trail cameras outside of red-headed woodpecker cavities at Cedar Creek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zwicky Chemical Factory</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/zwicky-chemical-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/zwicky-chemical-factory/</guid>
      <description>Zwicky Chemical Factory View the project here.
Overview Every year astronomers discover thousands of new supernovae (exploding stars). Once these spectacular events are found, we use spectroscopy to understand the chemical elements in the explosion and what type of star exploded. Help us classify these explosions!
The elements created by an individual supernova (SN) differ depending on the type of SN (for example, oxygen and sodium are primarily created when massive stars explode, whereas iron is primarily created when white dwarf stars explode).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
