<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>entomology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/entomology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in entomology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/entomology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dragonfly Mercury Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/dragonfly-mercury/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/dragonfly-mercury/</guid>
      <description>Dragonfly Mercury Project View the project here.
Overview The Dragonfly Mercury Project engages citizen scientists such as students and teachers in the collection of juvenile dragonflies, also known as dragonfly larvae, from national parks for mercury analysis.
Experience the Dragonfly Mercury Project by watching this short video. Then, grab some rubber boots and a sampling net and join park rangers as we search for juvenile dragonflies! Park rangers and enthusiastic volunteer citizen scientists collect many times the number of dragonflies from many more parks than would be possible for scientists alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLOBE Observer</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</guid>
      <description>GLOBE Observer View the project here.
Overview When you download the GLOBE Observer app, you join the community of The GLOBE Program - citizen scientists, students, and teachers in 120+ countries around the world contributing to Earth system science research.
Your observations:
 Help monitor the conditions of clouds, water (especially as a habitat for mosquitoes), plants (trees and other land cover), and see change over time. Can be used to help interpret NASA and other satellite data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</guid>
      <description>iNaturalist View the project here.
Overview One of the world’s most popular nature apps, iNaturalist helps you identify the plants and animals around you. Get connected with a community of over a million scientists and naturalists who can help you learn more about nature! What’s more, by recording and sharing your observations, you’ll create research quality data for scientists working to better understand and protect nature. iNaturalist is a joint initiative by the California Academy of Sciences and the National Geographic Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkweeds and Monarchs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</guid>
      <description>Milkweeds and Monarchs View the project here.
Overview Help preserve the majestic monarch butterfly.
Soaring from Mexico into the United States and Canada, monarch butterflies are searching for one thing: milkweed plants. Monarch butterflies are beautiful, charismatic insects known for their long-distance migration and their reliance on milkweeds (Asclepias species). Milkweeds are the only plants on which monarchs lay their eggs. After the eggs hatch, the caterpillars, also called larvae, eat milkweed leaves to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monarch (Butterfly) Larva Monitoring Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/monarch-larva-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/monarch-larva-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Monarch (Butterfly) Larva Monitoring Project View the project here.
Overview The Monarch Larva Monitoring Project (MLMP) is a citizen science project involving volunteers from across the United States and Canada in monarch research. It was developed in 1997 by researchers at the University of Minnesota to collect long-term data on larval monarch populations and milkweed habitat. The project focuses on monarch distribution and abundance during the breeding season in North America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - CalBug</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-calbug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-calbug/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - CalBug View the project here.
Overview Natural history collections house over a billion insect specimens worldwide collected over several centuries. Specimen labels encode data denoting species, location, and date captured and are used to study biogeographic patterns, spread of invasive species, and responses to land use, climate, and other environmental changes. However, access to data is impractical for most of the research community.
Because of enormous collection sizes, entomology has lagged behind other disciplines in digitizing collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Terrestrial Parasite Tracker</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-terrestrial-parasite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-terrestrial-parasite/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Terrestrial Parasite Tracker View the project here.
Overview Parasitic arthropods inflict an enormous burden on human society; they afflict human health and the animals on which we depend. The negative effects of parasitic arthropods are exacerbated by current climate and ecosystem change. Fleas that vectored the pathogen causing bubonic plague wreaked havoc on historic human populations. Mosquitos continue to vector pathogens responsible for malaria and dengue, and ticks vector the bacteria responsible for Lyme disease; these arthropod borne pathogens infect and kill millions of people each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pollinators and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Pollinators and Climate View the project here.
Overview Help us understand how plant-pollinator interactions are responding to a changing climate.
Changes in pollination has significant impacts on how we humans live our lives and interact with our environment on a daily basis. Pollinator and pollinator health changes the success of fruiting for plants and our food supply and therefore our health. We know that phenological events can vary from year to year, but how are pollinators affected by these variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PollinatorWatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/pollinatorwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/pollinatorwatch/</guid>
      <description>PollinatorWatch View the project here.
Overview For the past three years time-lapse cameras set up at various locations across the Arctic have gathered millions of images of flowers. The goal is to monitor the periodic changes in plant and insect life and ultimately to train a computer to automatically locate and identify pollinators in the images. Now we need your help spotting the pollinators that visit the flowers!
Pollinators, such as bees and other insects, play important roles in many ecological processes such as pollination of crops, disease transmission and pest regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Migratory Dragonfly Partnership</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/migratory-dragonfly-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/migratory-dragonfly-partnership/</guid>
      <description>The Migratory Dragonfly Partnership View the project here.
Overview To better understand and conserve North America&amp;rsquo;s dragonfly migration, dragonfly experts, nongovernmental programs, academic institutions, and federal agencies from the United States, Mexico, and Canada have formed the collaborative Migratory Dragonfly Partnership (MDP).
Regular monitoring and centralized reporting among participants across three nations will help us answer some of the many questions currently surrounding dragonfly migration and provide information needed to create cross-border conservation programs to protect and sustain the phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
