<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in biology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chimp and See</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</guid>
      <description>Chimp and See View the project here.
Overview Studies of human evolution often focus on the fossils and artifacts left by our early ancestors. However, we can also make inferences about human origins by studying our closest living relatives: chimpanzees, the great apes that live across equatorial Africa. Because humans and chimps are so closely related, patterns in chimpanzee behavior may tell us quite a bit about how the earliest hominids lived and evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Endo</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Endo View the project here.
Overview In order to study a disease, we need to know what it looks like. When it comes to endometriosis, there are many different ways in which the disease can present itself in patients. There is a disconnect between how doctors think about the disease and what patients experience on a daily basis. Bridging this gap is critical to further research on endometriosis. Citizen Endo will use a series of studies to better understand the disease from the perspective of patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program View the project here.
Overview The key to the next life-saving biomedical discovery might be living right below your feet. Dozens of fungi can occupy a single handful of soil and many of them are adept at making new compounds called natural products. These remarkable molecules hold tremendous promise for treating human diseases.
It only takes a few minutes to help by collecting a scoop of soil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID.SI</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/covid/</guid>
      <description>CITIZEN SCIENCE AND THE FIGHT AGAINST THE CORONAVIRUS (COVID.SI) View the project here.
Overview “CITIZEN SCIENCE AND THE FIGHT AGAINST THE CORONAVIRUS” is an open project by a collective of good-willed researchers and volunteers, who with to contribute a stone in the mosaic of the full picture of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19, with the sum of our work, knowledge and experience. The group is lead by dr. Črtomir Podlipnik and dr. Marko Jukić, experts with years of experience in computer supported molecular modelling, pharmaceutical chemistry and chemo/bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyewire</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</guid>
      <description>Eyewire View the project here.
Overview Eyewire is a game to map the brain. Anyone can play and you need no scientific background. Hundreds of thousands of people from around the world already do. Together we are mapping the 3D structure of neurons and advancing our quest to understand ourselves.
By joining Eyewire, you can help map the connectome, starting with connections between retinal neurons. Eyewire gameplay advances neuroscience by helping researchers discover how neurons connect and network to process information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folding@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Install our software to become a citizen scientist and contribute your compute power to help fight global health threats like COVID19, Alzheimer’s Disease, and cancer!
Folding@Home began in October 2000 in the lab of Dr. Vijay Pande at Stanford University. Since 2019, the project has been in the hands of Dr. Gregory Bowman, a former Pande Lab graduate student. In addition to the numerous scientists who have worked on the project over the years, F@h has been supported by thousands of dedicated volunteers who have enabled outstanding scientific research and computational achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foldit</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/foldit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/foldit/</guid>
      <description>Foldit View the project here.
Overview Foldit is a revolutionary crowdsourcing computer game enabling you to contribute to important scientific research.
Knowing the structure of a protein is key to understanding how it works and to targeting it with drugs. A small protein can consist of 100 amino acids, while some human proteins can be huge (1000 amino acids). The number of different ways even a small protein can fold is astronomical because there are so many degrees of freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUGRID.net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gpugrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gpugrid/</guid>
      <description>GPUGRID.net View the project here.
Overview GPUGRID.net is a distributed computing infrastructure devoted to biomedical research. Thanks to the contribution of volunteers, GPUGRID scientists can perform molecular simulations to understand the function of proteins in health and disease.
This is a volunteer distributed computing project for biomedical research from the Universitat Pompeu Fabra in Barcelona (Spain). GPUGRID is made of many graphics cards (GPUs) joined together to deliver high-performance all-atom biomolecular simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Stop TB</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/help-stop-tb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/help-stop-tb/</guid>
      <description>Help Stop TB View the project here.
Overview Tuberculosis (TB) is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most dangerous diseases, and has plagued humans for thousands of years. About one-third of the world&amp;rsquo;s population harbors the TB bacterium, with 1.5 million people dying in 2014 alone, and the World Health Organization now ranks TB alongside HIV as the world&amp;rsquo;s deadliest infectious disease. Through Help Stop TB, researchers are using World Community Grid to help fight this deadly disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</guid>
      <description>iNaturalist View the project here.
Overview One of the world’s most popular nature apps, iNaturalist helps you identify the plants and animals around you. Get connected with a community of over a million scientists and naturalists who can help you learn more about nature! What’s more, by recording and sharing your observations, you’ll create research quality data for scientists working to better understand and protect nature. iNaturalist is a joint initiative by the California Academy of Sciences and the National Geographic Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Cancer Markers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mapping-cancer-markers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mapping-cancer-markers/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Mapping Cancer Markers on World Community Grid aims to identify the markers associated with various types of cancer. The project is analyzing millions of data points collected from thousands of healthy and cancerous patient tissue samples. These include tissues with lung, ovarian, prostate, pancreatic and breast cancers. By comparing these different data points, researchers aim to identify patterns of markers for different cancers and correlate them with different outcomes, including responsiveness to various treatment options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrafter</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nanocrafter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nanocrafter/</guid>
      <description>Nanocrafter View the project here.
Overview The field of synthetic biology has grown to a multibillion-dollar market as a result of how broad the applications are. From terraforming to fighting viruses! One of the avenues of synthetic biology, and the focus of Nanocrafter, is using synthesized DNA to create biological machines.
But actually building the DNA components in real life isn’t very easy, although the price has gone down drastically. Normally, scientists and researchers work with digital models, which will then have to go through a long process before being accepted for synthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</guid>
      <description>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes View the project here.
Overview We are running ‘Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes’ to analyse images of lymph nodes from breast cancer patients. This project will generate data that will be used to help improve our AI model performance. We are trying to find the germinal centres, the light pink circles in lymph nodes. When the immune system spot something foreign, new immune cells were produced in germinal centres of lymph nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Insulin</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/open-insulin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/open-insulin/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview The Open Insulin Foundation is a non-profit creating the means for communities in-need to have local sources of safe, affordable, high-quality insulin.
Our governance is shared between people with diabetes and people working on the project. Our working groups collaborate to develop new tools for open drug production, from R&amp;amp;D to manufacturing for medical use. Our goal is that people living with diabetes and their communities can own and govern the organizations that produce the medicine they depend on to survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA World (beta)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rna-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rna-world/</guid>
      <description>RNA World (beta) View the project here.
Overview RNA World is a distributed supercomputer that uses Internet-connected computers to advance RNA research. This system is dedicated to identify, analyze, structurally predict and design RNA molecules on the basis of established bioinformatics software in a high-performance, high-throughput fashion.
In contrast to classical bioinformatic approaches, RNA World does not rely on individual desktop computers, web servers or supercomputers. Instead, it represents a continuously evolving cluster of world-wide distributed machines of any type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosetta@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rosetta-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rosetta-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Rosetta@home View the project here.
Overview By running Rosetta@home on your computer when you&amp;rsquo;re not using it you will speed up and extend our efforts to design new proteins and to predict their 3-dimensional shapes. Proteins are the molecular machines and building blocks of life. You can read more about protein folding and design here.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiDock@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/sidock-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/sidock-at-home/</guid>
      <description>SiDock@home View the project here.
Overview Sidock@home is an international volunteer computing project aimed at drug discovery. The first mission of the project is discovery of possible drugs against the SARS-CoV-2 virus. It started as an extension of the project COVID.SI to engage the BOINC community into the drug discovery.
You can help with your computer. With the help of BOINC, you will download a subset of compounds on your computer, examine the compounds in the context of the studied target and send the results to a server where they are collected for later analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</guid>
      <description>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR) View the project here.
Overview Traits Across Species’ Ranges is a community science project focused on understanding how variation within plant species influences the size and movement of different pools of elements (e.g., carbon, nitrogen) on the surface of the Earth.
For 2021 we are currently focused on developing partnerships with community scientist groups and individuals to survey patterns of green vs. freshly fallen leaf nutrient concentrations (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</guid>
      <description>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration View the project here.
Overview Questions about how people make sense of and engage with their personal omic information including their personal genomics and microbiome data, and how comfortable they feel about sharing such information in order to advance scientific and biomedical research, are not only of paramount importance for society and policy makers, but also a pressing issue for HCI researchers. Funded by the National Science Foundation, and in collaboration with Open Humans, we investigate how to design effective interaction techniques to empower nonexpert users to engage with and make sense of their personal omic information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
