<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>environmental science on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/environmental-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in environmental science on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/environmental-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality Citizen Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air Quality Citizen Science View the project here.
Overview Are you interested in helping in this NASA-funded science project? Do you have interest in understanding more about the air quality in your neighborhood? Would you like to measure air quality near your home or place of work? Have you been intrigued by the type of data that NASA collects from their satellites? Then this is the perfect opportunity for you to get involved!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bloomWatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/bloomwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/bloomwatch/</guid>
      <description>bloomWatch View the project here.
Overview Do you notice that a lake suddenly turned the color of pea soup or a blue-green paint spill? Or do you see green clumps, flakes or filaments floating in a lake?
Blooms in fresh waterbodies are commonly due to cyanobacteria, which have the potential to produce toxins that affect humans, pets, and our ecosystems.
State and local officials can’t be watching every lake at all times!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cyanoScope</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cyanoscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cyanoscope/</guid>
      <description>cyanoScope View the project here.
Overview cyanoScope uses modern technologies and a social approach to learn more about cyanobacteria and their distribution. By participating you will be helping scientists and water resource managers gain information on the occurrence of cyanobacteria in surface waters.
We will use submitted reports to map the spatial distribution and seasonal occurrence of cyanobacteria in lakes, ponds, and reservoirs.
Collect cyanobacteria:
 collect cyanobacteria with a net tow, prepare your microscope slides, identify cyanobacteria found in your sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EarthEcho Water Challenge</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/earthecho-water-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/earthecho-water-challenge/</guid>
      <description>EarthEcho Water Challenge View the project here.
Overview The EarthEcho Water Challenge (formerly World Water Monitoring Challenge) is an international program that runs annually from March 22 (the United Nations World Water Day) through December and equips anyone to protect the water resources we depend on every day. The EarthEcho Water Challenge builds public awareness and involvement in protecting water resources around the world by engaging citizens to conduct basic monitoring of their local waterbodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iWitness Pollution Map</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/iwitness-pollution-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/iwitness-pollution-map/</guid>
      <description>iWitness Pollution Map View the project here.
Overview The iWitness Pollution map is a tool that communities can use to document pollution in their neighborhoods. By calling or texting to (504) 272 – 7645 (27 27 OIL), residents can crowdsource pollution and tell the world about the bad smells, flares and noise from the neighboring petrochemical plant.
We first deployed the map in 2010 in the days after the BP Disaster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp; Satellites</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/locss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/locss/</guid>
      <description>Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp;amp; Satellites (LOCSS) View the project here.
Overview The Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp;amp; Satellites project seeks to better understand how the quantity of water in lakes is changing.
Are lake volumes affected most by precipitation, water table height, evaporation or some other factors? Knowing the answer to this question will help us better understand how water moves in relation to these lakes and the surrounding land and what that may mean for lake users and these ecosystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Origins</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</guid>
      <description>Plastic Origins View the project here.
Overview Plastic Origins is a project initiated by the not-for-profit Surfrider Foundation Europe in search of solutions to address the source of ocean pollution. Supported by citizens, associations, scientists, and socially responsible companies, the Plastic Origins project aims to map plastic pollution in European rivers by applying participatory science and Artificial Intelligence technology. This mapping data helps to identify areas of high impact, gain a deeper understanding of the problem on the field, and measure the evolution of pollution over time as well as to raise awareness among political decision-makers on the local, national, and European levels and urge them to act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project RISE</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rise/</guid>
      <description>Project RISE View the project [here](https://smoke.createlab.org/label.html
Overview Project RISE, initiated by the CMU CREATE Lab, aims to train an Artificial Intelligence model to Recognize Industrial Smoke Emissions, and we need volunteers to help label smoke emissions. So far, 22099 (23.05%) videos are fully labeled. We would greatly appreciate your participation in this community-powered AI research!
Our goal is to invite citizens in creating data-driven evidence that shows the pollution source (using the smoke emissions found by the AI model) and its impact on the community (using Smell Pittsburgh).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoke Sense Study</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/smoke-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/smoke-sense/</guid>
      <description>Smoke Sense Study View the project here.
Overview Smoke Sense is a crowdsourcing, citizen science research project developed by EPA researchers focused on increasing public awareness and engagement related to wildfire smoke health risks. Specifically, EPA wants to understand the extent that exposure to wildland fire smoke affects health and productivity, discover what steps people are willing to take to reduce their exposure, and develop health risk communication strategies that improve public health when there is wildfire smoke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Tides</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/uk-tides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/uk-tides/</guid>
      <description>UK Tides View the project here.
Overview About 28% of the people live near the coast, and with global sea level rising, we need long records to be able to investigate how local tides and sea level are changing. One way this can be done is by recovering data from old documents. In this project, we are trying to convert data from old tide gauge ledgers from the North West of England into data usable by scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild and Scenic Rivers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</guid>
      <description>Wild and Scenic Rivers View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
This is a multi-year effort to sample National Wild and Scenic Rivers. The project spans from northern Alaska to southeast Florida, from small scenic creeks to wild raging rivers.
The National Wild and Scenic Rivers System contributes 10% of drinking water throughout the United States. In addition, these rivers are essential for their cultural, recreational, and natural value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
