<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hub Websites on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hub Websites on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/hubs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Citizen Science NL</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/cs-nederlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/cs-nederlands/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Citizen Science NL View the project here.
Overview A list of awesome Citizen Science projects from the Netherlands with additional information such as duration, organizations, and links to resources.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOINC</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/boinc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/boinc/</guid>
      <description>BOINC View the project here.
Overview BOINC lets you help cutting-edge science research using your computer. The BOINC app, running on your computer, downloads scientific computing jobs and runs them invisibly in the background. It&amp;rsquo;s easy and safe. About 30 science projects use BOINC. They investigate diseases, study climate change, discover pulsars, and do many other types of scientific research.
The BOINC and Science United projects are located at the University of California, Berkeley and are supported by the National Science Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>citizenscience.gov</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/citizenscience-gov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/citizenscience-gov/</guid>
      <description>citizenscience.gov View the project here.
Overview NOTE: When viewing the catalog page, make sure you set the View by Status filter to only &amp;ldquo;Active&amp;rdquo; projects!
CitizenScience.gov is an official government website designed to accelerate the use of crowdsourcing and citizen science across the U.S. government. The site provides a portal to three key components: a catalog of federally supported citizen science projects, a toolkit to assist federal practitioners with designing and maintaining their projects, and a gateway to a community of hundreds of citizen science practitioners and coordinators across government as called for in the Crowdsourcing and Citizen Science Act of 2016 (15 USC 3724).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Research on the Net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</guid>
      <description>Psychological Research on the Net View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
On this website you will find links to known experiments on the internet that are psychologically related. They are organized by general topic area with the topic areas listed chronologically with the most recently added at the top.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science United</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/science-united/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/science-united/</guid>
      <description>Science United View the project here.
Overview Science United lets you help scientific research projects by giving them computing power. These projects do research in astronomy, physics, biomedicine, mathematics, and environmental science; you can pick the areas you want to support.
You help by installing BOINC, a free program that runs scientific jobs in the background and when you&amp;rsquo;re not using the computer. BOINC is secure and will not affect your normal use of the computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciStarter</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/scistarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/scistarter/</guid>
      <description>SciStarter View the project here.
Overview SciStarter is a globally acclaimed, online citizen science hub where more than 3,000 projects, searchable by location, topic, age level, etc, have been registered by individual project leaders or imported through partnerships with federal governments, NGOs, and universities. As a research affiliate of NCSU and ASU, and a popular citizen science portal, SciStarter hosts an active community of close to 100,000 registered citizen scientists and millions of additional site visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Psychology Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</guid>
      <description>Social Psychology Network View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
This page contains links to 259 web-based experiments, surveys, and other social psychology studies.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web Experiment List</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
The Web Experiment List NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
An interactive Web-based hotspot and archive for Internet-based experiments and surveys.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/volunteerscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/volunteerscience/</guid>
      <description>Volunteer Science View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
Volunteer Science is a platform for creating online labs. Individual researchers can create unlimited online studies and recruit unlimited participants from anywhere around the world. Research labs can create research teams, giving all their members access to lab experiments and data. Large research organizations like universities, government agencies, and private companies can provide their research teams with organization-specific behavioral lab facilities connecting to internal- and external-facing audiences and subject pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Community Grid</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/world-community-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/world-community-grid/</guid>
      <description>World Community Grid View the project here.
Overview Donate your device’s spare computing power to help scientists solve the world’s biggest problems.
As a World Community Grid volunteer, your device does research calculations when it has spare power. With your help, scientists can identify the most important results to study in the lab, bringing them one step closer to discoveries that save lives and address global problems.
View already-completed research here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zooniverse</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/zooniverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/zooniverse/</guid>
      <description>Zooniverse View the project here.
Overview NOTE: As of November 2021, ALL active projects listed on Zooniverse are listed on this website in individual entries. New projects are added to Zooniverse intermittently, however, and sometimes their &amp;ldquo;Paused&amp;rdquo; projects turn active again, so it&amp;rsquo;s worth checking Zooniverse on occasion to see if there is anything new.
The Zooniverse is the world’s largest and most popular platform for people-powered research. This research is made possible by volunteers — more than a million people around the world who come together to assist professional researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
