<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neurology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/neurology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in neurology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/neurology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eyewire</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</guid>
      <description>Eyewire View the project here.
Overview Eyewire is a game to map the brain. Anyone can play and you need no scientific background. Hundreds of thousands of people from around the world already do. Together we are mapping the 3D structure of neurons and advancing our quest to understand ourselves.
By joining Eyewire, you can help map the connectome, starting with connections between retinal neurons. Eyewire gameplay advances neuroscience by helping researchers discover how neurons connect and network to process information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LabintheWild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</guid>
      <description>LabintheWild View the project here.
Overview LabintheWild tests your abilities and preferences. At the end of each experiment, you will see a page with your personalized feedback, which lets you compare yourself and your performance to other people around the world.
By participating, you contribute to research on people&amp;rsquo;s similarities and differences and help improve users&#39; experience when interacting with technology. We believe that research should be done in collaboration with people—people like you from all over the world who are interested in learning about themselves and helping research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestMyBrain</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</guid>
      <description>TestMyBrain View the project here.
Overview TestMyBrain is a not-for-profit initiative dedicated to collaborating with citizen scientists throughout the world by providing measurement tools that allow people to engage in science and learn about themselves.
At TestMyBrain, we have the same goal that you do - to understand more about your brain. All of our experiments are designed to provide personalized feedback that is specific to you and will help you learn more about your own mind and brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You see it? You name it!</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/u-see-it-u-name-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/u-see-it-u-name-it/</guid>
      <description>You see it? You name it! View the project here.
Overview One of our goals is to provide cognitive neuroscience and machine learning researchers with high quality stimuli. One issue both community face is in fact the lack of freely available large set of images appropriately curated by humans. This is were anyone can help and become part of an international and interdisciplinary scientific effort! We here present tons of pictures and ask volunteers to name the main item in the image (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
