<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ecology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/ecology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ecology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/ecology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</guid>
      <description>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count View the project here.
Overview Every year, thousands of seals and sea lions haul out on Año Nuevo Island to give birth, molt, and rest. The secluded shores of the island make a perfect spot for northern elephant seal and California sea lion mothers to give birth and nurse their pups. Researchers at the University of California, Santa Cruz are interested in tracking the number of animals that haul out onto the island&amp;rsquo;s beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</guid>
      <description>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field View the project here.
Overview The British Library wildlife and environmental sounds archive was established in 1969 by the ornithologist Patrick Seller and the BBC radio producer Jeffrey Boswell, with the endeavour to create a national collection that can document, preserve and share the sounds of nature for future generations to study and enjoy. Since then we have amassed over 6.5 million recordings and are now one of the most comprehensive collections in the world, used by scientists and amateur naturalists alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance View the project here.
Overview The Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance is a group of researchers from across the Smithsonian and local universities, with a goal to study and educate the public about North American River Otters in the Chesapeake Bay. We need your help to figure out where these otters are in the Chesapeake Bay!
Very little to no research has been done regarding the numbers, health, and populations of otters in the Chesapeake Bay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chesapeake Water Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-water-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-water-watch/</guid>
      <description>Chesapeake Water Watch View the project here.
Overview We are aiming to improve how effective satellites are at monitoring the health of Chesapeake Bay by comparing information collected from satellites with information collected by researchers and citizen scientists on the ground. Right now, NASA&amp;rsquo;s cutting-edge satellites, provide a unique capability to capture water quality changes in areas that are economically and environmentally important.
There is a long history of public engagement in water quality monitoring in fresh and coastal ecosystems, with volunteer collected data being used as part of monitoring for the US Clean Water Act (Jollymore et al 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago EcoFlora Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Help us track native and non-native plant species in Chicagoland.
Now more than ever we need to understand urban flora-both native and invasive species. The Chicago EcoFlora project is collecting observations of plants in Cook County, Illinois to learn more about local plant life and contribute to conservation planning. With your help, we will collect data on important native species and troublesome new invaders that call our city home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program View the project here.
Overview The key to the next life-saving biomedical discovery might be living right below your feet. Dozens of fungi can occupy a single handful of soil and many of them are adept at making new compounds called natural products. These remarkable molecules hold tremendous promise for treating human diseases.
It only takes a few minutes to help by collecting a scoop of soil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBird</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/ebird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/ebird/</guid>
      <description>eBird View the project here.
Overview eBird transforms the global birding community’s passion for birds into a powerful resource for research, conservation, and education. Your sightings contribute to hundreds of conservation decisions and peer-reviewed papers, thousands of student projects, and help inform bird research worldwide.
eBird is among the world’s largest biodiversity-related science projects, with more than 100 million bird sightings contributed annually by eBirders around the world and an average participation growth rate of approximately 20% year over year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyes of the Reef Hawaii</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/eyes-of-the-reef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/eyes-of-the-reef/</guid>
      <description>Eyes of the Reef Hawaii View the project here.
Overview The Eyes of the Reef Network is a volunteer member-based organization developed to increase public awareness and engage communities in the monitoring and reporting of coral bleaching and disease, marine invasive species, Crown-of-Thorn Sea Star (COTS) outbreaks and other reef diseases.
The statewide network is the first tier of a rapid response protocol developed by the Division of Aquatic Resources and the Climate Change and Marine Disease Local Action Strategy, implemented by Reef Check Hawai‘i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</guid>
      <description>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey View the project here.
Overview Many invasive species, like Garlic Mustard (Alliaria petiolata), are threatening the world’s natural resources, but the abundance of invasive species can vary dramatically over space and time. Scientists still do not have a good understanding of why this is so.
Through large-scale sampling, scientists can identify areas that differ in the intensity of invasion and try to understand why these differences exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLOBE Observer</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</guid>
      <description>GLOBE Observer View the project here.
Overview When you download the GLOBE Observer app, you join the community of The GLOBE Program - citizen scientists, students, and teachers in 120+ countries around the world contributing to Earth system science research.
Your observations:
 Help monitor the conditions of clouds, water (especially as a habitat for mosquitoes), plants (trees and other land cover), and see change over time. Can be used to help interpret NASA and other satellite data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iberian Camera Trap Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/iberian-camera-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/iberian-camera-trap/</guid>
      <description>Iberian Camera Trap Project View the project here.
Overview Wildlife monitoring is often based on outdated protocols. However, advances in technology have paved the way for optimizing data collection and profusing cutting-edge analytical methods. Our cameras are placed in one of the most important protected areas in Europe, the Parque Nacional de Doñana (South Spain). Your classifications will serve to train an artificial intelligence algorithm to do the same with an exorbitant amount of images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</guid>
      <description>iNaturalist View the project here.
Overview One of the world’s most popular nature apps, iNaturalist helps you identify the plants and animals around you. Get connected with a community of over a million scientists and naturalists who can help you learn more about nature! What’s more, by recording and sharing your observations, you’ll create research quality data for scientists working to better understand and protect nature. iNaturalist is a joint initiative by the California Academy of Sciences and the National Geographic Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Wild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</guid>
      <description>Instant Wild View the project here.
Overview ZSL’s Instant Wild empowers you to take part in vital conservation work, bringing you LIVE images and videos from amazing locations all around the world. By identifying the animals in each image, you are contributing to conservation and making a positive impact on the future for wildlife.
Available both as a smartphone app and online at instantwild.zsl.org, Instant Wild mobilises people power to scale up important animal monitoring work, which helps scientists to protect wildlife and secure a richer biodiversity for all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leafsnap</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</guid>
      <description>leafmolester View the project here.
Overview Leafsnap turns users into citizen scientists, automatically sharing images, species identifications, and geo-coded stamps of species locations with a community of scientists who will use the stream of data to map and monitor the ebb and flow of flora.
Leafsnap is a series of electronic field guides being developed by researchers from Columbia University, the University of Maryland, and the Smithsonian Institution. The free mobile apps use visual recognition software to help identify tree species from photographs of their leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Coral Reefs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</guid>
      <description>Mexican Coral Reefs View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Mexico’s Pacific Coast is home to some of the world’s most biodiverse coral reefs, underwater communities that support sharks, turtles, and other marine life. They also support human lives by buffering the coastline from intense storms and providing livelihoods from fishing and tourism. Yet these reefs are imperiled by ocean acidification, more frequent and powerful storms due to climate change, and damage from human overuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkweeds and Monarchs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</guid>
      <description>Milkweeds and Monarchs View the project here.
Overview Help preserve the majestic monarch butterfly.
Soaring from Mexico into the United States and Canada, monarch butterflies are searching for one thing: milkweed plants. Monarch butterflies are beautiful, charismatic insects known for their long-distance migration and their reliance on milkweeds (Asclepias species). Milkweeds are the only plants on which monarchs lay their eggs. After the eggs hatch, the caterpillars, also called larvae, eat milkweed leaves to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s Notebook</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook View the project here.
Overview Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook gathers information on plant and animal phenology across the U.S. to be used for decision-making on local, national and global scales to ensure the continued vitality of our environment.
Scientists alone cannot collect enough data: They need your help. Join more than 15,000 other naturalists across the nation in taking the pulse of our planet. You&amp;rsquo;ll use scientifically-vetted observation guidelines, developed for over 1000 species, to ensure data are useful to researchers and decision-makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&#39;s Flowers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&amp;rsquo;s Flowers View the project here.
Overview The California Phenology Network was originally an NSF-funded collaboration of 22 California herbaria that aimed to image 904,200 herbarium specimens by 2022. In July 2020, this network was expanded by a partner-to-existing-network grant to include six additional institutions and over 148,000 more specimens, for a total of over one million specimens. We will also georeference and transcribe over 320,000 specimens, making their data publicly available on our data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity View the project here.
Overview Digitizing data of southeast United States species allows comparisons of geographic distributions and niche specificity between endemic vascular plant species and non-endemics – essential to characterize and manage a significant component of this nation’s biodiversity imperiled by the effects of climate change, the loss of native habitat to anthropogenic uses, and biotic invasions.
Researchers can utilize herbarium specimen data to model current and future distributions of rare and endemic species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants View the project here.
Overview WeDigFLPlants is a collaboration between professional research botanists, amateur naturalists, gardeners, educators, and citizen scientists to build the most complete picture possible of plant distribution and diversity in Florida over the past 200 years. The data for this historical baseline come from archived plant specimens curated by the world&amp;rsquo;s 3,000 herbaria. Each of these specimens includes a label that answers the who, what, when, and where of the collecting event that produced it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenology and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Phenology and Climate View the project here.
Overview Research Question: How is climate change affecting plant phenology?
Help us understand how plants are responding to this year&amp;rsquo;s seasons and longer-term changes in climate.
How plants react to seasonal change has a big impact on the environment. Because plants are at the base of the food chain, anything that affects plants can impact other parts of the ecosystem. Phenology is important because it affects plants ability to produce fruits and seeds and food availability for other animals like birds and squirrels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pollinators and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Pollinators and Climate View the project here.
Overview Help us understand how plant-pollinator interactions are responding to a changing climate.
Changes in pollination has significant impacts on how we humans live our lives and interact with our environment on a daily basis. Pollinator and pollinator health changes the success of fruiting for plants and our food supply and therefore our health. We know that phenological events can vary from year to year, but how are pollinators affected by these variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot Wisconsin</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/snapshot-wisconsin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/snapshot-wisconsin/</guid>
      <description>Snapshot Wisconsin View the project here.
Overview Snapshot Wisconsin is a statewide wildlife monitoring program that relies on volunteers to host trail cameras throughout the year. Trail cameras are mounted to trees or posts and take photos when triggered by the movement and heat of a passing animal. Once the photos are uploaded and classified by the Zooniverse community, they become data that can be used to understand patterns of animal occurrence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timber Tracking</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Timber Tracking View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Do you care about healthy forests? You can apply to join this project if you are a hiker, a birder, a biker, a forager, or a tree lover to explore the hardwood forests of the eastern and central United States in search of black walnut trees!.
One of the most valuable hardwood species in the United States, black walnut trees are threatened by timber poaching across the 30+ states in their range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</guid>
      <description>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch View the project here.
Overview Want an exclusive view of the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S? Take a closer look at urban wildlife activity through this camera trap project by joining our citizen science team and helping us tag pictures and contribute to urban ecology theory!
Wesselman Woods is home to the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S with over 200 acres of land, making this camera trap project like none other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild and Scenic Rivers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</guid>
      <description>Wild and Scenic Rivers View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
This is a multi-year effort to sample National Wild and Scenic Rivers. The project spans from northern Alaska to southeast Florida, from small scenic creeks to wild raging rivers.
The National Wild and Scenic Rivers System contributes 10% of drinking water throughout the United States. In addition, these rivers are essential for their cultural, recreational, and natural value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildlife of Los Angeles</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildlife-of-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildlife-of-la/</guid>
      <description>Wildlife of Los Angeles View the project here.
Overview In the United States greater than 80% of the human population occurs in cities, yet we know very little about the wildlife in these areas. Much work needs to be done to understand how increases in urbanized areas impact wildlife species and their ability to survive around us. Urbanization poses many threats to wildlife such as loss of habitat, fragmentation of habitat, roads and traffic, poisons and toxins, people, and our pets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woodpecker Cavity Cam</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/woodpecker-cavity-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/woodpecker-cavity-cam/</guid>
      <description>Woodpecker Cavity Cam View the project here.
Overview Help researchers explore the world of woodpecker cavities and the animals that use them!
The Woodpecker Cavity Cam project began in 2019 to augment ongoing research and fill additional knowledge gaps about red-headed woodpeckers. We are working to learn more about their nesting ecology and behavior and the many other animals that use and compete for the cavities these woodpeckers create. Researchers at the Cedar Creek Ecosystem Science Reserve, the University of Minnesota, and volunteers with the Red-headed Woodpecker Recovery Project and Audubon Chapter of Minneapolis have collaborated to place trail cameras outside of red-headed woodpecker cavities at Cedar Creek.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
