<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>humanities on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/humanities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in humanities on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/humanities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Davy Notebooks Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>Davy Notebooks Project View the project here.
Overview Help us to transcribe the manuscript notebooks of Sir Humphry Davy – one of the most significant and famous figures in the scientific and literary culture of early nineteenth-century Britain, Europe, and America.
Davy’s scientific accomplishments include: conducting pioneering research into the physiological effects of nitrous oxide (often called ‘laughing gas’); isolating seven chemical elements (magnesium, calcium, potassium, sodium, strontium, barium, and boron) and establishing the elemental status of chlorine and iodine; inventing a miners’ safety lamp; developing the electrochemical protection of the copper sheeting of Royal Navy vessels; conserving the Herculaneum papyri; and writing an influential text on agricultural chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceResearch.org</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/faceresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/faceresearch/</guid>
      <description>FaceResearch.org View the project here.
Overview FaceResearch.org allows you to participate in short online psychology experiments, most of which are about how we perceive faces and voices. All experiments can be found listed here, and you can play with face demos here.
In addition to participating in face perception experiments, you can also complete lifestyle and personality questionnaires about characteristics that may be associated with face and voice perception and see how you compare to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Pace</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/keeping-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/keeping-pace/</guid>
      <description>Keeping Pace View the project here.
Overview Keeping Pace seeks to study data about how we move around, to understand how seasons and local environment influence our movement patterns.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LabintheWild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</guid>
      <description>LabintheWild View the project here.
Overview LabintheWild tests your abilities and preferences. At the end of each experiment, you will see a page with your personalized feedback, which lets you compare yourself and your performance to other people around the world.
By participating, you contribute to research on people&amp;rsquo;s similarities and differences and help improve users&#39; experience when interacting with technology. We believe that research should be done in collaboration with people—people like you from all over the world who are interested in learning about themselves and helping research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Research on the Net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</guid>
      <description>Psychological Research on the Net View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
On this website you will find links to known experiments on the internet that are psychologically related. They are organized by general topic area with the topic areas listed chronologically with the most recently added at the top.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Flu</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</guid>
      <description>Quantified Flu View the project here.
Overview The question we want to answer is: Can the various physiological parameters tracked by our wearables help to predict when we’re getting sick? With the COVID-19 pandemic influencing all of our lives right now, this question seems more timely than ever. But it&amp;rsquo;s not only the pandemic, this question equally applies to the flu and the common cold!
There is some preliminary data which shows that the data from wearables (like resting heart rate and sleep quality) might be predictive of coming down with a cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small world of words</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/small-world-of-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/small-world-of-words/</guid>
      <description>small world of words View the project here.
Overview The small world of words project is a large-scale scientific study that aims to build a mental dictionary or lexicon in the major languages of the world and make this information widely available.
In contrast to a thesaurus or dictionary, we use word associations to learn about what words mean and which ones are central in the human mind. This enables psychologists, linguists, neuro-scientists and others to test new theories about how we represent and process language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smithsonian National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</guid>
      <description>Smithsonian National Archives View the project here.
Overview Become a Smithsonian Digital Volunteer and help us make historical documents and biodiversity data more accessible.
Join 55,775 &amp;ldquo;volunpeers&amp;rdquo; to add more to the total 912,645 pages of field notes, diaries, ledgers, logbooks, currency proof sheets, photo albums, manuscripts, biodiversity specimens labels, and historic audio recordings, that have been collaboratively transcribed and reviewed since June 2013.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Psychology Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</guid>
      <description>Social Psychology Network View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
This page contains links to 259 web-based experiments, surveys, and other social psychology studies.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestMyBrain</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</guid>
      <description>TestMyBrain View the project here.
Overview TestMyBrain is a not-for-profit initiative dedicated to collaborating with citizen scientists throughout the world by providing measurement tools that allow people to engage in science and learn about themselves.
At TestMyBrain, we have the same goal that you do - to understand more about your brain. All of our experiments are designed to provide personalized feedback that is specific to you and will help you learn more about your own mind and brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Map Corps</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</guid>
      <description>The National Map Corps View the project here.
Overview By updating and verifying structures data, volunteers are making significant contributions to USGS National Structures Database, The National Map, and ultimately U.S. Topo Maps!
TNMCorps is an online crowdsourcing mapping project with volunteers successfully editing structures in all 50 States, Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands.
Anyone with an interest in contributing can volunteer. It is easy to sign up and get started!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web Experiment List</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
The Web Experiment List NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
An interactive Web-based hotspot and archive for Internet-based experiments and surveys.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/volunteerscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/volunteerscience/</guid>
      <description>Volunteer Science View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
Volunteer Science is a platform for creating online labs. Individual researchers can create unlimited online studies and recruit unlimited participants from anywhere around the world. Research labs can create research teams, giving all their members access to lab experiments and data. Large research organizations like universities, government agencies, and private companies can provide their research teams with organization-specific behavioral lab facilities connecting to internal- and external-facing audiences and subject pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zooniverse</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/zooniverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/zooniverse/</guid>
      <description>Zooniverse View the project here.
Overview NOTE: As of November 2021, ALL active projects listed on Zooniverse are listed on this website in individual entries. New projects are added to Zooniverse intermittently, however, and sometimes their &amp;ldquo;Paused&amp;rdquo; projects turn active again, so it&amp;rsquo;s worth checking Zooniverse on occasion to see if there is anything new.
The Zooniverse is the world’s largest and most popular platform for people-powered research. This research is made possible by volunteers — more than a million people around the world who come together to assist professional researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
