<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>botany on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/botany/</link>
    <description>Recent content in botany on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/botany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicago EcoFlora Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Help us track native and non-native plant species in Chicagoland.
Now more than ever we need to understand urban flora-both native and invasive species. The Chicago EcoFlora project is collecting observations of plants in Cook County, Illinois to learn more about local plant life and contribute to conservation planning. With your help, we will collect data on important native species and troublesome new invaders that call our city home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</guid>
      <description>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey View the project here.
Overview Many invasive species, like Garlic Mustard (Alliaria petiolata), are threatening the world’s natural resources, but the abundance of invasive species can vary dramatically over space and time. Scientists still do not have a good understanding of why this is so.
Through large-scale sampling, scientists can identify areas that differ in the intensity of invasion and try to understand why these differences exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLOBE Observer</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</guid>
      <description>GLOBE Observer View the project here.
Overview When you download the GLOBE Observer app, you join the community of The GLOBE Program - citizen scientists, students, and teachers in 120+ countries around the world contributing to Earth system science research.
Your observations:
 Help monitor the conditions of clouds, water (especially as a habitat for mosquitoes), plants (trees and other land cover), and see change over time. Can be used to help interpret NASA and other satellite data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</guid>
      <description>iNaturalist View the project here.
Overview One of the world’s most popular nature apps, iNaturalist helps you identify the plants and animals around you. Get connected with a community of over a million scientists and naturalists who can help you learn more about nature! What’s more, by recording and sharing your observations, you’ll create research quality data for scientists working to better understand and protect nature. iNaturalist is a joint initiative by the California Academy of Sciences and the National Geographic Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leafsnap</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</guid>
      <description>leafmolester View the project here.
Overview Leafsnap turns users into citizen scientists, automatically sharing images, species identifications, and geo-coded stamps of species locations with a community of scientists who will use the stream of data to map and monitor the ebb and flow of flora.
Leafsnap is a series of electronic field guides being developed by researchers from Columbia University, the University of Maryland, and the Smithsonian Institution. The free mobile apps use visual recognition software to help identify tree species from photographs of their leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkweeds and Monarchs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</guid>
      <description>Milkweeds and Monarchs View the project here.
Overview Help preserve the majestic monarch butterfly.
Soaring from Mexico into the United States and Canada, monarch butterflies are searching for one thing: milkweed plants. Monarch butterflies are beautiful, charismatic insects known for their long-distance migration and their reliance on milkweeds (Asclepias species). Milkweeds are the only plants on which monarchs lay their eggs. After the eggs hatch, the caterpillars, also called larvae, eat milkweed leaves to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s Notebook</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook View the project here.
Overview Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook gathers information on plant and animal phenology across the U.S. to be used for decision-making on local, national and global scales to ensure the continued vitality of our environment.
Scientists alone cannot collect enough data: They need your help. Join more than 15,000 other naturalists across the nation in taking the pulse of our planet. You&amp;rsquo;ll use scientifically-vetted observation guidelines, developed for over 1000 species, to ensure data are useful to researchers and decision-makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&#39;s Flowers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&amp;rsquo;s Flowers View the project here.
Overview The California Phenology Network was originally an NSF-funded collaboration of 22 California herbaria that aimed to image 904,200 herbarium specimens by 2022. In July 2020, this network was expanded by a partner-to-existing-network grant to include six additional institutions and over 148,000 more specimens, for a total of over one million specimens. We will also georeference and transcribe over 320,000 specimens, making their data publicly available on our data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Flora of Texas and Oklahoma</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-tx-and-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-tx-and-ok/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Flora of Texas and Oklahoma View the project here.
Overview Naturalists and Scientists have been exploring Nature for centuries, collecting a massive amount of specimens over the course of many lifetimes. While this meticulous work has resulted in more than 3 million botanical specimens being housed in herbaria across Texas and Oklahoma, only a small fraction of this treasure is digitally accessible for observation, or for inclusion in scientific studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - Herbarium</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-herbarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-herbarium/</guid>
      <description>Notes From Nature - Herbarium View the project here.
Overview Welcome to the Herbarium Project on Notes from Nature. We will be hosting lots of great expeditions related to plants on this Project from a variety of institutions.
For the time being these will be mostly specimens related to the from the NitFix project.
The NitFix project received funding from the U.S. Department of Energy to develop mechanisms to engineer bioenergy crops so that these plants can fix nitrogen via root nodule symbioses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Plants of Arkansas</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-plants-of-arkansas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-plants-of-arkansas/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Plants of Arkansas View the project here.
Overview Plants of Arkansas is a data-generating collaboration between professional botanists, amateur naturalists, gardeners, educators, students, and citizen scientists. The goal of the project is to make available to the research community and the public the natural history record of Arkansas plant specimens. It is from these specimens, maintained in herbaria, that we can know what plant species grow in Arkansas and where they can be found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity View the project here.
Overview Digitizing data of southeast United States species allows comparisons of geographic distributions and niche specificity between endemic vascular plant species and non-endemics – essential to characterize and manage a significant component of this nation’s biodiversity imperiled by the effects of climate change, the loss of native habitat to anthropogenic uses, and biotic invasions.
Researchers can utilize herbarium specimen data to model current and future distributions of rare and endemic species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants View the project here.
Overview WeDigFLPlants is a collaboration between professional research botanists, amateur naturalists, gardeners, educators, and citizen scientists to build the most complete picture possible of plant distribution and diversity in Florida over the past 200 years. The data for this historical baseline come from archived plant specimens curated by the world&amp;rsquo;s 3,000 herbaria. Each of these specimens includes a label that answers the who, what, when, and where of the collecting event that produced it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenology and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Phenology and Climate View the project here.
Overview Research Question: How is climate change affecting plant phenology?
Help us understand how plants are responding to this year&amp;rsquo;s seasons and longer-term changes in climate.
How plants react to seasonal change has a big impact on the environment. Because plants are at the base of the food chain, anything that affects plants can impact other parts of the ecosystem. Phenology is important because it affects plants ability to produce fruits and seeds and food availability for other animals like birds and squirrels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants of Concern</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/plants-of-concern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/plants-of-concern/</guid>
      <description>Plants of Concern View the project here.
Overview Interested in monitoring rare plants and joining our team? Fantastic!
Plants of Concern is active in Northeastern and Southern Illinois. We invite you to join us in monitoring rare plants in these regions.
We offer online training through a series of six video modules that you can view at any time. All modules together take approximately 45 minutes to watch. Short quizzes (less than 5 min each) separate each module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/growing-beyond-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/growing-beyond-earth/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here (2021-2022 page) and here (main page).
Overview *NOTE: While the project is already underway for the 2021-2022 school year, this is an annually recurring project that has been going for six years already and will absolutely run again next year. If you are interested in having your class participate
Growing Beyond Earth® (GBE) is a classroom-based citizen science project operated in partnership with NASA. It includes a series of plant experiments conducted by students using equipment similar to the Vegetable Production System (Veggie) on the International Space Station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timber Tracking</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Timber Tracking View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Do you care about healthy forests? You can apply to join this project if you are a hiker, a birder, a biker, a forager, or a tree lover to explore the hardwood forests of the eastern and central United States in search of black walnut trees!.
One of the most valuable hardwood species in the United States, black walnut trees are threatened by timber poaching across the 30+ states in their range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</guid>
      <description>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR) View the project here.
Overview Traits Across Species’ Ranges is a community science project focused on understanding how variation within plant species influences the size and movement of different pools of elements (e.g., carbon, nitrogen) on the surface of the Earth.
For 2021 we are currently focused on developing partnerships with community scientist groups and individuals to survey patterns of green vs. freshly fallen leaf nutrient concentrations (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
