<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/superwasp-black-hole-hunters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/superwasp-black-hole-hunters/</guid>
      <description>title = &amp;ldquo;SuperWASP: Black Hole Hunters&amp;rdquo; tags = [&amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;astronomy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;physics&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;online&amp;rdquo;] +++
SuperWASP: Black Hole Hunters View the project here.
Overview SuperWASP is the Wide Angle Search for Planets; due to the combination of sky coverage (all latitudes above and below the Galactic plane), observing cadence (how regularly each star is observed) and long temporal baseline (the overall lengths of the lightcurves for each star) the archive is the ideal place to start searching for periodic lensing on the timescales of hours to years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/disabled-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/disabled-access/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/equity-vs-equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/equity-vs-equality/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/financial-inequality-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/financial-inequality-us/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/internet-access-inequity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/internet-access-inequity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/rural-access-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/rural-access-issues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/scientific-access-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/scientific-access-issues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/senior-friendly-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/senior-friendly-content/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/technology-access-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/technology-access-issues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility Defined</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/what-is-accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/this-site-matters/what-is-accessibility/</guid>
      <description>What is accessibility? Wikipedia:
My favorite one-page summary: https://www.seewritehear.com/learn/what-is-accessibility/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Asteroids</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/active-asteroids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/active-asteroids/</guid>
      <description>Active Asteroids View the project here.
Overview Active Asteroids &amp;ndash; asteroids with comet-like activity such as tails &amp;ndash; are poorly understood in part because so few of these objects have been found. At the time of this project launch, fewer than 30 active asteroids have been found since 1949. Finding more active asteroids will enable scientists to study these enigmatic objects as a population. The implications for science and engineering are far-reaching, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Health</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</guid>
      <description>Addressing Health View the project here.
Overview Why did the UK&amp;rsquo;s Post Office employees in the nineteenth century retire from work? Some reached retirement age but many had to end their careers early because of ill health. Be a part of this Wellcome-funded project to find out what Post Office workers&#39; lives tell us about the history of health and wellbeing in the Victorian period. Transcribe the records of their career histories from images of documents held at the Postal Museum, London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Africa Rainfall Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/africa-rainfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/africa-rainfall/</guid>
      <description>Africa Rainfall Project View the project here.
Overview In sub-Saharan Africa, 95 percent of agriculture depends on rainfall, which makes accurate weather forecasts absolutely crucial. However, because rainfall in this area is often localized—sometimes almost at the level of one farm—it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to forecast accurately with satellite data, which show larger weather patterns.
Through the Africa Rainfall Project, researchers at Delft University of Technology will create high-resolution computer simulations of localized rainstorms in sub-Saharan Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents of Enslavement</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/agents-of-enslavement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/agents-of-enslavement/</guid>
      <description>Agents of Enslavement View the project here.
Overview Agents of Enslavement? is a research project, which seeks to explore the ways in which colonial newspapers in the Caribbean facilitated and challenged the practice of slavery.
It also seeks to identify the networks and voices of enslaved people hidden within these newspapers.
These crowdsourcing tasks are integral to both these aims as your help will create new datasets for analysis.
One of the goals of this project is to create a database of enslaved people identified within these newspapers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI4Mars</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ai4mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ai4mars/</guid>
      <description>AI4Mars View the project here.
Overview We need YOUR help to make future Mars rovers safer!
By participating in this project, you will help improve the rovers’ ability to identify different, sometimes dangerous terrain - an essential skill for autonomous exploration!
You’ll be using your superior cognitive and artistic abilities to label images from the Curiosity Rover, collectively creating the first open-source navigation-classification dataset of the Red Planet. It will be used - like the cityscapes dataset - by teams to train rovers to understand Martian environments, laying the way for future missions to unlock the secrets of our nearest neighbor!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality Citizen Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air Quality Citizen Science View the project here.
Overview Are you interested in helping in this NASA-funded science project? Do you have interest in understanding more about the air quality in your neighborhood? Would you like to measure air quality near your home or place of work? Have you been intrigued by the type of data that NASA collects from their satellites? Then this is the perfect opportunity for you to get involved!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amicable Pairs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/amicable-pairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/amicable-pairs/</guid>
      <description>Amicable Pairs View the project here.
Overview Though mathematics is not an experimental science, mathematicians often look for examples to test conjectures (which they then hope to prove). As the number of examples increases, so does (in a sense) their understanding of the distribution.
The goal is to collect all amicable numbers up to a very large limit. This data will facilitate theoretical research in the field: 1, 2, 3 to name a few examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancestry® World Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ancestry-world-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ancestry-world-archives/</guid>
      <description>Ancestry® World Archives View the project here.
Overview The Ancestry® World Archives Project is volunteers from around the world creating searchable record indexes from digitized records. We gather historical records and scan them into our system. You look at the records and type out what you see (so that the facts in the records become searchable). The index you create is added to Ancestry’s free collections and is accessible to anyone who wants to search it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audubon Christmas Bird Count</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/audubon-bird-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/audubon-bird-count/</guid>
      <description>Audubon Christmas Bird Count View the project here.
Overview The Christmas Bird Count occurs December 14 to January 5 every year.
Frank Chapman and 26 other conservationists initiated the Christmas Bird Count (CBC) as a way of promoting conservation by counting, rather than hunting, birds on Christmas Day of 1900. Some counts have been running every year since then and the CBC now happens in over 20 countries in the western hemisphere!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurorasaurus</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</guid>
      <description>Aurorasaurus View the project here.
Overview Aurorasaurus is the first and only citizen science initiative that tracks auroras around the world via reports on our website and social media. All aurora-related tweets and reports are placed on the Aurorasaurus.org map. We then ask people to log in and verify the tweets or reports. Each verified report serves as a valuable data point for scientists to analyze and incorporate into space weather models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Citizen Science NL</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/cs-nederlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/cs-nederlands/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Citizen Science NL View the project here.
Overview A list of awesome Citizen Science projects from the Netherlands with additional information such as duration, organizations, and links to resources.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</guid>
      <description>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count View the project here.
Overview Every year, thousands of seals and sea lions haul out on Año Nuevo Island to give birth, molt, and rest. The secluded shores of the island make a perfect spot for northern elephant seal and California sea lion mothers to give birth and nurse their pups. Researchers at the University of California, Santa Cruz are interested in tracking the number of animals that haul out onto the island&amp;rsquo;s beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backyard Worlds: Planet 9</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/backyard-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/backyard-worlds/</guid>
      <description>Backyard Worlds: Planet 9 View the project here.
Overview Is there a large planet at the fringes of our solar system awaiting discovery, a world astronomers call Planet Nine? We’re looking for this planet and for new brown dwarfs in the backyard of the solar system using data from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer (WISE) mission. But we need your help!
Finding these dim objects requires combing through the images by eye to distinguish moving celestial bodies from ghosts and other artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents View the project here.
Overview Help turn our collection of 17th-19th century handwritten documents relating to Maine&amp;rsquo;s land history into text that may be more easily read, keyword searchable, and accessed by students, teachers, and historians.
Maine Historical Society received a grant in the summer of 2020 from the National Endowment for the Humanities to fully digitized three significant land collections covering 1625-1893. In addition to digitization, Maine Historical is making an effort to transcribe these collections for easier access to their historic content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bloomWatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/bloomwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/bloomwatch/</guid>
      <description>bloomWatch View the project here.
Overview Do you notice that a lake suddenly turned the color of pea soup or a blue-green paint spill? Or do you see green clumps, flakes or filaments floating in a lake?
Blooms in fresh waterbodies are commonly due to cyanobacteria, which have the potential to produce toxins that affect humans, pets, and our ecosystems.
State and local officials can’t be watching every lake at all times!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOINC</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/boinc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/boinc/</guid>
      <description>BOINC View the project here.
Overview BOINC lets you help cutting-edge science research using your computer. The BOINC app, running on your computer, downloads scientific computing jobs and runs them invisibly in the background. It&amp;rsquo;s easy and safe. About 30 science projects use BOINC. They investigate diseases, study climate change, discover pulsars, and do many other types of scientific research.
The BOINC and Science United projects are located at the University of California, Berkeley and are supported by the National Science Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOINC@TACC</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/boinc-at-tacc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/boinc-at-tacc/</guid>
      <description>BOINC@TACC View the project here.
Overview BOINC@TACC is a project based on the Volunteer Computing (VC) model. It helps TACC/XSEDE researchers in running applications from a wide range of scientific domains (such as, aerospace engineering, computational biology, and earthquake engineering) on the laptops, desktops, tablets, or cloud-based Virtual Machines (VMs) owned by volunteers.
Volunteers can help scientific research by signing up for the BOINC@TACC project and allowing it to run applications on their computers and VMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bursts from Space</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/bursts-from-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/bursts-from-space/</guid>
      <description>Bursts from Space View the project here.
Overview Fast Radio Bursts are massive bursts of energy we see from across half the universe. We call them Fast Radio Bursts because that&amp;rsquo;s what we see - a brief millisecond &amp;lsquo;burst&amp;rsquo; of energy in radio waves.
What are they? We don&amp;rsquo;t know! But every burst we find tells us a little more about what&amp;rsquo;s happening. We need to find these bursts!
Sounds easy right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buzzy Bee - African Canopy Pollinators</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/buzzy-bee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/buzzy-bee/</guid>
      <description>Buzzy Bee - African Canopy Pollinators View the project here.
Overview Help us identify insect pollinators of large African timber trees!
In order to define sustainable exploitation practices, it is necessary to understand regeneration cycles of timber tree species. The purpose of this research is to describe the relationship between pollen dispersal distances, floral traits, and pollinators of several timber species, as well as document the size and composition of pollinators communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</guid>
      <description>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field View the project here.
Overview The British Library wildlife and environmental sounds archive was established in 1969 by the ornithologist Patrick Seller and the BBC radio producer Jeffrey Boswell, with the endeavour to create a national collection that can document, preserve and share the sounds of nature for future generations to study and enjoy. Since then we have amassed over 6.5 million recordings and are now one of the most comprehensive collections in the world, used by scientists and amateur naturalists alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Urban Birds Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/celebrate-urban-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/celebrate-urban-birds/</guid>
      <description>Celebrate Urban Birds Project View the project here.
Overview From the Cornell Lab of Ornithology.
 Learn to identify your regional birds. Choose your birdwatching area. Watch birds for 10 minutes a day for 3 days. Report your results!  Our vision is to embrace community-led scientific research and programming and promote inclusive, accessible, and equitable birdwatching for all. We believe that birds have the power to connect us — as long as we intentionally value and center the power of equitable co-creation in birdwatching, monitoring, and conservation projects, and focus on culture through local leadership, creativity, and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance View the project here.
Overview The Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance is a group of researchers from across the Smithsonian and local universities, with a goal to study and educate the public about North American River Otters in the Chesapeake Bay. We need your help to figure out where these otters are in the Chesapeake Bay!
Very little to no research has been done regarding the numbers, health, and populations of otters in the Chesapeake Bay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chesapeake Water Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-water-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-water-watch/</guid>
      <description>Chesapeake Water Watch View the project here.
Overview We are aiming to improve how effective satellites are at monitoring the health of Chesapeake Bay by comparing information collected from satellites with information collected by researchers and citizen scientists on the ground. Right now, NASA&amp;rsquo;s cutting-edge satellites, provide a unique capability to capture water quality changes in areas that are economically and environmentally important.
There is a long history of public engagement in water quality monitoring in fresh and coastal ecosystems, with volunteer collected data being used as part of monitoring for the US Clean Water Act (Jollymore et al 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago EcoFlora Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Help us track native and non-native plant species in Chicagoland.
Now more than ever we need to understand urban flora-both native and invasive species. The Chicago EcoFlora project is collecting observations of plants in Cook County, Illinois to learn more about local plant life and contribute to conservation planning. With your help, we will collect data on important native species and troublesome new invaders that call our city home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimp and See</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</guid>
      <description>Chimp and See View the project here.
Overview Studies of human evolution often focus on the fossils and artifacts left by our early ancestors. However, we can also make inferences about human origins by studying our closest living relatives: chimpanzees, the great apes that live across equatorial Africa. Because humans and chimps are so closely related, patterns in chimpanzee behavior may tell us quite a bit about how the earliest hominids lived and evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Endo</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Endo View the project here.
Overview In order to study a disease, we need to know what it looks like. When it comes to endometriosis, there are many different ways in which the disease can present itself in patients. There is a disconnect between how doctors think about the disease and what patients experience on a daily basis. Bridging this gap is critical to further research on endometriosis. Citizen Endo will use a series of studies to better understand the disease from the perspective of patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program View the project here.
Overview The key to the next life-saving biomedical discovery might be living right below your feet. Dozens of fungi can occupy a single handful of soil and many of them are adept at making new compounds called natural products. These remarkable molecules hold tremendous promise for treating human diseases.
It only takes a few minutes to help by collecting a scoop of soil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>citizenscience.gov</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/citizenscience-gov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/citizenscience-gov/</guid>
      <description>citizenscience.gov View the project here.
Overview NOTE: When viewing the catalog page, make sure you set the View by Status filter to only &amp;ldquo;Active&amp;rdquo; projects!
CitizenScience.gov is an official government website designed to accelerate the use of crowdsourcing and citizen science across the U.S. government. The site provides a portal to three key components: a catalog of federally supported citizen science projects, a toolkit to assist federal practitioners with designing and maintaining their projects, and a gateway to a community of hundreds of citizen science practitioners and coordinators across government as called for in the Crowdsourcing and Citizen Science Act of 2016 (15 USC 3724).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>climateprediction.net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/climateprediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/climateprediction/</guid>
      <description>climateprediction.net View the project here.
Overview Climateprediction.net is a volunteer computing climate modeling project.
We run climate models on people’s home computers to help answer questions about how climate change is affecting our world, now and in the future. Evidence of how our climate is changing is vital to encourage investment in reducing greenhouse gas emissions, as well as coping with inevitable change.
You can help discover how the climate could look by running our free software on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collatz Conjecture</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/collatz-conjecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/collatz-conjecture/</guid>
      <description>Collatz Conjecture View the project here.
Overview Collatz is a research project that uses Internet-connected computers to do research in mathematics. You can contribute to our research by running a free program on your computer.
Collatz Conjecture is based in Wood Dale, Illinois. It is a privately managed BOINC project attempting to disprove the Collatz Conjecture. For more information about the Collatz Conjecture, check out the Wikipedia Collatz page. The Collatz Conjecture project makes use of the parity sequence optimization and runs on Linux, Windows, and OS X and can utilize CPUs as well as AMD, nVidia, and Intel graphics cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cocorahs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cocorahs/</guid>
      <description>Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network View the project here.
Overview CoCoRaHS is an acronym for the Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network. CoCoRaHS is a unique, non-profit, community-based network of volunteers of all ages and backgrounds working together to measure and map precipitation (rain, hail and snow). By using low-cost measurement tools, stressing training and education, and utilizing an interactive Web-site, our aim is to provide the highest quality data for natural resource, education and research applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Snow Observations</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/community-snow-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/community-snow-observations/</guid>
      <description>Community Snow Observations (CSO) View the project here.
Overview CSO is a citizen science campaign to measure snow. Make your backcountry travels count! We need your help measuring snow depths in mountain places too vast for researchers to monitor.
Your observations help us predict snow conditions and improve safety for mountain travelers.
This project aims to improve our understanding of snow depth variability in mountainous regions. We need community-based observers, including backcountry professionals and recreationists, to help gather snow observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/about/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/about/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Contribute via email If you notice any typos, know a project that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been added yet, or have suggestions for the website, email me with all the relevant information and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back with you as soon as I can.
Contribute via GitHub 🌟 If you&amp;rsquo;re new to using GitHub, I have a guide just for you written here!
Full contribution guidelines and instructions are available on GitHub in CONTRIBUTING.md.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological jellyfish</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmological-jellyfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmological-jellyfish/</guid>
      <description>Cosmological jellyfish View the project here.
Overview We are a group of researchers at the Max Planck Institute of Astronomy using simulations of the Universe to study the various ways in which galaxies in the Universe evolve, both through their own internal processes, and under the influence of their environment.
Galaxies in the Universe can come in many forms and shapes.
Some of them can show very asymmetric distributions, with long tails of material that depart from their main body made of stars and cosmic gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmology@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/cosmology-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/cosmology-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Cosmology@Home View the project here.
Overview Cosmology@Home lets you volunteer your spare computer time (like when your screen saver is on) to help better understand our universe by searching for the range of theoretical models that agree with cutting-edge cosmological and particle physics data.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID.SI</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/covid/</guid>
      <description>CITIZEN SCIENCE AND THE FIGHT AGAINST THE CORONAVIRUS (COVID.SI) View the project here.
Overview “CITIZEN SCIENCE AND THE FIGHT AGAINST THE CORONAVIRUS” is an open project by a collective of good-willed researchers and volunteers, who with to contribute a stone in the mosaic of the full picture of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19, with the sum of our work, knowledge and experience. The group is lead by dr. Črtomir Podlipnik and dr. Marko Jukić, experts with years of experience in computer supported molecular modelling, pharmaceutical chemistry and chemo/bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cyanoScope</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cyanoscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cyanoscope/</guid>
      <description>cyanoScope View the project here.
Overview cyanoScope uses modern technologies and a social approach to learn more about cyanobacteria and their distribution. By participating you will be helping scientists and water resource managers gain information on the occurrence of cyanobacteria in surface waters.
We will use submitted reports to map the spatial distribution and seasonal occurrence of cyanobacteria in lakes, ponds, and reservoirs.
Collect cyanobacteria:
 collect cyanobacteria with a net tow, prepare your microscope slides, identify cyanobacteria found in your sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Energy Explorers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dark-energy-explorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dark-energy-explorers/</guid>
      <description>Dark Energy Explorers View the project here.
Overview The Hobby-Eberly Dark Energy Experiment (HETDEX) is designed to find over one million galaxies that are 9 billion to 11 billion light-years away, yielding the largest map of the universe ever produced. The map will allow HETDEX astronomers to measure how fast the universe was expanding at different times in its history. Changes in the expansion rate will reveal the role of dark energy at different epochs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davy Notebooks Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>Davy Notebooks Project View the project here.
Overview Help us to transcribe the manuscript notebooks of Sir Humphry Davy – one of the most significant and famous figures in the scientific and literary culture of early nineteenth-century Britain, Europe, and America.
Davy’s scientific accomplishments include: conducting pioneering research into the physiological effects of nitrous oxide (often called ‘laughing gas’); isolating seven chemical elements (magnesium, calcium, potassium, sodium, strontium, barium, and boron) and establishing the elemental status of chlorine and iodine; inventing a miners’ safety lamp; developing the electrochemical protection of the copper sheeting of Royal Navy vessels; conserving the Herculaneum papyri; and writing an influential text on agricultural chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Bay Horseshoe Crab Survey</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/delaware-bay-crabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/delaware-bay-crabs/</guid>
      <description>Delaware Bay Horseshoe Crab Survey View the project here.
Overview The Horseshoe Crab, Limulus polyphemus, visits the Delaware Bay Shore each year for spawning purposes. Through the work of volunteers, the spawning population is recorded to study the American Horseshoe Crab.
In 1990, the first organized survey of spawning horseshoe crabs in the Delaware Bay began. Now, every May and June during the full and new moon evening high tides, volunteers annually donate their time to count crabs on the beaches of the Delaware Bay in both Delaware and New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disk Detective</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/disk-detective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/disk-detective/</guid>
      <description>Disk Detective View the project here.
Overview NASA&amp;rsquo;s WISE mission is surveying the whole sky at infrared wavelengths. Here at Disk Detective, you&amp;rsquo;ll examine data from WISE and other surveys to search for dusty debris disks similar to our asteroid belt, and gas-rich primordial disks, the birthplaces of planets.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY History</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</guid>
      <description>DIY History View the project here.
Overview DIY History lets you do it yourself to help make historic artifacts easier to use. Our digital library holds hundreds of thousands of items—much more than library staff could ever catalog alone, so we&amp;rsquo;re appealing to the public to help out by attaching text in the form of transcriptions, tags, and comments. Through &amp;ldquo;crowdsourcing,&amp;rdquo; or engaging volunteers to contribute effort toward large-scale goals, these mass quantities of digitized artifacts become searchable, allowing researchers to quickly seek out specific information, and general users to browse and enjoy the materials more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragonfly Mercury Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/dragonfly-mercury/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/dragonfly-mercury/</guid>
      <description>Dragonfly Mercury Project View the project here.
Overview The Dragonfly Mercury Project engages citizen scientists such as students and teachers in the collection of juvenile dragonflies, also known as dragonfly larvae, from national parks for mercury analysis.
Experience the Dragonfly Mercury Project by watching this short video. Then, grab some rubber boots and a sampling net and join park rangers as we search for juvenile dragonflies! Park rangers and enthusiastic volunteer citizen scientists collect many times the number of dragonflies from many more parks than would be possible for scientists alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drones for Ducks</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/drones-for-ducks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/drones-for-ducks/</guid>
      <description>Drones for Ducks View the project here.
Overview Migrating birds like ducks, geese, and cranes are important parts of many ecosystems along their seasonal travel routes. To ensure there are enough resources to go around, managers of public lands in the Southwestern United States conduct waterfowl surveys to know how many birds to expect over winter. Traditional methods of counting birds out in the field present a lot of challenges and may not be very precise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EarthEcho Water Challenge</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/earthecho-water-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/earthecho-water-challenge/</guid>
      <description>EarthEcho Water Challenge View the project here.
Overview The EarthEcho Water Challenge (formerly World Water Monitoring Challenge) is an international program that runs annually from March 22 (the United Nations World Water Day) through December and equips anyone to protect the water resources we depend on every day. The EarthEcho Water Challenge builds public awareness and involvement in protecting water resources around the world by engaging citizens to conduct basic monitoring of their local waterbodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBird</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/ebird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/ebird/</guid>
      <description>eBird View the project here.
Overview eBird transforms the global birding community’s passion for birds into a powerful resource for research, conservation, and education. Your sightings contribute to hundreds of conservation decisions and peer-reviewed papers, thousands of student projects, and help inform bird research worldwide.
eBird is among the world’s largest biodiversity-related science projects, with more than 100 million bird sightings contributed annually by eBirders around the world and an average participation growth rate of approximately 20% year over year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einstein@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/einstein-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/einstein-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Einstein@Home View the project here.
Overview Einstein@Home is a World Year of Physics 2005 and an International Year of Astronomy 2009 project. It is supported by the American Physical Society (APS), the US National Science Foundation (NSF), the Max Planck Society (MPG), and a number of international organizations.
Einstein@Home uses your computer&amp;rsquo;s idle time to search for weak astrophysical signals from spinning neutron stars (often called pulsars) using data from the LIGO gravitational-wave detectors, the Arecibo radio telescope, and the Fermi gamma-ray satellite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eMammal</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/emammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/emammal/</guid>
      <description>eMammal View the project here.
Overview eMammal is a data management system and archive for camera trap research projects. This cyber-tool is designed to not only be useful to scientists, but also to the citizen scientists who aid scientists in photo collection. Camera trappers use our software to look at pictures, identify animals and upload them for review and archive at the Smithsonian. These data then help address important conservation-related questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etch A Cell - ER</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/etch-a-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/etch-a-cell/</guid>
      <description>Etch A Cell - ER View the project here.
Overview Help us study one of the biggest structures found in your cells - the Endoplasmic Reticulum.
In Etch A Cell - ER we need you to help us study the Endoplasmic Reticulum (ER) of a cell. The ER is often one of the biggest structures (organelles) in the cell, and is involved in lots of important cellular processes including the production and transport of new proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eterna</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eterna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eterna/</guid>
      <description>Eterna View the project here.
Overview Design molecular medicines by solving puzzles!
Eterna is a game that allows players to design RNAs by solving puzzles. Each puzzle represents a target RNA shape or a set of design requirements. Players design the pattern of bases they think will best meet the requirements. Scientists then create the molecules the players have designed and test them in the lab. The lab results are returned to the players, who can use them to improve their designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Name Counts</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/every-name-counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/every-name-counts/</guid>
      <description>Every Name Counts View the project here.
Overview With the initiative #everynamecounts, the Arolsen Archives aim to establish a digital memorial to the people persecuted by the Nazis. Future generations should be able to remember the names and identities of the victims and put faces to history.
Thousands of volunteers are contributing to this first major digital memorial, which will enable people all over the world to access and search the data themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyes of the Reef Hawaii</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/eyes-of-the-reef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/eyes-of-the-reef/</guid>
      <description>Eyes of the Reef Hawaii View the project here.
Overview The Eyes of the Reef Network is a volunteer member-based organization developed to increase public awareness and engage communities in the monitoring and reporting of coral bleaching and disease, marine invasive species, Crown-of-Thorn Sea Star (COTS) outbreaks and other reef diseases.
The statewide network is the first tier of a rapid response protocol developed by the Division of Aquatic Resources and the Climate Change and Marine Disease Local Action Strategy, implemented by Reef Check Hawai‘i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyewire</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</guid>
      <description>Eyewire View the project here.
Overview Eyewire is a game to map the brain. Anyone can play and you need no scientific background. Hundreds of thousands of people from around the world already do. Together we are mapping the 3D structure of neurons and advancing our quest to understand ourselves.
By joining Eyewire, you can help map the connectome, starting with connections between retinal neurons. Eyewire gameplay advances neuroscience by helping researchers discover how neurons connect and network to process information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireballs in the Sky</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/fireballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/fireballs/</guid>
      <description>Fireballs in the Sky View the project here.
Overview Fireballs in the Sky is an innovative citizen science program that connects the public with the research of the Desert Fireball Network.
Meteorites have the potential to show us how the Solar System formed and evolved, coming from the very first bodies to be created. They act as a snapshot in time, holding the minerals that came from their parent bodies and are unchanged as they hurtle towards Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix It&#43; Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</guid>
      <description>Fix It+ Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting View the project here.
Overview Help the American Archive of Public Broadcasting fix computer-generated transcripts from thousands of historic public broadcasting programs from across the country.
We need you to help ensure that public media remains accessible—not just today&amp;rsquo;s broadcasts, but the archive all the way back to the beginning.
FIX IT+ users can correct transcripts for any of the historic programs available in the AAPB&amp;rsquo;s Online Reading Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating Forests</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/floating-forests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/floating-forests/</guid>
      <description>Floating Forests View the project here.
Overview Welcome to Floating Forests, where you can help us uncover the history of Giant Kelp forests around the globe. Most life on the seafloor can only be sampled by SCUBA divers or dredging up samples from the deep. This kind of data requires a ton of (really fun) effort to collect, but it means we’re limited to places we can get to! Given the worldwide distribution of kelp, we need your help to track it across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folding@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Install our software to become a citizen scientist and contribute your compute power to help fight global health threats like COVID19, Alzheimer’s Disease, and cancer!
Folding@Home began in October 2000 in the lab of Dr. Vijay Pande at Stanford University. Since 2019, the project has been in the hands of Dr. Gregory Bowman, a former Pande Lab graduate student. In addition to the numerous scientists who have worked on the project over the years, F@h has been supported by thousands of dedicated volunteers who have enabled outstanding scientific research and computational achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foldit</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/foldit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/foldit/</guid>
      <description>Foldit View the project here.
Overview Foldit is a revolutionary crowdsourcing computer game enabling you to contribute to important scientific research.
Knowing the structure of a protein is key to understanding how it works and to targeting it with drugs. A small protein can consist of 100 amino acids, while some human proteins can be huge (1000 amino acids). The number of different ways even a small protein can fold is astronomical because there are so many degrees of freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom on the Move</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview We need your help to turn our collection of handwritten correspondence between anti-slavery activists in the 19th century into texts that can be more easily read and researched by students, teachers, historians, and big data applications.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frog Find</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frog-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frog-find/</guid>
      <description>Frog Find View the project here.
Overview Help us find threatened frogs in NSW National Parks. Understanding where they live helps us improve their chance of survival in the future.
Frogs need your help! Following bushfires, floods and a host of other threats including water pollution and disease, our frogs really have their back against the wall.
Frog Find uses frog sounds recorded from streams, ponds and wetlands to work out who is calling where.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FrogSong</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frogsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frogsong/</guid>
      <description>FrogSong View the project here.
Overview With your help, researchers at James Cook University and Monash University aim to develop automated techniques to identify frog calls in very long audio recordings. This will allow us to understand the environmental drivers of frog chorusing, detect changes in frog communities through time, determine how species partition the acoustic space, and much more!
This project contains audio recordings collected by the Australian Acoustic Observatory at sites around Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FrogWatch USA</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/frogwatch-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/frogwatch-usa/</guid>
      <description>FrogWatch USA View the project here.
Overview FrogWatch USA™ is a citizen science program of the Association of Zoos and Aquariums that invites individuals and families to learn about the wetlands in their communities and help conserve amphibians by reporting data on the calls of local frogs and toads.
Volunteers are trained to collect information about the calls from frogs and toads during the monitoring season of February through August.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerasim@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gerasim-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gerasim-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Gerasim@Home View the project here.
Overview The project uses internet-connected computers to do research in discrete mathematics and logic control.
The current goal: testing and comparison of heuristic methods for getting separations of parallel algorithms working in the CAD system for designing logic control systems.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</guid>
      <description>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey View the project here.
Overview Many invasive species, like Garlic Mustard (Alliaria petiolata), are threatening the world’s natural resources, but the abundance of invasive species can vary dramatically over space and time. Scientists still do not have a good understanding of why this is so.
Through large-scale sampling, scientists can identify areas that differ in the intensity of invasion and try to understand why these differences exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globe at Night</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-at-night/</guid>
      <description>Globe at Night View the project here.
Overview Globe at Night is an international citizen-science campaign to raise public awareness of the impact of light pollution by inviting citizen-scientists to measure &amp;amp; submit their night sky brightness observations. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get involved - all you need is computer or smart phone &amp;amp; follow these 6 Simple Steps!
The November 2021 campaign is using the Constellation Perseus. Check out the dates and constellations for our other campaigns during all 12 months of 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLOBE Observer</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</guid>
      <description>GLOBE Observer View the project here.
Overview When you download the GLOBE Observer app, you join the community of The GLOBE Program - citizen scientists, students, and teachers in 120+ countries around the world contributing to Earth system science research.
Your observations:
 Help monitor the conditions of clouds, water (especially as a habitat for mosquitoes), plants (trees and other land cover), and see change over time. Can be used to help interpret NASA and other satellite data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUGRID.net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gpugrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gpugrid/</guid>
      <description>GPUGRID.net View the project here.
Overview GPUGRID.net is a distributed computing infrastructure devoted to biomedical research. Thanks to the contribution of volunteers, GPUGRID scientists can perform molecular simulations to understand the function of proteins in health and disease.
This is a volunteer distributed computing project for biomedical research from the Universitat Pompeu Fabra in Barcelona (Spain). GPUGRID is made of many graphics cards (GPUs) joined together to deliver high-performance all-atom biomolecular simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GWitchHunters</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/gwitchhunters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/gwitchhunters/</guid>
      <description>GWitchHunters View the project here.
Overview GWITCHHUNTERS aims at improving the performance of current Gravitational Wave detectors in the experimental study of the Universe. Such instruments have reached extraordinary sensitivities to accomplish this task, but they are also very delicate and prone to spurious disturbances of non-astrophysical origin. Our goal is to better understand their disturbances and find new solutions to them.
We are a team of researchers devoted to this very challenging task, involving state of the art technologies and analysis methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Stop TB</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/help-stop-tb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/help-stop-tb/</guid>
      <description>Help Stop TB View the project here.
Overview Tuberculosis (TB) is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most dangerous diseases, and has plagued humans for thousands of years. About one-third of the world&amp;rsquo;s population harbors the TB bacterium, with 1.5 million people dying in 2014 alone, and the World Health Organization now ranks TB alongside HIV as the world&amp;rsquo;s deadliest infectious disease. Through Help Stop TB, researchers are using World Community Grid to help fight this deadly disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</guid>
      <description>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service View the project here.
Overview Transcribing a hundred years of seafarer&amp;rsquo;s medical data from the Dreadnought Seamen&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in Greenwich, 1826-1930.
&amp;lsquo;HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service&amp;rsquo;, refers to the records of the Dreadnought Seamen’s Hospital at Greenwich. This was the main clinical site of the Seamen’s Hospital Society (now Seafarer’s Hospital Society), founded with the philanthropic mission of providing relief to sick and injured seafarers of all nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use this site</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/about/how-to-use-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/about/how-to-use-this-site/</guid>
      <description>Project Delve is nice and simple. All content is viewable from one single menu, so you can&amp;rsquo;t get lost.
Sidebar/Menu Sections If you&amp;rsquo;re using a desktop computer, you will see a blue sidebar on the left side of your screen. If you&amp;rsquo;re on mobile, this sidebar will be tucked into a drop-down menu, which you can find by clicking the symbol with three horizontal lines in the top left corner of your device&amp;rsquo;s screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iberian Camera Trap Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/iberian-camera-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/iberian-camera-trap/</guid>
      <description>Iberian Camera Trap Project View the project here.
Overview Wildlife monitoring is often based on outdated protocols. However, advances in technology have paved the way for optimizing data collection and profusing cutting-edge analytical methods. Our cameras are placed in one of the most important protected areas in Europe, the Parque Nacional de Doñana (South Spain). Your classifications will serve to train an artificial intelligence algorithm to do the same with an exorbitant amount of images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</guid>
      <description>iNaturalist View the project here.
Overview One of the world’s most popular nature apps, iNaturalist helps you identify the plants and animals around you. Get connected with a community of over a million scientists and naturalists who can help you learn more about nature! What’s more, by recording and sharing your observations, you’ll create research quality data for scientists working to better understand and protect nature. iNaturalist is a joint initiative by the California Academy of Sciences and the National Geographic Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Wild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</guid>
      <description>Instant Wild View the project here.
Overview ZSL’s Instant Wild empowers you to take part in vital conservation work, bringing you LIVE images and videos from amazing locations all around the world. By identifying the animals in each image, you are contributing to conservation and making a positive impact on the future for wildlife.
Available both as a smartphone app and online at instantwild.zsl.org, Instant Wild mobilises people power to scale up important animal monitoring work, which helps scientists to protect wildlife and secure a richer biodiversity for all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iThena.Computational</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/ithena/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/ithena/</guid>
      <description>iThena.Computational View the project here.
Overview The project is brand-new as of early November 2021, and does not yet have a description posted. More info will be added as it becomes available.
The previous iThena project iThena.Measurements is in a closed beta phase.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iWitness Pollution Map</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/iwitness-pollution-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/iwitness-pollution-map/</guid>
      <description>iWitness Pollution Map View the project here.
Overview The iWitness Pollution map is a tool that communities can use to document pollution in their neighborhoods. By calling or texting to (504) 272 – 7645 (27 27 OIL), residents can crowdsource pollution and tell the world about the bad smells, flares and noise from the neighboring petrochemical plant.
We first deployed the map in 2010 in the days after the BP Disaster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LabintheWild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/labinthewild/</guid>
      <description>LabintheWild View the project here.
Overview LabintheWild tests your abilities and preferences. At the end of each experiment, you will see a page with your personalized feedback, which lets you compare yourself and your performance to other people around the world.
By participating, you contribute to research on people&amp;rsquo;s similarities and differences and help improve users&#39; experience when interacting with technology. We believe that research should be done in collaboration with people—people like you from all over the world who are interested in learning about themselves and helping research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp; Satellites</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/locss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/locss/</guid>
      <description>Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp;amp; Satellites (LOCSS) View the project here.
Overview The Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp;amp; Satellites project seeks to better understand how the quantity of water in lakes is changing.
Are lake volumes affected most by precipitation, water table height, evaporation or some other factors? Knowing the answer to this question will help us better understand how water moves in relation to these lakes and the surrounding land and what that may mean for lake users and these ecosystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landslides @ NASA</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/landslides-at-nasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/landslides-at-nasa/</guid>
      <description>Landslides @ NASA View the project here.
Overview NASA scientists are building an open global inventory of landslides and we need your help! Knowing where and when landslides occur can help communities worldwide prepare for these disasters. Become a citizen scientist and you can help inform decisions that could save lives and property today.
Landslides cause billions of dollars in infrastructural damage and thousands of deaths every year worldwide. Data on past landslide events guides future disaster prevention, but to date we do not have a global picture of exactly when and where landslides occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leafsnap</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</guid>
      <description>leafmolester View the project here.
Overview Leafsnap turns users into citizen scientists, automatically sharing images, species identifications, and geo-coded stamps of species locations with a community of scientists who will use the stream of data to map and monitor the ebb and flow of flora.
Leafsnap is a series of electronic field guides being developed by researchers from Columbia University, the University of Maryland, and the Smithsonian Institution. The free mobile apps use visual recognition software to help identify tree species from photographs of their leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LHC@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/lhc-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/lhc-at-home/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;LHC@Home&amp;rdquo; View the project here.
Overview The Large Hadron Collider @ Home project from CERN is a volunteer computing project that uses Internet-connected computers to advance Particle and Accelerator Physics. Participate by downloading and running a free program on your computer.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library of Congress: By the People</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</guid>
      <description>Library of Congress: By the People View the project here.
Overview Help transcribe Library of Congress documents. Volunteers create and review transcriptions to improve search, access, and discovery of these pages from history.
By the People invites you to transcribe, review, and tag digitized pages from the Library’s collections. Everyone is welcome to take part! Volunteer-created transcriptions improve search, readability, and access to handwritten and typed documents for everyone, including people who are not fully sighted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Environmental Observer (LEO) Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leo-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leo-network/</guid>
      <description>Local Environmental Observer (LEO) Network View the project here.
Overview The Local Environmental Observer (LEO) Network is a group of local observers and topic experts who share knowledge about unusual animal, environment, and weather events. With LEO, you can connect with others in your community, share observations, raise awareness, and find answers about significant environmental events. You can also engage with topic experts in many different organizations and become part of a broader observer community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macdonald Dictionary</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/macdonald-dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/macdonald-dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Macdonald Dictionary View the project here.
Overview George Ranald Macdonald (1891 - 1967) was a farmer and local historian in Canterbury, New Zealand. After retiring he began volunteering at Canterbury Museum. When Museum visitors mentioned there was a need for a biographical dictionary of colonial personalities to help with research, Macdonald volunteered for the project.
Compiled by Macdonald between 1952 and 1964, and comprised of over 12000 index cards with biographical information on over 22000 people, the dictionary took about 12 years to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Cancer Markers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mapping-cancer-markers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mapping-cancer-markers/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Mapping Cancer Markers on World Community Grid aims to identify the markers associated with various types of cancer. The project is analyzing millions of data points collected from thousands of healthy and cancerous patient tissue samples. These include tissues with lung, ovarian, prostate, pancreatic and breast cancers. By comparing these different data points, researchers aim to identify patterns of markers for different cancers and correlate them with different outcomes, including responsiveness to various treatment options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAPPPD (Penguins!)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/mapping-penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/mapping-penguins/</guid>
      <description>Mapping Application for Penguin Populations and Projected Dynamics (MAPPPD) View the project here.
Overview Help us locate new colonies by exploring high resolution Google earth imagery. Over the last several years, penguin biologists have been working hard to find all the penguin colonies in Antarctica using satellite imagery. However, the massive expanse of the continent and the challenges of finding each last penguin colony leave many likely undiscovered. This is where you can help!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the ANZACs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/measuring-anzacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/measuring-anzacs/</guid>
      <description>Measuring the ANZACs View the project here.
Overview The Measuring the ANZACs project brings together an international team of researchers, community connections around New Zealand’s military history from the Auckland War Memorial Museum, and the power of the Zooniverse community to explore, analyze, and digitize original World War I personnel files from Archives New Zealand.
Data gathered from Measuring the ANZACs will be used for three main purposes:
 To create a complete and rich index of persons who served in the New Zealand military in World War I and the South African War (also called the Second Boer War).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/m-a-e-terrae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/m-a-e-terrae/</guid>
      <description>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae View the project here.
Overview Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae (MET - Meteorology of the End of the World) aims to recover weather and oceanic data record in Argentina since at least the beginning of the XIXth Century. The first currently known records date back to 1801. Other than the Oficina Meteorológica Argentina, later Servicio Meteorológico Nacional, many public and private organizations have registered weather data. Argentine Navy ships, lighthouses, railway stations, &amp;ldquo;estancias&amp;rdquo; are among many data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/meteorum-ad-extremum-terrae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/meteorum-ad-extremum-terrae/</guid>
      <description>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae View the project here.
Overview Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae (MET - Meteorology of the End of the World) aims to recover weather and oceanic data record in Argentina since at least the beginning of the XIXth Century. The first currently known records date back to 1801. Other than the Oficina Meteorológica Argentina, later Servicio Meteorológico Nacional, many public and private organizations have registered weather data. Argentine Navy ships, lighthouses, railway stations, &amp;ldquo;estancias&amp;rdquo; are among many data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Coral Reefs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</guid>
      <description>Mexican Coral Reefs View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Mexico’s Pacific Coast is home to some of the world’s most biodiverse coral reefs, underwater communities that support sharks, turtles, and other marine life. They also support human lives by buffering the coastline from intense storms and providing livelihoods from fishing and tourism. Yet these reefs are imperiled by ocean acidification, more frequent and powerful storms due to climate change, and damage from human overuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkweeds and Monarchs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</guid>
      <description>Milkweeds and Monarchs View the project here.
Overview Help preserve the majestic monarch butterfly.
Soaring from Mexico into the United States and Canada, monarch butterflies are searching for one thing: milkweed plants. Monarch butterflies are beautiful, charismatic insects known for their long-distance migration and their reliance on milkweeds (Asclepias species). Milkweeds are the only plants on which monarchs lay their eggs. After the eggs hatch, the caterpillars, also called larvae, eat milkweed leaves to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MilkyWay@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/milkyway-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/milkyway-at-home/</guid>
      <description>MilkyWay@home View the project here.
Overview Milkyway@Home uses the BOINC platform to harness volunteered computing resources, creating a highly accurate three dimensional model of the Milky Way galaxy using data gathered by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. This project enables research in both astroinformatics and computer science.
In computer science, the project is investigating different optimization methods which are resilient to the fault-prone, heterogeneous and asynchronous nature of Internet computing; such as evolutionary and genetic algorithms, as well as asynchronous newton methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/minecraft-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/minecraft-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Minecraft@Home View the project here.
Overview This is a volunteer computing project which allows anyone on the internet to contribute resources to research projects related to Minecraft.
We are an open community seeking to solve some of Minecraft&amp;rsquo;s biggest mysteries. Minecraft@Home enables the study of the fundemental laws of Minecraft to answer unanswered questions regarding the features and true limits of the game.
The project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub is here and project list is viewable here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLC@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mlc-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mlc-at-home/</guid>
      <description>MLC@Home View the project here.
Overview MLC@Home is a distributed computing project dedicated to understanding and interpreting complex machine learning models, with an emphasis on neural networks. It uses the BOINC distributed computing platform. You can find more information on our main website here: https://www.mlcathome.org.
Neural Networks have fuelled a machine learning revolution over the past decade that has led to machines accomplishing amazingly complex tasks. However, these models are largly black boxes: we know they work, but they are so complex (up to hundreds of millions of parameters!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monarch (Butterfly) Larva Monitoring Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/monarch-larva-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/monarch-larva-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Monarch (Butterfly) Larva Monitoring Project View the project here.
Overview The Monarch Larva Monitoring Project (MLMP) is a citizen science project involving volunteers from across the United States and Canada in monarch research. It was developed in 1997 by researchers at the University of Minnesota to collect long-term data on larval monarch populations and milkweed habitat. The project focuses on monarch distribution and abundance during the breeding season in North America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moo! Wrapper</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/moo-wrapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/moo-wrapper/</guid>
      <description>Moo! Wrapper View the project here.
Overview Moo! Wrapper brings together BOINC volunteer computing network resources and the Distributed.net projects. It allows a BOINC Client to participate in the RC5-72 challenge.
Having successfully completed RC5-56 and RC5-64, we are now working on the 72-bit variant of this encryption algorithm! More information is available on the RC5 Project Page.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrafter</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nanocrafter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nanocrafter/</guid>
      <description>Nanocrafter View the project here.
Overview The field of synthetic biology has grown to a multibillion-dollar market as a result of how broad the applications are. From terraforming to fighting viruses! One of the avenues of synthetic biology, and the focus of Nanocrafter, is using synthesized DNA to create biological machines.
But actually building the DNA components in real life isn’t very easy, although the price has gone down drastically. Normally, scientists and researchers work with digital models, which will then have to go through a long process before being accepted for synthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nanoHUB@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/nanohub-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/nanohub-at-home/</guid>
      <description>nanoHUB@Home View the project here.
Overview nanoHUB is a research project, based at nanoHUB.org, that uses Internet-connected computers to do research in nanoscience and nanotechnology. You can contribute to our research by running a free program on your computer.
This project supports over 200 simulation tools deployed at nanoHUB.org. These tools are used for both education and research, and they enable simulations that can run in a few minutes or over several hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s Notebook</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook View the project here.
Overview Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook gathers information on plant and animal phenology across the U.S. to be used for decision-making on local, national and global scales to ensure the continued vitality of our environment.
Scientists alone cannot collect enough data: They need your help. Join more than 15,000 other naturalists across the nation in taking the pulse of our planet. You&amp;rsquo;ll use scientifically-vetted observation guidelines, developed for over 1000 species, to ensure data are useful to researchers and decision-makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood Nestwatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/neighborhood-nestwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/neighborhood-nestwatch/</guid>
      <description>Neighborhood Nestwatch View the project here.
Overview This Smithsonian citizen science program provides an outdoor educational experience for backyard wildlife enthusiasts and underserved youth. Participants contribute to important scientific research by re-sighting banded birds and monitoring nests. The Neighborhood Nestwatch approach features face-to-face interaction on an annual basis between Smithsonian scientists, participants and neighborhood birds. The program takes place in metro-area backyards, as well as at under-resourced schools in cities throughout the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeMO-Net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nemo-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nemo-net/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview NeMO-Net is a single player iPad game where players help NASA classify coral reefs by painting 3D and 2D images of coral. Players can rate the classifications of other players and level up in the food chain as they explore and classify coral reefs and other shallow marine environments and creatures from locations all over the world!
Data from the NeMO-Net game is fed to NASA NeMO-Net, the first neural multi-modal observation and training network for global coral reef assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nest Quest Go: Mourning Doves</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nqg-mourning-doves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nqg-mourning-doves/</guid>
      <description>Nest Quest Go: Mourning Doves View the project here.
Overview Join the Cornell Lab of Ornithology&amp;rsquo;s Citizen-Science Project, NestWatch, in understanding the historical nesting patterns of Mourning Doves. In North America, Mourning Doves are the most abundant and widespread game bird.
While they are hunted in North America, these nest-record cards demonstrate a different kind of hunting: the quest for data!
These nest record cards are a subset of a larger collection of more than 300,000 nest records that NestWatch is working on digitizing and transcribing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nest Quest Go: Sparrows</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nest-quest-go-sparrows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nest-quest-go-sparrows/</guid>
      <description>Nest Quest Go: Sparrows View the project here.
Overview Join the Cornell Lab of Ornithology&amp;rsquo;s Citizen-Science Project, NestWatch in understanding the historical nesting patterns of various sparrows, including Black-throated Sparrow, Vesper Sparrow, Savannah Sparrow, Chipping Sparrow, Song Sparrow, Field Sparrow, Lark Sparrow, Eastern Towhee and many more! Generally, for most types of sparrows, the female searches for a nest location and builds her nest with little to no help from the male, who often guards the nesting territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Particle Search at CERN</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/new-particle-search-cern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/new-particle-search-cern/</guid>
      <description>New Particle Search at CERN View the project here.
Overview You have the opportunity to contribute to the search for undiscovered particles, which are produced from the collisions of high-energy protons at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), the world’s most powerful particle accelerator.
While the Higgs boson was discovered in 2012, after about 40 years of intense experimental and theoretical research, and was the last missing component of our present model of particle physics, there are still many unanswered questions and even more theories that try to answer them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Public Library: What&#39;s on the menu?</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</guid>
      <description>New York Public Library: What&amp;rsquo;s on the menu? View the project here.
Overview Help The New York Public Library improve a unique collection!
We’re transcribing our historical restaurant menus, dish by dish, so that they can be searched by what people were eating back in the day. It’s a big job so we need your help!
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFS@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/nfs-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/nfs-at-home/</guid>
      <description>NFS@Home View the project here.
Overview NFS@Home is a research project that uses Internet-connected computers to do the lattice sieving step in the Number Field Sieve factorization of large integers. As a young school student, you gained your first experience at breaking an integer into prime factors, such as 15 = 3 * 5 or 35 = 5 * 7. NFS@Home is a continuation of that experience, only with integers that are hundreds of digits long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</guid>
      <description>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes View the project here.
Overview We are running ‘Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes’ to analyse images of lymph nodes from breast cancer patients. This project will generate data that will be used to help improve our AI model performance. We are trying to find the germinal centres, the light pink circles in lymph nodes. When the immune system spot something foreign, new immune cells were produced in germinal centres of lymph nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - CalBug</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-calbug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-calbug/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - CalBug View the project here.
Overview Natural history collections house over a billion insect specimens worldwide collected over several centuries. Specimen labels encode data denoting species, location, and date captured and are used to study biogeographic patterns, spread of invasive species, and responses to land use, climate, and other environmental changes. However, access to data is impractical for most of the research community.
Because of enormous collection sizes, entomology has lagged behind other disciplines in digitizing collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&#39;s Flowers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-capturing-californias-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Capturing California&amp;rsquo;s Flowers View the project here.
Overview The California Phenology Network was originally an NSF-funded collaboration of 22 California herbaria that aimed to image 904,200 herbarium specimens by 2022. In July 2020, this network was expanded by a partner-to-existing-network grant to include six additional institutions and over 148,000 more specimens, for a total of over one million specimens. We will also georeference and transcribe over 320,000 specimens, making their data publicly available on our data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Flora of Texas and Oklahoma</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-tx-and-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-tx-and-ok/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Flora of Texas and Oklahoma View the project here.
Overview Naturalists and Scientists have been exploring Nature for centuries, collecting a massive amount of specimens over the course of many lifetimes. While this meticulous work has resulted in more than 3 million botanical specimens being housed in herbaria across Texas and Oklahoma, only a small fraction of this treasure is digitally accessible for observation, or for inclusion in scientific studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - Herbarium</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-herbarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-herbarium/</guid>
      <description>Notes From Nature - Herbarium View the project here.
Overview Welcome to the Herbarium Project on Notes from Nature. We will be hosting lots of great expeditions related to plants on this Project from a variety of institutions.
For the time being these will be mostly specimens related to the from the NitFix project.
The NitFix project received funding from the U.S. Department of Energy to develop mechanisms to engineer bioenergy crops so that these plants can fix nitrogen via root nodule symbioses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-se-us-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Notes From Nature - Southeastern U.S. Biodiversity View the project here.
Overview Digitizing data of southeast United States species allows comparisons of geographic distributions and niche specificity between endemic vascular plant species and non-endemics – essential to characterize and manage a significant component of this nation’s biodiversity imperiled by the effects of climate change, the loss of native habitat to anthropogenic uses, and biotic invasions.
Researchers can utilize herbarium specimen data to model current and future distributions of rare and endemic species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - Terrestrial Parasite Tracker</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-terrestrial-parasite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-terrestrial-parasite/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - Terrestrial Parasite Tracker View the project here.
Overview Parasitic arthropods inflict an enormous burden on human society; they afflict human health and the animals on which we depend. The negative effects of parasitic arthropods are exacerbated by current climate and ecosystem change. Fleas that vectored the pathogen causing bubonic plague wreaked havoc on historic human populations. Mosquitos continue to vector pathogens responsible for malaria and dengue, and ticks vector the bacteria responsible for Lyme disease; these arthropod borne pathogens infect and kill millions of people each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nfn-wedigflplants/</guid>
      <description>Notes from Nature - WeDigFLPlants View the project here.
Overview WeDigFLPlants is a collaboration between professional research botanists, amateur naturalists, gardeners, educators, and citizen scientists to build the most complete picture possible of plant distribution and diversity in Florida over the past 200 years. The data for this historical baseline come from archived plant specimens curated by the world&amp;rsquo;s 3,000 herbaria. Each of these specimens includes a label that answers the who, what, when, and where of the collecting event that produced it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NumberFields@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/numberfields-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/numberfields-at-home/</guid>
      <description>NumberFields@Home View the project here.
Overview NumberFields@home is a research project that uses Internet-connected computers to do research in number theory. You can participate by downloading and running a free program on your computer.
NumberFields@home searches for fields with special properties. The primary application of this research is in the realm of algebraic number theory. Number theorists can mine the data for interesting patterns to help them formulate conjectures about number fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OceanEYEs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/oceaneyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/oceaneyes/</guid>
      <description>OceanEYEs View the project here.
Overview NOAA scientists need your help to count fish and improve data used in management of the Hawaiʻi “Deep 7” bottomfish fishery! NOAA&amp;rsquo;s Pacific Islands Fisheries Science Center deploys stereo-camera systems on the seafloor to help monitor populations of deep-water snappers and groupers. The local commercial fishery in Hawaiʻi targets these fish primarily. Each camera can record tens of thousands of images! Human observers annotate the images to count and measure each species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ODLK1</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/odlk1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/odlk1/</guid>
      <description>ODLK1 View the project here.
Overview BOINC-project ODLK1 continues to solve the problem of BOINC-project ODLK. The project generates a database of canonical forms (CF) of diagonal Latin squares (DLS) of order 10 having orthogonal diagonal Latin squares (ODLS).
The necessary definitions for the theme can be found here:
 Latin square (English) Latin square (Russian)  Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offal Wildlife Watching</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/offal-ww/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/offal-ww/</guid>
      <description>Offal Wildlife Watching View the project here.
Overview Who Eats your Guts? Help us better understand scavenging of deer gut piles provided by hunters across Minnesota. IMPORTANT: IMAGES SHOW ANIMALS FEEDING ON THE REMAINS OF DEER
The purpose of this research is to better understand what and when species use deer gut piles provided by hunters across Minnesota. Minnesota offers a unique opportunity to look at this across four different biomes and a major metropolitan area, different hunting methods (rifle, archery, and shotgun), and different scavenger assemblages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - Naval Rendezvous</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-naval-rendezvous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-naval-rendezvous/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - Naval Rendezvous View the project here.
Overview This project seeks volunteers to help transcribe sea ice and weather observations from the logbooks of military vessels that sailed Arctic seas in the 19th and 20th century. This information is used to improve climate and sea ice data sets used by scientists every day.
To learn how to participate in this project, visit the Old Weather forum here.
In this project we use customized LibreOffice spreadsheets to guide the collection and organization of information extracted from the logbooks posted online, as in the example below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - Shipping Office</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-shipping-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-shipping-office/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - Shipping Office View the project here.
Overview This project seeks volunteers to help transcribe sea ice and weather observations from the logbooks of whaling ships that sailed Arctic seas from 1849 to 1912. This information is used to improve climate and sea ice data sets used by scientists every day.
To learn how to participate in this project, visit the Old Weather forum here.
In this project we use Microsoft Excel to guide the collection and organization of information extracted from the logbooks posted online, as in the example below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - WW2</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - WW2 View the project here.
Overview Help recover hidden weather data collected by the U.S. Navy during World War II!
The purpose of this project is to recover hidden marine weather data recorded in U.S. Navy ships&#39; logbooks during World War II. Like all Old Weather projects, these data will be used to drive sophisticated computer models that help us understand weather and climate in extraordinary detail. But there is another goal that is just as vital - to uncover the source of a mysterious distortion in the Navy temperature data collected during the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Insulin</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/open-insulin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/open-insulin/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview The Open Insulin Foundation is a non-profit creating the means for communities in-need to have local sources of safe, affordable, high-quality insulin.
Our governance is shared between people with diabetes and people working on the project. Our working groups collaborate to develop new tools for open drug production, from R&amp;amp;D to manufacturing for medical use. Our goal is that people living with diabetes and their communities can own and govern the organizations that produce the medicine they depend on to survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenPandemics - COVID-19</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/openpandemics-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/openpandemics-covid19/</guid>
      <description>OpenPandemics - COVID-19 View the project here.
Overview COVID-19 is a disease caused by SARS-CoV2, a virus of the coronavirus family. These viruses cause diseases that affect mainly the human respiratory system and potentially other major organs. COVID-19 can lead to serious illness or even death.
As of the launch of this project, there is no treatment, cure, or vaccine for COVID-19.
Scientists at Scripps Research are doing molecular modeling simulations to look for possible candidates for the development of treatments for COVID-19, but to be successful they need massive computing power to carry out millions of simulated laboratory experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers of the War Department</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</guid>
      <description>Papers of the War Department View the project here.
Overview The War Department office was established in 1790. It burned in 1800.
For decades historians believed that its files, and the window they provide into the early federal government, had been lost forever. This collection unites copies of the lost files in a digital archive that reconstitutes this invaluable historical resource. Our community of transcribers are working to create full text transcriptions of every possible document in the collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenology and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Phenology and Climate View the project here.
Overview Research Question: How is climate change affecting plant phenology?
Help us understand how plants are responding to this year&amp;rsquo;s seasons and longer-term changes in climate.
How plants react to seasonal change has a big impact on the environment. Because plants are at the base of the food chain, anything that affects plants can impact other parts of the ecosystem. Phenology is important because it affects plants ability to produce fruits and seeds and food availability for other animals like birds and squirrels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Hunters NGTS</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-ngts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-ngts/</guid>
      <description>Planet Hunters NGTS View the project here.
Overview The Next-Generation Transit Survey have been searching for transiting exoplanets around the brightest stars in the sky. We need your help sifting through the observations flagged by the computers to search for hidden worlds that might have been missed in the NGTS team&amp;rsquo;s review. Most of the planets in the dataset have likely been found already, but you just might be the first to find a new exoplanet not known before!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Hunters TESS</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-tess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-tess/</guid>
      <description>Planet Hunters TESS View the project here.
Overview The recently launched Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) is providing us with a huge amount of data that lets us look for planets outside of our own Solar System, including planets that could support life. With your help, we are going to find planets that will help us understand how these extrasolar systems form and evolve over time. The results may even bring us closer to answering the question that we all want to answer: Are we alone in the Universe?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Patrol</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-patrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-patrol/</guid>
      <description>Planet Patrol View the project here.
Overview NASA’s Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission will take pictures of more than a million stars to search for planets orbiting them, called &amp;ldquo;transiting exoplanets&amp;rdquo;. We expect this mission will see thousands of these transiting exoplanets when they pass in front of nearby stars and periodically block some of the starlight.
But sometimes when a star dims like that, it&amp;rsquo;s not because of a planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants of Concern</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/plants-of-concern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/plants-of-concern/</guid>
      <description>Plants of Concern View the project here.
Overview Interested in monitoring rare plants and joining our team? Fantastic!
Plants of Concern is active in Northeastern and Southern Illinois. We invite you to join us in monitoring rare plants in these regions.
We offer online training through a series of six video modules that you can view at any time. All modules together take approximately 45 minutes to watch. Short quizzes (less than 5 min each) separate each module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Origins</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</guid>
      <description>Plastic Origins View the project here.
Overview Plastic Origins is a project initiated by the not-for-profit Surfrider Foundation Europe in search of solutions to address the source of ocean pollution. Supported by citizens, associations, scientists, and socially responsible companies, the Plastic Origins project aims to map plastic pollution in European rivers by applying participatory science and Artificial Intelligence technology. This mapping data helps to identify areas of high impact, gain a deeper understanding of the problem on the field, and measure the evolution of pollution over time as well as to raise awareness among political decision-makers on the local, national, and European levels and urge them to act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pollinators and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Pollinators and Climate View the project here.
Overview Help us understand how plant-pollinator interactions are responding to a changing climate.
Changes in pollination has significant impacts on how we humans live our lives and interact with our environment on a daily basis. Pollinator and pollinator health changes the success of fruiting for plants and our food supply and therefore our health. We know that phenological events can vary from year to year, but how are pollinators affected by these variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prickly Pear Project Kenya</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/prickly-pear-project-kenya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/prickly-pear-project-kenya/</guid>
      <description>Prickly Pear Project Kenya View the project here.
Overview Prickly pear cacti (Opuntia sp.) are one of the worst invasive plants in East Africa. We are a team of researchers from Durham University (UK) and Mpala Research Centre (Kenya) using camera traps to understand how Opuntia affects the habitat use of medium to large mammal species. This research has important implications for human-wildlife conflict and the future spread of the cactus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrimeGrid</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/primegrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/primegrid/</guid>
      <description>PrimeGrid View the project here.
Overview PrimeGrid&amp;rsquo;s primary goal is to advance mathematics by enabling everyday computer users to contribute their system&amp;rsquo;s processing power towards prime finding. By simply downloading and installing BOINC and attaching to the PrimeGrid project, participants can choose from a variety of prime forms to search. With a little patience, you may find a large or even record breaking prime and enter into Chris Caldwell&amp;rsquo;s The Largest Known Primes Database with a multi-million digit prime!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project FeederWatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/project-feederwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/project-feederwatch/</guid>
      <description>Project FeederWatch View the project here.
Overview Project FeederWatch turns your love of feeding birds into scientific discoveries. FeederWatch is a November-April survey of birds that visit backyards, nature centers, community areas, and other locales in North America. You don’t even need a feeder! All you need is an area with plantings, habitat, water or food that attracts birds. The schedule is completely flexible. Count your birds for as long as you like on days of your choosing, then enter your counts online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Four</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</guid>
      <description>Project Four View the project here.
Overview Welcome to Planet Four, a citizen science project designed to help planetary scientists identify and measure features on the surface of Mars&amp;hellip; the likes of which don’t exist on Earth. All of the images on this site depict the south polar region, where dark seasonal fans and blotches appear during the Spring. By mapping these features in images from the HiRISE camera, the highest resolution camera ever sent to a planet, we can explore the Martian climate and how it changes over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Unlock the past! Transcribe letters and diaries to help with historical research.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/galaxy-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/galaxy-zoo/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here (for desktop users) and its mobile version (for Android and iPhone) here.
Overview To understand how galaxies formed we need your help to classify them according to their shapes. If you&amp;rsquo;re quick, you may even be the first person to see the galaxies you&amp;rsquo;re asked to classify.
Welcome to Galaxy Zoo&amp;rsquo;s latest incarnation. For more than a decade, we&amp;rsquo;ve asked volunteers to help us explore galaxies near and far, sampling a fraction of the roughly one hundred billion that are scattered throughout the observable Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/growing-beyond-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/growing-beyond-earth/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here (2021-2022 page) and here (main page).
Overview *NOTE: While the project is already underway for the 2021-2022 school year, this is an annually recurring project that has been going for six years already and will absolutely run again next year. If you are interested in having your class participate
Growing Beyond Earth® (GBE) is a classroom-based citizen science project operated in partnership with NASA. It includes a series of plant experiments conducted by students using equipment similar to the Vegetable Production System (Veggie) on the International Space Station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/junocam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/junocam/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview We’re calling all amateur astronomers to upload their telescopic images and data of Jupiter. These uploads are critical for providing context for new JunoCam images and will help NASA successfully plan the future of the mission.
If you&amp;rsquo;re a veteran astrophotographer or if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting started with your first telescope, we highly recommend you read our Submission Guidelines before submitting data. In the PDF you&amp;rsquo;ll find information about the best capture and process workflows as well as links to free software and tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project RattleCam</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rattlecam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rattlecam/</guid>
      <description>Project RattleCam View the project here.
Overview This project was conceived in 2020 when Dr. Scott Boback of Dickinson College and Dr. Emily Taylor of the California Polytechnic State University decided to design a Zooniverse project for help analyzing game camera images they&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting from prairie rattlesnake rookeries in a remote area of Colorado. Rattlesnake rookeries are areas where females come together to give birth and care for their young.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project RISE</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rise/</guid>
      <description>Project RISE View the project [here](https://smoke.createlab.org/label.html
Overview Project RISE, initiated by the CMU CREATE Lab, aims to train an Artificial Intelligence model to Recognize Industrial Smoke Emissions, and we need volunteers to help label smoke emissions. So far, 22099 (23.05%) videos are fully labeled. We would greatly appreciate your participation in this community-powered AI research!
Our goal is to invite citizens in creating data-driven evidence that shows the pollution source (using the smoke emissions found by the AI model) and its impact on the community (using Smell Pittsburgh).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Research on the Net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/psych-researc-on-the-net/</guid>
      <description>Psychological Research on the Net View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
On this website you will find links to known experiments on the internet that are psychologically related. They are organized by general topic area with the topic areas listed chronologically with the most recently added at the top.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Flu</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</guid>
      <description>Quantified Flu View the project here.
Overview The question we want to answer is: Can the various physiological parameters tracked by our wearables help to predict when we’re getting sick? With the COVID-19 pandemic influencing all of our lives right now, this question seems more timely than ever. But it&amp;rsquo;s not only the pandemic, this question equally applies to the flu and the common cold!
There is some preliminary data which shows that the data from wearables (like resting heart rate and sleep quality) might be predictive of coming down with a cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QuChemPedIA@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/quchempedia-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/quchempedia-at-home/</guid>
      <description>QuChemPedIA@home View the project here.
Overview Molecular chemistry is lagging behind in term of open science. Although modelization by quantum mechanics applied to chemistry has become almost mandatory in any major publication, computational raw data is most of the time kept in the labs or destroyed. Furthermore, the software used in this area tend to lack effective quality control and computational details are usually incomplete in the articles and the information may not be reused or reproduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio Galaxy Zoo: LOFAR</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-galaxy-zoo-lofar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-galaxy-zoo-lofar/</guid>
      <description>Radio Galaxy Zoo: LOFAR View the project here.
Overview Help astronomers locate and identify supermassive black holes and starforming galaxies!
The LOFAR project offers us an unprecedented view of what our skies look like at radio wavelengths. Never before have we been able to map such a large part of the radio sky at such high sensitivity. This allows scientists all over the world to answer many questions on the evolution of galaxies and the supermassive black holes that they harbour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio JOVE</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-jove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-jove/</guid>
      <description>Radio JOVE View the project here.
Overview Radio JOVE students and amateur scientists from around the world observe and analyze natural radio emissions of Jupiter, the Sun, and our galaxy building their own radio telescope from an easy to build kit or using remote radio telescopes through the Internet.
 Build and use your own Decametric Radio Telescope Share your observations with other project members Teachers, See Our Lesson Ideas and other Educational Materials  There is much more to astronomy than what can be learned by peering at the skies through an optical telescope!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radioactive@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/radioactive-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/radioactive-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Radioactive@Home View the project here.
Overview Radioactive@Home is a polish science project using distributed computing capabilities of BOINC platform. The main goal of the project is to create free and constantly updated map of radiation available for all people, by gathering information about gamma radiation using using sensors connected to computers of volunteers willing to participate in the project. The project uses dedicated hardware sensor; without it the app does nothing and no credits are granted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RakeSearch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rakesearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rakesearch/</guid>
      <description>RakeSearch View the project here.
Overview The enormous size of the diagonal Latin squares space makes it unfeasible to enumerate all its objects straightforwardly in reasonable time. So, in order to discover the structure of this space, sophisticated search methods are needed. In RakeSearch project, we implement an application that picks up separate pairs of mutually orthogonal DLSs, which allows to reconstruct full graphs of their orthogonality.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA World (beta)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rna-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rna-world/</guid>
      <description>RNA World (beta) View the project here.
Overview RNA World is a distributed supercomputer that uses Internet-connected computers to advance RNA research. This system is dedicated to identify, analyze, structurally predict and design RNA molecules on the basis of established bioinformatics software in a high-performance, high-throughput fashion.
In contrast to classical bioinformatic approaches, RNA World does not rely on individual desktop computers, web servers or supercomputers. Instead, it represents a continuously evolving cluster of world-wide distributed machines of any type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosetta@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rosetta-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/rosetta-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Rosetta@home View the project here.
Overview By running Rosetta@home on your computer when you&amp;rsquo;re not using it you will speed up and extend our efforts to design new proteins and to predict their 3-dimensional shapes. Proteins are the molecular machines and building blocks of life. You can read more about protein folding and design here.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan White Letters</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</guid>
      <description>Ryan White Letters View the project here.
Overview The Ryan White Letters Collection consists of almost 6000 letters and cards written to Ryan White and his family during the last years of his life. After being diagnosed with HIV/AIDS at the age of 13, Ryan’s legal fight to attend school despite his disease brought him to the forefront of public discussion about AIDS and its victims in the late 1980s. Thousands of letters came to Ryan from all over the world, many of them from children and teens who had seen his story in the media and wanted Ryan to know he was loved and supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scarlets and Blues</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</guid>
      <description>Scarlets and Blues View the project here.
Overview Travel back in time and take a behind-the-scenes look at the stories, lives and interactions of WWI-era staff and soldiers at the Royal Hospital Chelsea, one of London’s most iconic and longstanding institutions.
Named for the colours of the coats worn by England’s famous Chelsea Pensioners, the Scarlets and Blues project takes a behind-the-scenes look at the Royal Hospital Chelsea using records from The National Archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science United</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/science-united/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/science-united/</guid>
      <description>Science United View the project here.
Overview Science United lets you help scientific research projects by giving them computing power. These projects do research in astronomy, physics, biomedicine, mathematics, and environmental science; you can pick the areas you want to support.
You help by installing BOINC, a free program that runs scientific jobs in the background and when you&amp;rsquo;re not using the computer. BOINC is secure and will not affect your normal use of the computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciStarter</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/scistarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/scistarter/</guid>
      <description>SciStarter View the project here.
Overview SciStarter is a globally acclaimed, online citizen science hub where more than 3,000 projects, searchable by location, topic, age level, etc, have been registered by individual project leaders or imported through partnerships with federal governments, NGOs, and universities. As a research affiliate of NCSU and ASU, and a popular citizen science portal, SciStarter hosts an active community of close to 100,000 registered citizen scientists and millions of additional site visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed Sleuth</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/seed-sleuth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/seed-sleuth/</guid>
      <description>Seed Sleuth View the project here.
Overview Arabidopsis thaliana (Arabidopsis) was the first plant to have its genome completely sequenced (circa 2000). Although technically a weed, this small plant has been transformed into an important model system for plant research.
This project aims to provide ABRC with new information about these seed lines by asking citizen scientists to quantify the number of mutant phenotypes and dead seeds in different seed samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiDock@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/sidock-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/sidock-at-home/</guid>
      <description>SiDock@home View the project here.
Overview Sidock@home is an international volunteer computing project aimed at drug discovery. The first mission of the project is discovery of possible drugs against the SARS-CoV-2 virus. It started as an extension of the project COVID.SI to engage the BOINC community into the drug discovery.
You can help with your computer. With the help of BOINC, you will download a subset of compounds on your computer, examine the compounds in the context of the studied target and send the results to a server where they are collected for later analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small world of words</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/small-world-of-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/small-world-of-words/</guid>
      <description>small world of words View the project here.
Overview The small world of words project is a large-scale scientific study that aims to build a mental dictionary or lexicon in the major languages of the world and make this information widely available.
In contrast to a thesaurus or dictionary, we use word associations to learn about what words mean and which ones are central in the human mind. This enables psychologists, linguists, neuro-scientists and others to test new theories about how we represent and process language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smash Childhood Cancer (paused)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/smash-childhood-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/smash-childhood-cancer/</guid>
      <description>Smash Childhood Cancer View the project here.
Overview In the past 20 years, only a small number of new drugs designed to treat childhood cancer have been approved by the US Food and Drug Administration. Half of all the chemotherapy treatments used for children with cancer have been in existence for 25 years or longer.
Members of the Smash Childhood Cancer research team have identified proteins and other molecules that play key roles in certain childhood cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smithsonian Institute: Transcribing Audio Collections</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-audio-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-audio-collections/</guid>
      <description>Smithsonian Institute: Transcribing Audio Collections View the project here.
Overview The Smithsonian holds over 150,000 audio recordings - in various formats, and dating from the late 19th century to the present - in its many museums, archives, and libraries. Transcription of these collections will increase accessibility, unlock hidden content, and preserve historical audio assets for future generations.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smithsonian National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</guid>
      <description>Smithsonian National Archives View the project here.
Overview Become a Smithsonian Digital Volunteer and help us make historical documents and biodiversity data more accessible.
Join 55,775 &amp;ldquo;volunpeers&amp;rdquo; to add more to the total 912,645 pages of field notes, diaries, ledgers, logbooks, currency proof sheets, photo albums, manuscripts, biodiversity specimens labels, and historic audio recordings, that have been collaboratively transcribed and reviewed since June 2013.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoke Sense Study</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/smoke-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/smoke-sense/</guid>
      <description>Smoke Sense Study View the project here.
Overview Smoke Sense is a crowdsourcing, citizen science research project developed by EPA researchers focused on increasing public awareness and engagement related to wildfire smoke health risks. Specifically, EPA wants to understand the extent that exposure to wildland fire smoke affects health and productivity, discover what steps people are willing to take to reduce their exposure, and develop health risk communication strategies that improve public health when there is wildfire smoke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot Wisconsin</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/snapshot-wisconsin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/snapshot-wisconsin/</guid>
      <description>Snapshot Wisconsin View the project here.
Overview Snapshot Wisconsin is a statewide wildlife monitoring program that relies on volunteers to host trail cameras throughout the year. Trail cameras are mounted to trees or posts and take photos when triggered by the movement and heat of a passing animal. Once the photos are uploaded and classified by the Zooniverse community, they become data that can be used to understand patterns of animal occurrence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Psychology Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/social-psych-network/</guid>
      <description>Social Psychology Network View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
This page contains links to 259 web-based experiments, surveys, and other social psychology studies.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/about/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/about/sources/</guid>
      <description>As all scientists learn, one of the most important things when sharing work with others is to be transparent about your sources, methods, and evidence. Here are mine.
Hub websites you can sign up on to help with (and keep track of) a lot of volunteer science projects at once:  Zooniverse - The world’s largest and most popular platform for people-powered research. World Community Grid - Donate your device’s spare computing power to help scientists solve the world’s biggest problems in health and sustainability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spyfish Aotearoa</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/spyfish-aotearoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/spyfish-aotearoa/</guid>
      <description>Spyfish Aotearoa View the project here.
Overview Our team deploys baited underwater cameras in marine reserves all over Aotearoa New Zealand to monitor the abundance and diversity of marine life. Help us identify and count the species of fish recorded by the cameras. Your classifications will be used to determine the effectiveness of the reserves, inform marine management, and protect our taonga (treasured) species.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRBase</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/srbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/srbase/</guid>
      <description>SRBase View the project here.
Overview SRBase is a mathematical research project that uses Internet-connected computers trying to solve Sierpinski / Riesel Bases up to 1030. You can participate by downloading and running a free program on your computer.
The project is in collaboration with the Mersenne CRUS project. The server is running on a private computer in a VM.
Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford University Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</guid>
      <description>Stanford University Archives View the project here.
Overview The Stanford University Archives is the official repository for records of Stanford University and serves as its institutional memory. The Archives collects, preserves, administers, and promotes access to materials in any format that document the history of Stanford, including its founders, administration, faculty, students, and alumni/ae. Our holdings include more than 30,000 linear feet of material and 20+ TB of electronic records within 2,200+ collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Notes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</guid>
      <description>Star Notes View the project here.
Overview Help us transcribe the groundbreaking work of early women astronomers!
We have digitized the notebooks of the Harvard Computers and early Harvard astronomers including Williamina Fleming, Annie Jump Cannon, Henrietta Swan Leavitt, and many others. The goal of Star Notes is to link these notebooks back to their original source material: 500,000 glass plate photographs representing the first ever picture of the visible universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardust@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/stardust-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/stardust-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Stardust@home View the project here.
Overview On January 15, 2006, the Stardust spacecraft’s sample return capsule parachuted gently onto the Utah desert. Nestled within the capsule were precious particles collected during Stardust’s dramatic encounter with comet Wild 2 in January of 2004; and something else, even rarer and no less precious: tiny particles of interstellar dust that originated in distant stars, light-years away. They are the first such contemporary interstellar dust particles ever collected in space and returned to Earth for study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardust@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/stardust-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/stardust-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Stardust@home View the project here.
Overview The interstellar dust particles returned to Earth by the Stardust mission are the first such pristine dust particles ever collected in space, and scientists are eager to “get their hands” on them. We estimate that Stardust collected less than 100 interstellar dust particles. They are tiny-only about a micron (a millionth of a meter) in size! These miniscule particles were captured in an aerogel collector about 1,000 square centimeters in size, and in about 150 square centimeters of aluminum metal foils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of St James&#39;s Burial Ground</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</guid>
      <description>Stories of St James&amp;rsquo;s Burial Ground View the project here.
Overview High-Speed Rail 2 (HS2) is a major infrastructure project connecting cities across the UK with faster train lines and services. In London, contractors Costain Skanska Joint Venture (CSJV) are managing work near Euston Station where construction is taking place on the site of St James’s Burial Ground, a major 18th-19th century cemetery site. Ahead of this work over 100 archaeologists and specialists from MOLA Headland Infrastructure were brought in to excavate and record over 40,000 burials, the largest archaeological excavation of its kind ever undertaken in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swipes for Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/swipes-for-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/swipes-for-science/</guid>
      <description>Swipes for Science View the project here.
Overview The problem
 Big data in biomedical research needs individual inspection, but this doesn’t scale for large datasets. For example, some researchers analyze MRI images to study the brain. But before they start the analysis, they have to visually inspect each image to make sure it is good quality. And at various stages in data processing, researchers have to check images to make sure the analysis is correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag Along with Adler</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/tag-with-adler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/tag-with-adler/</guid>
      <description>Tag Along with Adler View the project here.
Overview Help the Adler Planetarium tag our collections to expand how we catalogue our objects, and how our users can find them!
As museums add collections online, the language that describes the objects - known as metadata - affects how people find and search for these objects. Cataloguers and museum staff create metadata based on standards and rules. This means access is often limited to only those who understand the style used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Target NEOs!</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/target-neo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/target-neo/</guid>
      <description>Target NEOs! View the project here.
Overview Target NEOs!* is an exciting opportunity for amateur astronomers to participate in a long-term citizen science project that will contribute to basic scientific understanding of near-Earth objects (NEOs). Observers collect data about asteroids on a selected list and submit images and corresponding reports. These observations support spacecraft missions in progress and aid future mission designers and scientists. Citizen scientists’ astrometry and photometry data will enable scientists to test theoretical models about these objects to refine orbits and taxonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestMyBrain</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/testmybrain/</guid>
      <description>TestMyBrain View the project here.
Overview TestMyBrain is a not-for-profit initiative dedicated to collaborating with citizen scientists throughout the world by providing measurement tools that allow people to engage in science and learn about themselves.
At TestMyBrain, we have the same goal that you do - to understand more about your brain. All of our experiments are designed to provide personalized feedback that is specific to you and will help you learn more about your own mind and brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</guid>
      <description>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project View the project here.
Overview The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project belongs to all of us who live in Berkeley. We invite you to participate by making a contribution, e-mailing us current or historical photos that will add to this website, or writing and sending us your own e-Plaque texts with photos.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Indy Wildlife Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/indy-wildlife-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/indy-wildlife-watch/</guid>
      <description>The Indy Wildlife Watch: An Initiative of the CUES View the project here.
Overview Join the Center for Urban Ecology and Sustainability (CUES) at Butler University and the Indianapolis Zoo by tagging animals in our photos!
Urbanization describes a human population shift from rural areas to cities, which usually results in the physical growth of urban areas.
As the global population of humans continues to grow, so will the rate of urbanization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Koster seafloor observatory</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/koster-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/koster-observatory/</guid>
      <description>The Koster seafloor observatory View the project here.
Overview At the Koster seafloor observatory we want to know how climate change and human activities influence Sweden&amp;rsquo;s marine ecosystems.
For the last 20 years, we have used Remotely Operated Vehicles and cameras to monitor the Kosterhavets National Park. A highly-diverse and unique marine reserve in the south of Sweden. Now, we need your help identifying the habitat, species, and presence of litter recorded in over 3,000 hours of underwater videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Migratory Dragonfly Partnership</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/migratory-dragonfly-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/migratory-dragonfly-partnership/</guid>
      <description>The Migratory Dragonfly Partnership View the project here.
Overview To better understand and conserve North America&amp;rsquo;s dragonfly migration, dragonfly experts, nongovernmental programs, academic institutions, and federal agencies from the United States, Mexico, and Canada have formed the collaborative Migratory Dragonfly Partnership (MDP).
Regular monitoring and centralized reporting among participants across three nations will help us answer some of the many questions currently surrounding dragonfly migration and provide information needed to create cross-border conservation programs to protect and sustain the phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Map Corps</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</guid>
      <description>The National Map Corps View the project here.
Overview By updating and verifying structures data, volunteers are making significant contributions to USGS National Structures Database, The National Map, and ultimately U.S. Topo Maps!
TNMCorps is an online crowdsourcing mapping project with volunteers successfully editing structures in all 50 States, Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands.
Anyone with an interest in contributing can volunteer. It is easy to sign up and get started!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web Experiment List</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/the-web-experiment-list/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
The Web Experiment List NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
An interactive Web-based hotspot and archive for Internet-based experiments and surveys.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timber Tracking</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Timber Tracking View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Do you care about healthy forests? You can apply to join this project if you are a hiker, a birder, a biker, a forager, or a tree lover to explore the hardwood forests of the eastern and central United States in search of black walnut trees!.
One of the most valuable hardwood species in the United States, black walnut trees are threatened by timber poaching across the 30+ states in their range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</guid>
      <description>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR) View the project here.
Overview Traits Across Species’ Ranges is a community science project focused on understanding how variation within plant species influences the size and movement of different pools of elements (e.g., carbon, nitrogen) on the surface of the Earth.
For 2021 we are currently focused on developing partnerships with community scientist groups and individuals to survey patterns of green vs. freshly fallen leaf nutrient concentrations (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</guid>
      <description>Transcribe View the project here.
Overview Transcribe is the Library of Virginia’s collaborative online workspace where the public can participate in enhancing access to many of our amazing collections documenting over 400 years of Virginia history, people, and culture. This is the perfect opportunity for participants to dig deep into our collections and transcribe historical materials from five to ten active projects at a time. From peace to wartime, court records to letters home, and conspiracies to political statements, there will be something for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translate TED Talks</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/ted-translate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/ted-translate/</guid>
      <description>Translate TED Talks View the project here.
Overview TED Translators are a global community of volunteers who subtitle TED Talks, and enable the inspiring ideas in them to crisscross languages and borders.
Help make TED accessible to your language! Join our global community of volunteers.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</guid>
      <description>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration View the project here.
Overview Questions about how people make sense of and engage with their personal omic information including their personal genomics and microbiome data, and how comfortable they feel about sharing such information in order to advance scientific and biomedical research, are not only of paramount importance for society and policy makers, but also a pressing issue for HCI researchers. Funded by the National Science Foundation, and in collaboration with Open Humans, we investigate how to design effective interaction techniques to empower nonexpert users to engage with and make sense of their personal omic information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Tides</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/uk-tides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/uk-tides/</guid>
      <description>UK Tides View the project here.
Overview About 28% of the people live near the coast, and with global sea level rising, we need long records to be able to investigate how local tides and sea level are changing. One way this can be done is by recovering data from old documents. In this project, we are trying to convert data from old tide gauge ledgers from the North West of England into data usable by scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</guid>
      <description>United States National Archives View the project here.
Overview Welcome to our Citizen Archivist program. You can contribute to the National Archives Catalog by tagging, transcribing and adding comments to our records, making them more accessible and searchable. Join us! Every contribution you make helps unlock history.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universe@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/universe-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/universe-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Universe@home View the project here.
Overview Universe@home project&amp;rsquo;s two main goals are:
 to provide scientist with a necessary computational power and to provide the way of involvement for anyone equipped with a computer and willing to take part in the research  We live in times which are marked by the fastest scientific development in the history. Our knowledge grows faster than ever before. We explore the structures of the Universe, nuclei of stars and evolution of galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/volunteerscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/volunteerscience/</guid>
      <description>Volunteer Science View the project here.
Overview NOTE: This is a hub website, not a volunteer project itself.
Volunteer Science is a platform for creating online labs. Individual researchers can create unlimited online studies and recruit unlimited participants from anywhere around the world. Research labs can create research teams, giving all their members access to lab experiments and data. Large research organizations like universities, government agencies, and private companies can provide their research teams with organization-specific behavioral lab facilities connecting to internal- and external-facing audiences and subject pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Rescue At Sea</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/weather-rescue-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/weather-rescue-at-sea/</guid>
      <description>Weather Rescue At Sea View the project here.
Overview The aim of the Weather Rescue At Sea project is to construct and extended the global surface temperature record back to the 1780s, based on the air temperature observations recorded across the planet.
This will be achieved by crowd-sourcing the recovery (or data rescue) of the weather observations from historical ship logbooks, station records, weather journals and other sources, to produce a longer, and more consistent dataset of global surface temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</guid>
      <description>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch View the project here.
Overview Want an exclusive view of the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S? Take a closer look at urban wildlife activity through this camera trap project by joining our citizen science team and helping us tag pictures and contribute to urban ecology theory!
Wesselman Woods is home to the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S with over 200 acres of land, making this camera trap project like none other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale Chat</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whale-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whale-chat/</guid>
      <description>Whale Chat View the project here.
Overview The current development of deep learning and artificial intelligence allows a new approach to trying to understand the whale song. Deep learning models could help with identification of humpback sounds and unsupervised learning models could help to classify the song “units” in perhaps different ways. This project aims to investigate humpback songs from different years and regions, to identify humpback whale sounds in recordings, to classify these calls or units, and eventually to see if we can find individually distinct calls or units (the same way we do in Manatee Chat).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whooping Cranes!</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whooping-cranes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whooping-cranes/</guid>
      <description>Whooping Cranes! View the project here.
Overview Help us look for large white birds (Whooping Cranes) in Northern Canada so we can monitor the population of this endangered species!
Whooping Cranes (Grus americana) are one of North America’s rarest birds. The only remaining wild and self-sustaining population of Whooping Cranes breeds in northern Canada and winters on the Texas Gulf Coast. Canada has monitored the population by aerial surveys since the 1960s but the population is now growing quickly and expanding into new breeding areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild and Scenic Rivers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</guid>
      <description>Wild and Scenic Rivers View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
This is a multi-year effort to sample National Wild and Scenic Rivers. The project spans from northern Alaska to southeast Florida, from small scenic creeks to wild raging rivers.
The National Wild and Scenic Rivers System contributes 10% of drinking water throughout the United States. In addition, these rivers are essential for their cultural, recreational, and natural value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Mont-Blanc</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wild-mont-blanc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wild-mont-blanc/</guid>
      <description>Wild Mont-Blanc View the project here.
Overview Help us explore the secret life of the Mont-Blanc massif! Our cameras track the distribution, behavior and seasonal rhythm of animals year after year.
Forty camera traps installed across France’s Mont-Blanc massif are giving us a powerful new window into the dynamics of alpine wildlife species. The Research Center for Alpine Ecosystems (CREA Mont-Blanc) needs your help to identify all the different animals caught in hundreds of thousands of camera trap images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildlife of Los Angeles</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildlife-of-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildlife-of-la/</guid>
      <description>Wildlife of Los Angeles View the project here.
Overview In the United States greater than 80% of the human population occurs in cities, yet we know very little about the wildlife in these areas. Much work needs to be done to understand how increases in urbanized areas impact wildlife species and their ability to survive around us. Urbanization poses many threats to wildlife such as loss of habitat, fragmentation of habitat, roads and traffic, poisons and toxins, people, and our pets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</guid>
      <description>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl View the project here.
Overview The western burrowing owl needs our help. Unusual among owl species, this pint-sized raptor lives in elaborate underground burrows. These owls cannot dig their own burrows, and instead “reuse” excavated dens dug by ground squirrels and other fossorial (burrowing) animals. With its penchant for open, native grasslands, the burrowing owl has been on a collision course with humans throughout much of Southern California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woodpecker Cavity Cam</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/woodpecker-cavity-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/woodpecker-cavity-cam/</guid>
      <description>Woodpecker Cavity Cam View the project here.
Overview Help researchers explore the world of woodpecker cavities and the animals that use them!
The Woodpecker Cavity Cam project began in 2019 to augment ongoing research and fill additional knowledge gaps about red-headed woodpeckers. We are working to learn more about their nesting ecology and behavior and the many other animals that use and compete for the cavities these woodpeckers create. Researchers at the Cedar Creek Ecosystem Science Reserve, the University of Minnesota, and volunteers with the Red-headed Woodpecker Recovery Project and Audubon Chapter of Minneapolis have collaborated to place trail cameras outside of red-headed woodpecker cavities at Cedar Creek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Community Grid</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/world-community-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/world-community-grid/</guid>
      <description>World Community Grid View the project here.
Overview Donate your device’s spare computing power to help scientists solve the world’s biggest problems.
As a World Community Grid volunteer, your device does research calculations when it has spare power. With your help, scientists can identify the most important results to study in the lab, bringing them one step closer to discoveries that save lives and address global problems.
View already-completed research here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>yoyo@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/yoyo-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/yoyo-at-home/</guid>
      <description>yoyo@home View the project here.
Overview yoyo@home brings existing distributed computing projects to the BOINC world using the BOINC Wrapper technology.
yoyo@home is currently running the following sub-projects:
 M Queens (tackling the M Queens puzzle) Siever (Sieve Files for the CRUS-project) ECM (for Elliptic Curve Factorization) OGR (Optimal Golumb Ruler)  Runs on:  Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zooniverse</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/zooniverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/hubs/zooniverse/</guid>
      <description>Zooniverse View the project here.
Overview NOTE: As of November 2021, ALL active projects listed on Zooniverse are listed on this website in individual entries. New projects are added to Zooniverse intermittently, however, and sometimes their &amp;ldquo;Paused&amp;rdquo; projects turn active again, so it&amp;rsquo;s worth checking Zooniverse on occasion to see if there is anything new.
The Zooniverse is the world’s largest and most popular platform for people-powered research. This research is made possible by volunteers — more than a million people around the world who come together to assist professional researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zwicky Chemical Factory</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/zwicky-chemical-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/zwicky-chemical-factory/</guid>
      <description>Zwicky Chemical Factory View the project here.
Overview Every year astronomers discover thousands of new supernovae (exploding stars). Once these spectacular events are found, we use spectroscopy to understand the chemical elements in the explosion and what type of star exploded. Help us classify these explosions!
The elements created by an individual supernova (SN) differ depending on the type of SN (for example, oxygen and sodium are primarily created when massive stars explode, whereas iron is primarily created when white dwarf stars explode).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ОДЛК</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/%D0%BE%D0%B4%D0%BB%D0%BA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/%D0%BE%D0%B4%D0%BB%D0%BA/</guid>
      <description>ОДЛК View the project here.
Overview В проекте составляется база данных канонических форм (КФ) диагональных латинских квадратов (ДЛК) 10-го порядка, имеющих ортогональные диагональные латинские квадраты (ОДЛК). Необходимые определения по теме можно найти здесь:
Первые три ортогональные пары ДЛК были найдены в 1992 году, они опубликованы в статье “Completion of the Spectrum of Orthogonal Diagonal Latin Squares” (J. W. Brown и другие).
В 2012-2016 гг. действовал научный BOINC-проект SAT@home, в котором искались новые ортогональные пары ДЛК 10-го порядка.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
