<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>uk history on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/uk-history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in uk history on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/uk-history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Health</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</guid>
      <description>Addressing Health View the project here.
Overview Why did the UK&amp;rsquo;s Post Office employees in the nineteenth century retire from work? Some reached retirement age but many had to end their careers early because of ill health. Be a part of this Wellcome-funded project to find out what Post Office workers&#39; lives tell us about the history of health and wellbeing in the Victorian period. Transcribe the records of their career histories from images of documents held at the Postal Museum, London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</guid>
      <description>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service View the project here.
Overview Transcribing a hundred years of seafarer&amp;rsquo;s medical data from the Dreadnought Seamen&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in Greenwich, 1826-1930.
&amp;lsquo;HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service&amp;rsquo;, refers to the records of the Dreadnought Seamen’s Hospital at Greenwich. This was the main clinical site of the Seamen’s Hospital Society (now Seafarer’s Hospital Society), founded with the philanthropic mission of providing relief to sick and injured seafarers of all nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scarlets and Blues</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</guid>
      <description>Scarlets and Blues View the project here.
Overview Travel back in time and take a behind-the-scenes look at the stories, lives and interactions of WWI-era staff and soldiers at the Royal Hospital Chelsea, one of London’s most iconic and longstanding institutions.
Named for the colours of the coats worn by England’s famous Chelsea Pensioners, the Scarlets and Blues project takes a behind-the-scenes look at the Royal Hospital Chelsea using records from The National Archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of St James&#39;s Burial Ground</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</guid>
      <description>Stories of St James&amp;rsquo;s Burial Ground View the project here.
Overview High-Speed Rail 2 (HS2) is a major infrastructure project connecting cities across the UK with faster train lines and services. In London, contractors Costain Skanska Joint Venture (CSJV) are managing work near Euston Station where construction is taking place on the site of St James’s Burial Ground, a major 18th-19th century cemetery site. Ahead of this work over 100 archaeologists and specialists from MOLA Headland Infrastructure were brought in to excavate and record over 40,000 burials, the largest archaeological excavation of its kind ever undertaken in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
