<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>outdoors on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/outdoors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in outdoors on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/outdoors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality Citizen Science</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air Quality Citizen Science View the project here.
Overview Are you interested in helping in this NASA-funded science project? Do you have interest in understanding more about the air quality in your neighborhood? Would you like to measure air quality near your home or place of work? Have you been intrigued by the type of data that NASA collects from their satellites? Then this is the perfect opportunity for you to get involved!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audubon Christmas Bird Count</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/audubon-bird-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/audubon-bird-count/</guid>
      <description>Audubon Christmas Bird Count View the project here.
Overview The Christmas Bird Count occurs December 14 to January 5 every year.
Frank Chapman and 26 other conservationists initiated the Christmas Bird Count (CBC) as a way of promoting conservation by counting, rather than hunting, birds on Christmas Day of 1900. Some counts have been running every year since then and the CBC now happens in over 20 countries in the western hemisphere!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurorasaurus</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</guid>
      <description>Aurorasaurus View the project here.
Overview Aurorasaurus is the first and only citizen science initiative that tracks auroras around the world via reports on our website and social media. All aurora-related tweets and reports are placed on the Aurorasaurus.org map. We then ask people to log in and verify the tweets or reports. Each verified report serves as a valuable data point for scientists to analyze and incorporate into space weather models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bloomWatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/bloomwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/bloomwatch/</guid>
      <description>bloomWatch View the project here.
Overview Do you notice that a lake suddenly turned the color of pea soup or a blue-green paint spill? Or do you see green clumps, flakes or filaments floating in a lake?
Blooms in fresh waterbodies are commonly due to cyanobacteria, which have the potential to produce toxins that affect humans, pets, and our ecosystems.
State and local officials can’t be watching every lake at all times!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Urban Birds Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/celebrate-urban-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/celebrate-urban-birds/</guid>
      <description>Celebrate Urban Birds Project View the project here.
Overview From the Cornell Lab of Ornithology.
 Learn to identify your regional birds. Choose your birdwatching area. Watch birds for 10 minutes a day for 3 days. Report your results!  Our vision is to embrace community-led scientific research and programming and promote inclusive, accessible, and equitable birdwatching for all. We believe that birds have the power to connect us — as long as we intentionally value and center the power of equitable co-creation in birdwatching, monitoring, and conservation projects, and focus on culture through local leadership, creativity, and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance View the project here.
Overview The Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance is a group of researchers from across the Smithsonian and local universities, with a goal to study and educate the public about North American River Otters in the Chesapeake Bay. We need your help to figure out where these otters are in the Chesapeake Bay!
Very little to no research has been done regarding the numbers, health, and populations of otters in the Chesapeake Bay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chesapeake Water Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-water-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-water-watch/</guid>
      <description>Chesapeake Water Watch View the project here.
Overview We are aiming to improve how effective satellites are at monitoring the health of Chesapeake Bay by comparing information collected from satellites with information collected by researchers and citizen scientists on the ground. Right now, NASA&amp;rsquo;s cutting-edge satellites, provide a unique capability to capture water quality changes in areas that are economically and environmentally important.
There is a long history of public engagement in water quality monitoring in fresh and coastal ecosystems, with volunteer collected data being used as part of monitoring for the US Clean Water Act (Jollymore et al 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago EcoFlora Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-chicago-ecoflora/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Help us track native and non-native plant species in Chicagoland.
Now more than ever we need to understand urban flora-both native and invasive species. The Chicago EcoFlora project is collecting observations of plants in Cook County, Illinois to learn more about local plant life and contribute to conservation planning. With your help, we will collect data on important native species and troublesome new invaders that call our city home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/citizen-science-soil/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Science Soil Collection Program View the project here.
Overview The key to the next life-saving biomedical discovery might be living right below your feet. Dozens of fungi can occupy a single handful of soil and many of them are adept at making new compounds called natural products. These remarkable molecules hold tremendous promise for treating human diseases.
It only takes a few minutes to help by collecting a scoop of soil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cocorahs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cocorahs/</guid>
      <description>Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network View the project here.
Overview CoCoRaHS is an acronym for the Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network. CoCoRaHS is a unique, non-profit, community-based network of volunteers of all ages and backgrounds working together to measure and map precipitation (rain, hail and snow). By using low-cost measurement tools, stressing training and education, and utilizing an interactive Web-site, our aim is to provide the highest quality data for natural resource, education and research applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Snow Observations</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/community-snow-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/community-snow-observations/</guid>
      <description>Community Snow Observations (CSO) View the project here.
Overview CSO is a citizen science campaign to measure snow. Make your backcountry travels count! We need your help measuring snow depths in mountain places too vast for researchers to monitor.
Your observations help us predict snow conditions and improve safety for mountain travelers.
This project aims to improve our understanding of snow depth variability in mountainous regions. We need community-based observers, including backcountry professionals and recreationists, to help gather snow observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cyanoScope</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cyanoscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cyanoscope/</guid>
      <description>cyanoScope View the project here.
Overview cyanoScope uses modern technologies and a social approach to learn more about cyanobacteria and their distribution. By participating you will be helping scientists and water resource managers gain information on the occurrence of cyanobacteria in surface waters.
We will use submitted reports to map the spatial distribution and seasonal occurrence of cyanobacteria in lakes, ponds, and reservoirs.
Collect cyanobacteria:
 collect cyanobacteria with a net tow, prepare your microscope slides, identify cyanobacteria found in your sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Bay Horseshoe Crab Survey</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/delaware-bay-crabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/delaware-bay-crabs/</guid>
      <description>Delaware Bay Horseshoe Crab Survey View the project here.
Overview The Horseshoe Crab, Limulus polyphemus, visits the Delaware Bay Shore each year for spawning purposes. Through the work of volunteers, the spawning population is recorded to study the American Horseshoe Crab.
In 1990, the first organized survey of spawning horseshoe crabs in the Delaware Bay began. Now, every May and June during the full and new moon evening high tides, volunteers annually donate their time to count crabs on the beaches of the Delaware Bay in both Delaware and New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragonfly Mercury Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/dragonfly-mercury/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/dragonfly-mercury/</guid>
      <description>Dragonfly Mercury Project View the project here.
Overview The Dragonfly Mercury Project engages citizen scientists such as students and teachers in the collection of juvenile dragonflies, also known as dragonfly larvae, from national parks for mercury analysis.
Experience the Dragonfly Mercury Project by watching this short video. Then, grab some rubber boots and a sampling net and join park rangers as we search for juvenile dragonflies! Park rangers and enthusiastic volunteer citizen scientists collect many times the number of dragonflies from many more parks than would be possible for scientists alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EarthEcho Water Challenge</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/earthecho-water-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/earthecho-water-challenge/</guid>
      <description>EarthEcho Water Challenge View the project here.
Overview The EarthEcho Water Challenge (formerly World Water Monitoring Challenge) is an international program that runs annually from March 22 (the United Nations World Water Day) through December and equips anyone to protect the water resources we depend on every day. The EarthEcho Water Challenge builds public awareness and involvement in protecting water resources around the world by engaging citizens to conduct basic monitoring of their local waterbodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eMammal</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/emammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/emammal/</guid>
      <description>eMammal View the project here.
Overview eMammal is a data management system and archive for camera trap research projects. This cyber-tool is designed to not only be useful to scientists, but also to the citizen scientists who aid scientists in photo collection. Camera trappers use our software to look at pictures, identify animals and upload them for review and archive at the Smithsonian. These data then help address important conservation-related questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireballs in the Sky</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/fireballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/fireballs/</guid>
      <description>Fireballs in the Sky View the project here.
Overview Fireballs in the Sky is an innovative citizen science program that connects the public with the research of the Desert Fireball Network.
Meteorites have the potential to show us how the Solar System formed and evolved, coming from the very first bodies to be created. They act as a snapshot in time, holding the minerals that came from their parent bodies and are unchanged as they hurtle towards Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/global-garlic-mustard/</guid>
      <description>Global Garlic Mustard Field Survey View the project here.
Overview Many invasive species, like Garlic Mustard (Alliaria petiolata), are threatening the world’s natural resources, but the abundance of invasive species can vary dramatically over space and time. Scientists still do not have a good understanding of why this is so.
Through large-scale sampling, scientists can identify areas that differ in the intensity of invasion and try to understand why these differences exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globe at Night</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-at-night/</guid>
      <description>Globe at Night View the project here.
Overview Globe at Night is an international citizen-science campaign to raise public awareness of the impact of light pollution by inviting citizen-scientists to measure &amp;amp; submit their night sky brightness observations. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get involved - all you need is computer or smart phone &amp;amp; follow these 6 Simple Steps!
The November 2021 campaign is using the Constellation Perseus. Check out the dates and constellations for our other campaigns during all 12 months of 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLOBE Observer</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</guid>
      <description>GLOBE Observer View the project here.
Overview When you download the GLOBE Observer app, you join the community of The GLOBE Program - citizen scientists, students, and teachers in 120+ countries around the world contributing to Earth system science research.
Your observations:
 Help monitor the conditions of clouds, water (especially as a habitat for mosquitoes), plants (trees and other land cover), and see change over time. Can be used to help interpret NASA and other satellite data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</guid>
      <description>iNaturalist View the project here.
Overview One of the world’s most popular nature apps, iNaturalist helps you identify the plants and animals around you. Get connected with a community of over a million scientists and naturalists who can help you learn more about nature! What’s more, by recording and sharing your observations, you’ll create research quality data for scientists working to better understand and protect nature. iNaturalist is a joint initiative by the California Academy of Sciences and the National Geographic Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp; Satellites</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/locss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/locss/</guid>
      <description>Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp;amp; Satellites (LOCSS) View the project here.
Overview The Lake Observations by Citizen Scientists &amp;amp; Satellites project seeks to better understand how the quantity of water in lakes is changing.
Are lake volumes affected most by precipitation, water table height, evaporation or some other factors? Knowing the answer to this question will help us better understand how water moves in relation to these lakes and the surrounding land and what that may mean for lake users and these ecosystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landslides @ NASA</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/landslides-at-nasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/landslides-at-nasa/</guid>
      <description>Landslides @ NASA View the project here.
Overview NASA scientists are building an open global inventory of landslides and we need your help! Knowing where and when landslides occur can help communities worldwide prepare for these disasters. Become a citizen scientist and you can help inform decisions that could save lives and property today.
Landslides cause billions of dollars in infrastructural damage and thousands of deaths every year worldwide. Data on past landslide events guides future disaster prevention, but to date we do not have a global picture of exactly when and where landslides occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leafsnap</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leafsnap/</guid>
      <description>leafmolester View the project here.
Overview Leafsnap turns users into citizen scientists, automatically sharing images, species identifications, and geo-coded stamps of species locations with a community of scientists who will use the stream of data to map and monitor the ebb and flow of flora.
Leafsnap is a series of electronic field guides being developed by researchers from Columbia University, the University of Maryland, and the Smithsonian Institution. The free mobile apps use visual recognition software to help identify tree species from photographs of their leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Environmental Observer (LEO) Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leo-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/leo-network/</guid>
      <description>Local Environmental Observer (LEO) Network View the project here.
Overview The Local Environmental Observer (LEO) Network is a group of local observers and topic experts who share knowledge about unusual animal, environment, and weather events. With LEO, you can connect with others in your community, share observations, raise awareness, and find answers about significant environmental events. You can also engage with topic experts in many different organizations and become part of a broader observer community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Coral Reefs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</guid>
      <description>Mexican Coral Reefs View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Mexico’s Pacific Coast is home to some of the world’s most biodiverse coral reefs, underwater communities that support sharks, turtles, and other marine life. They also support human lives by buffering the coastline from intense storms and providing livelihoods from fishing and tourism. Yet these reefs are imperiled by ocean acidification, more frequent and powerful storms due to climate change, and damage from human overuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkweeds and Monarchs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/milkweeds-and-monarchs/</guid>
      <description>Milkweeds and Monarchs View the project here.
Overview Help preserve the majestic monarch butterfly.
Soaring from Mexico into the United States and Canada, monarch butterflies are searching for one thing: milkweed plants. Monarch butterflies are beautiful, charismatic insects known for their long-distance migration and their reliance on milkweeds (Asclepias species). Milkweeds are the only plants on which monarchs lay their eggs. After the eggs hatch, the caterpillars, also called larvae, eat milkweed leaves to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monarch (Butterfly) Larva Monitoring Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/monarch-larva-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/monarch-larva-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Monarch (Butterfly) Larva Monitoring Project View the project here.
Overview The Monarch Larva Monitoring Project (MLMP) is a citizen science project involving volunteers from across the United States and Canada in monarch research. It was developed in 1997 by researchers at the University of Minnesota to collect long-term data on larval monarch populations and milkweed habitat. The project focuses on monarch distribution and abundance during the breeding season in North America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s Notebook</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook View the project here.
Overview Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook gathers information on plant and animal phenology across the U.S. to be used for decision-making on local, national and global scales to ensure the continued vitality of our environment.
Scientists alone cannot collect enough data: They need your help. Join more than 15,000 other naturalists across the nation in taking the pulse of our planet. You&amp;rsquo;ll use scientifically-vetted observation guidelines, developed for over 1000 species, to ensure data are useful to researchers and decision-makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood Nestwatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/neighborhood-nestwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/neighborhood-nestwatch/</guid>
      <description>Neighborhood Nestwatch View the project here.
Overview This Smithsonian citizen science program provides an outdoor educational experience for backyard wildlife enthusiasts and underserved youth. Participants contribute to important scientific research by re-sighting banded birds and monitoring nests. The Neighborhood Nestwatch approach features face-to-face interaction on an annual basis between Smithsonian scientists, participants and neighborhood birds. The program takes place in metro-area backyards, as well as at under-resourced schools in cities throughout the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANOPTES</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-panoptes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-panoptes/</guid>
      <description>Panoptic Astronomical Networked Observatories for a Public Transiting Exoplanets Survey (PANOPTES) View the project here.
Overview PANOPTES is an open source citizen science project designed to find transiting exoplanets with digital cameras. The goal of PANOPTES is to establish a global network of of robotic cameras run by amateur astronomers and schools (or anyone!) in order to monitor, as continuously as possible, a very large number of stars. For more general information about the project, including the science case and resources for interested individuals, see the project overview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenology and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-phenology-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Phenology and Climate View the project here.
Overview Research Question: How is climate change affecting plant phenology?
Help us understand how plants are responding to this year&amp;rsquo;s seasons and longer-term changes in climate.
How plants react to seasonal change has a big impact on the environment. Because plants are at the base of the food chain, anything that affects plants can impact other parts of the ecosystem. Phenology is important because it affects plants ability to produce fruits and seeds and food availability for other animals like birds and squirrels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants of Concern</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/plants-of-concern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/plants-of-concern/</guid>
      <description>Plants of Concern View the project here.
Overview Interested in monitoring rare plants and joining our team? Fantastic!
Plants of Concern is active in Northeastern and Southern Illinois. We invite you to join us in monitoring rare plants in these regions.
We offer online training through a series of six video modules that you can view at any time. All modules together take approximately 45 minutes to watch. Short quizzes (less than 5 min each) separate each module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plastic Origins</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/plasticorigins/</guid>
      <description>Plastic Origins View the project here.
Overview Plastic Origins is a project initiated by the not-for-profit Surfrider Foundation Europe in search of solutions to address the source of ocean pollution. Supported by citizens, associations, scientists, and socially responsible companies, the Plastic Origins project aims to map plastic pollution in European rivers by applying participatory science and Artificial Intelligence technology. This mapping data helps to identify areas of high impact, gain a deeper understanding of the problem on the field, and measure the evolution of pollution over time as well as to raise awareness among political decision-makers on the local, national, and European levels and urge them to act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pollinators and Climate</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/budburst-pollinators-and-climate/</guid>
      <description>Pollinators and Climate View the project here.
Overview Help us understand how plant-pollinator interactions are responding to a changing climate.
Changes in pollination has significant impacts on how we humans live our lives and interact with our environment on a daily basis. Pollinator and pollinator health changes the success of fruiting for plants and our food supply and therefore our health. We know that phenological events can vary from year to year, but how are pollinators affected by these variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project FeederWatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/project-feederwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/project-feederwatch/</guid>
      <description>Project FeederWatch View the project here.
Overview Project FeederWatch turns your love of feeding birds into scientific discoveries. FeederWatch is a November-April survey of birds that visit backyards, nature centers, community areas, and other locales in North America. You don’t even need a feeder! All you need is an area with plantings, habitat, water or food that attracts birds. The schedule is completely flexible. Count your birds for as long as you like on days of your choosing, then enter your counts online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/junocam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/junocam/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview We’re calling all amateur astronomers to upload their telescopic images and data of Jupiter. These uploads are critical for providing context for new JunoCam images and will help NASA successfully plan the future of the mission.
If you&amp;rsquo;re a veteran astrophotographer or if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting started with your first telescope, we highly recommend you read our Submission Guidelines before submitting data. In the PDF you&amp;rsquo;ll find information about the best capture and process workflows as well as links to free software and tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardust@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/stardust-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/stardust-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Stardust@home View the project here.
Overview The interstellar dust particles returned to Earth by the Stardust mission are the first such pristine dust particles ever collected in space, and scientists are eager to “get their hands” on them. We estimate that Stardust collected less than 100 interstellar dust particles. They are tiny-only about a micron (a millionth of a meter) in size! These miniscule particles were captured in an aerogel collector about 1,000 square centimeters in size, and in about 150 square centimeters of aluminum metal foils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Target NEOs!</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/target-neo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/target-neo/</guid>
      <description>Target NEOs! View the project here.
Overview Target NEOs!* is an exciting opportunity for amateur astronomers to participate in a long-term citizen science project that will contribute to basic scientific understanding of near-Earth objects (NEOs). Observers collect data about asteroids on a selected list and submit images and corresponding reports. These observations support spacecraft missions in progress and aid future mission designers and scientists. Citizen scientists’ astrometry and photometry data will enable scientists to test theoretical models about these objects to refine orbits and taxonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timber Tracking</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/timber-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Timber Tracking View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Do you care about healthy forests? You can apply to join this project if you are a hiker, a birder, a biker, a forager, or a tree lover to explore the hardwood forests of the eastern and central United States in search of black walnut trees!.
One of the most valuable hardwood species in the United States, black walnut trees are threatened by timber poaching across the 30+ states in their range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR)</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/traits-across-species-ranges/</guid>
      <description>Traits Across Species Ranges (TASpeR) View the project here.
Overview Traits Across Species’ Ranges is a community science project focused on understanding how variation within plant species influences the size and movement of different pools of elements (e.g., carbon, nitrogen) on the surface of the Earth.
For 2021 we are currently focused on developing partnerships with community scientist groups and individuals to survey patterns of green vs. freshly fallen leaf nutrient concentrations (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild and Scenic Rivers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/wild-and-scenic-rivers/</guid>
      <description>Wild and Scenic Rivers View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
This is a multi-year effort to sample National Wild and Scenic Rivers. The project spans from northern Alaska to southeast Florida, from small scenic creeks to wild raging rivers.
The National Wild and Scenic Rivers System contributes 10% of drinking water throughout the United States. In addition, these rivers are essential for their cultural, recreational, and natural value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
