<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contribute</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/about/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/about/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Contribute via email If you notice any typos, know a project that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been added yet, or have suggestions for the website, email me with all the relevant information and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back with you as soon as I can.
Contribute via GitHub 🌟 If you&amp;rsquo;re new to using GitHub, I have a guide just for you written here!
Full contribution guidelines and instructions are available on GitHub in CONTRIBUTING.md.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use this site</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/about/how-to-use-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/about/how-to-use-this-site/</guid>
      <description>Project Delve is nice and simple. All content is viewable from one single menu, so you can&amp;rsquo;t get lost.
Sidebar/Menu Sections If you&amp;rsquo;re using a desktop computer, you will see a blue sidebar on the left side of your screen. If you&amp;rsquo;re on mobile, this sidebar will be tucked into a drop-down menu, which you can find by clicking the symbol with three horizontal lines in the top left corner of your device&amp;rsquo;s screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/about/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/about/sources/</guid>
      <description>As all scientists learn, one of the most important things when sharing work with others is to be transparent about your sources, methods, and evidence. Here are mine.
Hub websites you can sign up on to help with (and keep track of) a lot of volunteer science projects at once:  Zooniverse - The world’s largest and most popular platform for people-powered research. World Community Grid - Donate your device’s spare computing power to help scientists solve the world’s biggest problems in health and sustainability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
