<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>american history on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/american-history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in american history on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/american-history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DIY History</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</guid>
      <description>DIY History View the project here.
Overview DIY History lets you do it yourself to help make historic artifacts easier to use. Our digital library holds hundreds of thousands of items—much more than library staff could ever catalog alone, so we&amp;rsquo;re appealing to the public to help out by attaching text in the form of transcriptions, tags, and comments. Through &amp;ldquo;crowdsourcing,&amp;rdquo; or engaging volunteers to contribute effort toward large-scale goals, these mass quantities of digitized artifacts become searchable, allowing researchers to quickly seek out specific information, and general users to browse and enjoy the materials more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix It&#43; Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</guid>
      <description>Fix It+ Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting View the project here.
Overview Help the American Archive of Public Broadcasting fix computer-generated transcripts from thousands of historic public broadcasting programs from across the country.
We need you to help ensure that public media remains accessible—not just today&amp;rsquo;s broadcasts, but the archive all the way back to the beginning.
FIX IT+ users can correct transcripts for any of the historic programs available in the AAPB&amp;rsquo;s Online Reading Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom on the Move</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview We need your help to turn our collection of handwritten correspondence between anti-slavery activists in the 19th century into texts that can be more easily read and researched by students, teachers, historians, and big data applications.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library of Congress: By the People</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</guid>
      <description>Library of Congress: By the People View the project here.
Overview Help transcribe Library of Congress documents. Volunteers create and review transcriptions to improve search, access, and discovery of these pages from history.
By the People invites you to transcribe, review, and tag digitized pages from the Library’s collections. Everyone is welcome to take part! Volunteer-created transcriptions improve search, readability, and access to handwritten and typed documents for everyone, including people who are not fully sighted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Public Library: What&#39;s on the menu?</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</guid>
      <description>New York Public Library: What&amp;rsquo;s on the menu? View the project here.
Overview Help The New York Public Library improve a unique collection!
We’re transcribing our historical restaurant menus, dish by dish, so that they can be searched by what people were eating back in the day. It’s a big job so we need your help!
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers of the War Department</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</guid>
      <description>Papers of the War Department View the project here.
Overview The War Department office was established in 1790. It burned in 1800.
For decades historians believed that its files, and the window they provide into the early federal government, had been lost forever. This collection unites copies of the lost files in a digital archive that reconstitutes this invaluable historical resource. Our community of transcribers are working to create full text transcriptions of every possible document in the collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Unlock the past! Transcribe letters and diaries to help with historical research.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan White Letters</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</guid>
      <description>Ryan White Letters View the project here.
Overview The Ryan White Letters Collection consists of almost 6000 letters and cards written to Ryan White and his family during the last years of his life. After being diagnosed with HIV/AIDS at the age of 13, Ryan’s legal fight to attend school despite his disease brought him to the forefront of public discussion about AIDS and its victims in the late 1980s. Thousands of letters came to Ryan from all over the world, many of them from children and teens who had seen his story in the media and wanted Ryan to know he was loved and supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smithsonian National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</guid>
      <description>Smithsonian National Archives View the project here.
Overview Become a Smithsonian Digital Volunteer and help us make historical documents and biodiversity data more accessible.
Join 55,775 &amp;ldquo;volunpeers&amp;rdquo; to add more to the total 912,645 pages of field notes, diaries, ledgers, logbooks, currency proof sheets, photo albums, manuscripts, biodiversity specimens labels, and historic audio recordings, that have been collaboratively transcribed and reviewed since June 2013.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford University Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</guid>
      <description>Stanford University Archives View the project here.
Overview The Stanford University Archives is the official repository for records of Stanford University and serves as its institutional memory. The Archives collects, preserves, administers, and promotes access to materials in any format that document the history of Stanford, including its founders, administration, faculty, students, and alumni/ae. Our holdings include more than 30,000 linear feet of material and 20+ TB of electronic records within 2,200+ collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</guid>
      <description>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project View the project here.
Overview The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project belongs to all of us who live in Berkeley. We invite you to participate by making a contribution, e-mailing us current or historical photos that will add to this website, or writing and sending us your own e-Plaque texts with photos.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</guid>
      <description>Transcribe View the project here.
Overview Transcribe is the Library of Virginia’s collaborative online workspace where the public can participate in enhancing access to many of our amazing collections documenting over 400 years of Virginia history, people, and culture. This is the perfect opportunity for participants to dig deep into our collections and transcribe historical materials from five to ten active projects at a time. From peace to wartime, court records to letters home, and conspiracies to political statements, there will be something for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</guid>
      <description>United States National Archives View the project here.
Overview Welcome to our Citizen Archivist program. You can contribute to the National Archives Catalog by tagging, transcribing and adding comments to our records, making them more accessible and searchable. Join us! Every contribution you make helps unlock history.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
