<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ornithology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/ornithology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ornithology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/ornithology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Audubon Christmas Bird Count</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/audubon-bird-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/audubon-bird-count/</guid>
      <description>Audubon Christmas Bird Count View the project here.
Overview The Christmas Bird Count occurs December 14 to January 5 every year.
Frank Chapman and 26 other conservationists initiated the Christmas Bird Count (CBC) as a way of promoting conservation by counting, rather than hunting, birds on Christmas Day of 1900. Some counts have been running every year since then and the CBC now happens in over 20 countries in the western hemisphere!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Urban Birds Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/celebrate-urban-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/celebrate-urban-birds/</guid>
      <description>Celebrate Urban Birds Project View the project here.
Overview From the Cornell Lab of Ornithology.
 Learn to identify your regional birds. Choose your birdwatching area. Watch birds for 10 minutes a day for 3 days. Report your results!  Our vision is to embrace community-led scientific research and programming and promote inclusive, accessible, and equitable birdwatching for all. We believe that birds have the power to connect us — as long as we intentionally value and center the power of equitable co-creation in birdwatching, monitoring, and conservation projects, and focus on culture through local leadership, creativity, and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBird</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/ebird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/ebird/</guid>
      <description>eBird View the project here.
Overview eBird transforms the global birding community’s passion for birds into a powerful resource for research, conservation, and education. Your sightings contribute to hundreds of conservation decisions and peer-reviewed papers, thousands of student projects, and help inform bird research worldwide.
eBird is among the world’s largest biodiversity-related science projects, with more than 100 million bird sightings contributed annually by eBirders around the world and an average participation growth rate of approximately 20% year over year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood Nestwatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/neighborhood-nestwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/neighborhood-nestwatch/</guid>
      <description>Neighborhood Nestwatch View the project here.
Overview This Smithsonian citizen science program provides an outdoor educational experience for backyard wildlife enthusiasts and underserved youth. Participants contribute to important scientific research by re-sighting banded birds and monitoring nests. The Neighborhood Nestwatch approach features face-to-face interaction on an annual basis between Smithsonian scientists, participants and neighborhood birds. The program takes place in metro-area backyards, as well as at under-resourced schools in cities throughout the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nest Quest Go: Mourning Doves</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nqg-mourning-doves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nqg-mourning-doves/</guid>
      <description>Nest Quest Go: Mourning Doves View the project here.
Overview Join the Cornell Lab of Ornithology&amp;rsquo;s Citizen-Science Project, NestWatch, in understanding the historical nesting patterns of Mourning Doves. In North America, Mourning Doves are the most abundant and widespread game bird.
While they are hunted in North America, these nest-record cards demonstrate a different kind of hunting: the quest for data!
These nest record cards are a subset of a larger collection of more than 300,000 nest records that NestWatch is working on digitizing and transcribing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project FeederWatch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/project-feederwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/project-feederwatch/</guid>
      <description>Project FeederWatch View the project here.
Overview Project FeederWatch turns your love of feeding birds into scientific discoveries. FeederWatch is a November-April survey of birds that visit backyards, nature centers, community areas, and other locales in North America. You don’t even need a feeder! All you need is an area with plantings, habitat, water or food that attracts birds. The schedule is completely flexible. Count your birds for as long as you like on days of your choosing, then enter your counts online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seabird Soundscapes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/seabird-soundscapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/seabird-soundscapes/</guid>
      <description>Seabird Soundscapes View the project here.
Overview Join our team of citizen-scientists and help us explore the marine soundscapes of wild seabirds by listening to and classifying the sounds they make at sea.
Seabird Soundscapes is about expanding our understanding about seabird life at sea by exploring their marine soundscapes. When seabirds move, feed, vocalise and interact with their surroundings they produce sounds that help us learn about the activities they engage with in their environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</guid>
      <description>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl View the project here.
Overview The western burrowing owl needs our help. Unusual among owl species, this pint-sized raptor lives in elaborate underground burrows. These owls cannot dig their own burrows, and instead “reuse” excavated dens dug by ground squirrels and other fossorial (burrowing) animals. With its penchant for open, native grasslands, the burrowing owl has been on a collision course with humans throughout much of Southern California.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
