<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>medical on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/medical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in medical on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/medical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Health</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</guid>
      <description>Addressing Health View the project here.
Overview Why did the UK&amp;rsquo;s Post Office employees in the nineteenth century retire from work? Some reached retirement age but many had to end their careers early because of ill health. Be a part of this Wellcome-funded project to find out what Post Office workers&#39; lives tell us about the history of health and wellbeing in the Victorian period. Transcribe the records of their career histories from images of documents held at the Postal Museum, London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Endo</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/citizen-endo/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Endo View the project here.
Overview In order to study a disease, we need to know what it looks like. When it comes to endometriosis, there are many different ways in which the disease can present itself in patients. There is a disconnect between how doctors think about the disease and what patients experience on a daily basis. Bridging this gap is critical to further research on endometriosis. Citizen Endo will use a series of studies to better understand the disease from the perspective of patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID.SI</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/covid/</guid>
      <description>CITIZEN SCIENCE AND THE FIGHT AGAINST THE CORONAVIRUS (COVID.SI) View the project here.
Overview “CITIZEN SCIENCE AND THE FIGHT AGAINST THE CORONAVIRUS” is an open project by a collective of good-willed researchers and volunteers, who with to contribute a stone in the mosaic of the full picture of SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19, with the sum of our work, knowledge and experience. The group is lead by dr. Črtomir Podlipnik and dr. Marko Jukić, experts with years of experience in computer supported molecular modelling, pharmaceutical chemistry and chemo/bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eterna</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eterna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eterna/</guid>
      <description>Eterna View the project here.
Overview Design molecular medicines by solving puzzles!
Eterna is a game that allows players to design RNAs by solving puzzles. Each puzzle represents a target RNA shape or a set of design requirements. Players design the pattern of bases they think will best meet the requirements. Scientists then create the molecules the players have designed and test them in the lab. The lab results are returned to the players, who can use them to improve their designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyewire</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/eyewire/</guid>
      <description>Eyewire View the project here.
Overview Eyewire is a game to map the brain. Anyone can play and you need no scientific background. Hundreds of thousands of people from around the world already do. Together we are mapping the 3D structure of neurons and advancing our quest to understand ourselves.
By joining Eyewire, you can help map the connectome, starting with connections between retinal neurons. Eyewire gameplay advances neuroscience by helping researchers discover how neurons connect and network to process information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folding@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/folding-at-home/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Install our software to become a citizen scientist and contribute your compute power to help fight global health threats like COVID19, Alzheimer’s Disease, and cancer!
Folding@Home began in October 2000 in the lab of Dr. Vijay Pande at Stanford University. Since 2019, the project has been in the hands of Dr. Gregory Bowman, a former Pande Lab graduate student. In addition to the numerous scientists who have worked on the project over the years, F@h has been supported by thousands of dedicated volunteers who have enabled outstanding scientific research and computational achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUGRID.net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gpugrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/gpugrid/</guid>
      <description>GPUGRID.net View the project here.
Overview GPUGRID.net is a distributed computing infrastructure devoted to biomedical research. Thanks to the contribution of volunteers, GPUGRID scientists can perform molecular simulations to understand the function of proteins in health and disease.
This is a volunteer distributed computing project for biomedical research from the Universitat Pompeu Fabra in Barcelona (Spain). GPUGRID is made of many graphics cards (GPUs) joined together to deliver high-performance all-atom biomolecular simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Stop TB</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/help-stop-tb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/help-stop-tb/</guid>
      <description>Help Stop TB View the project here.
Overview Tuberculosis (TB) is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most dangerous diseases, and has plagued humans for thousands of years. About one-third of the world&amp;rsquo;s population harbors the TB bacterium, with 1.5 million people dying in 2014 alone, and the World Health Organization now ranks TB alongside HIV as the world&amp;rsquo;s deadliest infectious disease. Through Help Stop TB, researchers are using World Community Grid to help fight this deadly disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</guid>
      <description>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service View the project here.
Overview Transcribing a hundred years of seafarer&amp;rsquo;s medical data from the Dreadnought Seamen&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in Greenwich, 1826-1930.
&amp;lsquo;HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service&amp;rsquo;, refers to the records of the Dreadnought Seamen’s Hospital at Greenwich. This was the main clinical site of the Seamen’s Hospital Society (now Seafarer’s Hospital Society), founded with the philanthropic mission of providing relief to sick and injured seafarers of all nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Cancer Markers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mapping-cancer-markers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/mapping-cancer-markers/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Mapping Cancer Markers on World Community Grid aims to identify the markers associated with various types of cancer. The project is analyzing millions of data points collected from thousands of healthy and cancerous patient tissue samples. These include tissues with lung, ovarian, prostate, pancreatic and breast cancers. By comparing these different data points, researchers aim to identify patterns of markers for different cancers and correlate them with different outcomes, including responsiveness to various treatment options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/node-code-breakers/</guid>
      <description>Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes View the project here.
Overview We are running ‘Node Code Breakers: looking for patterns in lymph nodes’ to analyse images of lymph nodes from breast cancer patients. This project will generate data that will be used to help improve our AI model performance. We are trying to find the germinal centres, the light pink circles in lymph nodes. When the immune system spot something foreign, new immune cells were produced in germinal centres of lymph nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Insulin</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/open-insulin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/open-insulin/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview The Open Insulin Foundation is a non-profit creating the means for communities in-need to have local sources of safe, affordable, high-quality insulin.
Our governance is shared between people with diabetes and people working on the project. Our working groups collaborate to develop new tools for open drug production, from R&amp;amp;D to manufacturing for medical use. Our goal is that people living with diabetes and their communities can own and govern the organizations that produce the medicine they depend on to survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Flu</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/quantified-flu/</guid>
      <description>Quantified Flu View the project here.
Overview The question we want to answer is: Can the various physiological parameters tracked by our wearables help to predict when we’re getting sick? With the COVID-19 pandemic influencing all of our lives right now, this question seems more timely than ever. But it&amp;rsquo;s not only the pandemic, this question equally applies to the flu and the common cold!
There is some preliminary data which shows that the data from wearables (like resting heart rate and sleep quality) might be predictive of coming down with a cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiDock@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/sidock-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/sidock-at-home/</guid>
      <description>SiDock@home View the project here.
Overview Sidock@home is an international volunteer computing project aimed at drug discovery. The first mission of the project is discovery of possible drugs against the SARS-CoV-2 virus. It started as an extension of the project COVID.SI to engage the BOINC community into the drug discovery.
You can help with your computer. With the help of BOINC, you will download a subset of compounds on your computer, examine the compounds in the context of the studied target and send the results to a server where they are collected for later analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ubiqomix/</guid>
      <description>UbiQomix Microbiome Exploration View the project here.
Overview Questions about how people make sense of and engage with their personal omic information including their personal genomics and microbiome data, and how comfortable they feel about sharing such information in order to advance scientific and biomedical research, are not only of paramount importance for society and policy makers, but also a pressing issue for HCI researchers. Funded by the National Science Foundation, and in collaboration with Open Humans, we investigate how to design effective interaction techniques to empower nonexpert users to engage with and make sense of their personal omic information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
