<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>marine biology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/marine-biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in marine biology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/marine-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Bay Horseshoe Crab Survey</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/delaware-bay-crabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/delaware-bay-crabs/</guid>
      <description>Delaware Bay Horseshoe Crab Survey View the project here.
Overview The Horseshoe Crab, Limulus polyphemus, visits the Delaware Bay Shore each year for spawning purposes. Through the work of volunteers, the spawning population is recorded to study the American Horseshoe Crab.
In 1990, the first organized survey of spawning horseshoe crabs in the Delaware Bay began. Now, every May and June during the full and new moon evening high tides, volunteers annually donate their time to count crabs on the beaches of the Delaware Bay in both Delaware and New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyes of the Reef Hawaii</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/eyes-of-the-reef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/eyes-of-the-reef/</guid>
      <description>Eyes of the Reef Hawaii View the project here.
Overview The Eyes of the Reef Network is a volunteer member-based organization developed to increase public awareness and engage communities in the monitoring and reporting of coral bleaching and disease, marine invasive species, Crown-of-Thorn Sea Star (COTS) outbreaks and other reef diseases.
The statewide network is the first tier of a rapid response protocol developed by the Division of Aquatic Resources and the Climate Change and Marine Disease Local Action Strategy, implemented by Reef Check Hawai‘i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Coral Reefs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/mexican-coral-reefs/</guid>
      <description>Mexican Coral Reefs View the project here.
Overview SELECTIVE PROJECT. Strict requirements.
Mexico’s Pacific Coast is home to some of the world’s most biodiverse coral reefs, underwater communities that support sharks, turtles, and other marine life. They also support human lives by buffering the coastline from intense storms and providing livelihoods from fishing and tourism. Yet these reefs are imperiled by ocean acidification, more frequent and powerful storms due to climate change, and damage from human overuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeMO-Net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nemo-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/nemo-net/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview NeMO-Net is a single player iPad game where players help NASA classify coral reefs by painting 3D and 2D images of coral. Players can rate the classifications of other players and level up in the food chain as they explore and classify coral reefs and other shallow marine environments and creatures from locations all over the world!
Data from the NeMO-Net game is fed to NASA NeMO-Net, the first neural multi-modal observation and training network for global coral reef assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OceanEYEs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/oceaneyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/oceaneyes/</guid>
      <description>OceanEYEs View the project here.
Overview NOAA scientists need your help to count fish and improve data used in management of the Hawaiʻi “Deep 7” bottomfish fishery! NOAA&amp;rsquo;s Pacific Islands Fisheries Science Center deploys stereo-camera systems on the seafloor to help monitor populations of deep-water snappers and groupers. The local commercial fishery in Hawaiʻi targets these fish primarily. Each camera can record tens of thousands of images! Human observers annotate the images to count and measure each species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spyfish Aotearoa</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/spyfish-aotearoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/spyfish-aotearoa/</guid>
      <description>Spyfish Aotearoa View the project here.
Overview Our team deploys baited underwater cameras in marine reserves all over Aotearoa New Zealand to monitor the abundance and diversity of marine life. Help us identify and count the species of fish recorded by the cameras. Your classifications will be used to determine the effectiveness of the reserves, inform marine management, and protect our taonga (treasured) species.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Koster seafloor observatory</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/koster-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/koster-observatory/</guid>
      <description>The Koster seafloor observatory View the project here.
Overview At the Koster seafloor observatory we want to know how climate change and human activities influence Sweden&amp;rsquo;s marine ecosystems.
For the last 20 years, we have used Remotely Operated Vehicles and cameras to monitor the Kosterhavets National Park. A highly-diverse and unique marine reserve in the south of Sweden. Now, we need your help identifying the habitat, species, and presence of litter recorded in over 3,000 hours of underwater videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale Chat</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whale-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/whale-chat/</guid>
      <description>Whale Chat View the project here.
Overview The current development of deep learning and artificial intelligence allows a new approach to trying to understand the whale song. Deep learning models could help with identification of humpback sounds and unsupervised learning models could help to classify the song “units” in perhaps different ways. This project aims to investigate humpback songs from different years and regions, to identify humpback whale sounds in recordings, to classify these calls or units, and eventually to see if we can find individually distinct calls or units (the same way we do in Manatee Chat).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
