<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>government on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in government on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents View the project here.
Overview Help turn our collection of 17th-19th century handwritten documents relating to Maine&amp;rsquo;s land history into text that may be more easily read, keyword searchable, and accessed by students, teachers, and historians.
Maine Historical Society received a grant in the summer of 2020 from the National Endowment for the Humanities to fully digitized three significant land collections covering 1625-1893. In addition to digitization, Maine Historical is making an effort to transcribe these collections for easier access to their historic content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers of the War Department</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</guid>
      <description>Papers of the War Department View the project here.
Overview The War Department office was established in 1790. It burned in 1800.
For decades historians believed that its files, and the window they provide into the early federal government, had been lost forever. This collection unites copies of the lost files in a digital archive that reconstitutes this invaluable historical resource. Our community of transcribers are working to create full text transcriptions of every possible document in the collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Map Corps</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/humanities/national-map-corps/</guid>
      <description>The National Map Corps View the project here.
Overview By updating and verifying structures data, volunteers are making significant contributions to USGS National Structures Database, The National Map, and ultimately U.S. Topo Maps!
TNMCorps is an online crowdsourcing mapping project with volunteers successfully editing structures in all 50 States, Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands.
Anyone with an interest in contributing can volunteer. It is easy to sign up and get started!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</guid>
      <description>United States National Archives View the project here.
Overview Welcome to our Citizen Archivist program. You can contribute to the National Archives Catalog by tagging, transcribing and adding comments to our records, making them more accessible and searchable. Join us! Every contribution you make helps unlock history.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
