<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Historical Projects on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Historical Projects on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/historical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Health</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/addressing-health/</guid>
      <description>Addressing Health View the project here.
Overview Why did the UK&amp;rsquo;s Post Office employees in the nineteenth century retire from work? Some reached retirement age but many had to end their careers early because of ill health. Be a part of this Wellcome-funded project to find out what Post Office workers&#39; lives tell us about the history of health and wellbeing in the Victorian period. Transcribe the records of their career histories from images of documents held at the Postal Museum, London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents of Enslavement</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/agents-of-enslavement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/agents-of-enslavement/</guid>
      <description>Agents of Enslavement View the project here.
Overview Agents of Enslavement? is a research project, which seeks to explore the ways in which colonial newspapers in the Caribbean facilitated and challenged the practice of slavery.
It also seeks to identify the networks and voices of enslaved people hidden within these newspapers.
These crowdsourcing tasks are integral to both these aims as your help will create new datasets for analysis.
One of the goals of this project is to create a database of enslaved people identified within these newspapers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancestry® World Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ancestry-world-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ancestry-world-archives/</guid>
      <description>Ancestry® World Archives View the project here.
Overview The Ancestry® World Archives Project is volunteers from around the world creating searchable record indexes from digitized records. We gather historical records and scan them into our system. You look at the records and type out what you see (so that the facts in the records become searchable). The index you create is added to Ancestry’s free collections and is accessible to anyone who wants to search it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/bb-transcribing-maine/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Borders: Transcribing Historic Maine Land Documents View the project here.
Overview Help turn our collection of 17th-19th century handwritten documents relating to Maine&amp;rsquo;s land history into text that may be more easily read, keyword searchable, and accessed by students, teachers, and historians.
Maine Historical Society received a grant in the summer of 2020 from the National Endowment for the Humanities to fully digitized three significant land collections covering 1625-1893. In addition to digitization, Maine Historical is making an effort to transcribe these collections for easier access to their historic content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/canadian-wildlife/</guid>
      <description>Canadian wildlife: notes from the field View the project here.
Overview The British Library wildlife and environmental sounds archive was established in 1969 by the ornithologist Patrick Seller and the BBC radio producer Jeffrey Boswell, with the endeavour to create a national collection that can document, preserve and share the sounds of nature for future generations to study and enjoy. Since then we have amassed over 6.5 million recordings and are now one of the most comprehensive collections in the world, used by scientists and amateur naturalists alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corresponding with Quakers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/corresponding-with-quakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/corresponding-with-quakers/</guid>
      <description>Corresponding with Quakers View the project here.
Overview The Quakers of Ballitore, Ireland, were a small group, but they have fascinating links to many major political issues of the period: abolitionism, women&amp;rsquo;s rights, religious tensions, global migration, and the American and French Revolutions.
Corresponding with Quakers is an ongoing, collaborative research project investigating the Ballitore Collection held at UCSB Library’s Special Research Collections. The Ballitore Collection features more than 2,500 documents related to the Irish Quaker community of Ballitore, Ireland, including letters, journals, notebooks, and dream accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davy Notebooks Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/davy-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>Davy Notebooks Project View the project here.
Overview Help us to transcribe the manuscript notebooks of Sir Humphry Davy – one of the most significant and famous figures in the scientific and literary culture of early nineteenth-century Britain, Europe, and America.
Davy’s scientific accomplishments include: conducting pioneering research into the physiological effects of nitrous oxide (often called ‘laughing gas’); isolating seven chemical elements (magnesium, calcium, potassium, sodium, strontium, barium, and boron) and establishing the elemental status of chlorine and iodine; inventing a miners’ safety lamp; developing the electrochemical protection of the copper sheeting of Royal Navy vessels; conserving the Herculaneum papyri; and writing an influential text on agricultural chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY History</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/diy-history/</guid>
      <description>DIY History View the project here.
Overview DIY History lets you do it yourself to help make historic artifacts easier to use. Our digital library holds hundreds of thousands of items—much more than library staff could ever catalog alone, so we&amp;rsquo;re appealing to the public to help out by attaching text in the form of transcriptions, tags, and comments. Through &amp;ldquo;crowdsourcing,&amp;rdquo; or engaging volunteers to contribute effort toward large-scale goals, these mass quantities of digitized artifacts become searchable, allowing researchers to quickly seek out specific information, and general users to browse and enjoy the materials more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Name Counts</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/every-name-counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/every-name-counts/</guid>
      <description>Every Name Counts View the project here.
Overview With the initiative #everynamecounts, the Arolsen Archives aim to establish a digital memorial to the people persecuted by the Nazis. Future generations should be able to remember the names and identities of the victims and put faces to history.
Thousands of volunteers are contributing to this first major digital memorial, which will enable people all over the world to access and search the data themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix It&#43; Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/public-broadcasting-archives/</guid>
      <description>Fix It+ Project: American Archive of Public Broadcasting View the project here.
Overview Help the American Archive of Public Broadcasting fix computer-generated transcripts from thousands of historic public broadcasting programs from across the country.
We need you to help ensure that public media remains accessible—not just today&amp;rsquo;s broadcasts, but the archive all the way back to the beginning.
FIX IT+ users can correct transcripts for any of the historic programs available in the AAPB&amp;rsquo;s Online Reading Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom on the Move</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/freedom-on-the-move/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview We need your help to turn our collection of handwritten correspondence between anti-slavery activists in the 19th century into texts that can be more easily read and researched by students, teachers, historians, and big data applications.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/hms-nhs/</guid>
      <description>HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service View the project here.
Overview Transcribing a hundred years of seafarer&amp;rsquo;s medical data from the Dreadnought Seamen&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in Greenwich, 1826-1930.
&amp;lsquo;HMS NHS: The Nautical Health Service&amp;rsquo;, refers to the records of the Dreadnought Seamen’s Hospital at Greenwich. This was the main clinical site of the Seamen’s Hospital Society (now Seafarer’s Hospital Society), founded with the philanthropic mission of providing relief to sick and injured seafarers of all nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library of Congress: By the People</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/by-the-people/</guid>
      <description>Library of Congress: By the People View the project here.
Overview Help transcribe Library of Congress documents. Volunteers create and review transcriptions to improve search, access, and discovery of these pages from history.
By the People invites you to transcribe, review, and tag digitized pages from the Library’s collections. Everyone is welcome to take part! Volunteer-created transcriptions improve search, readability, and access to handwritten and typed documents for everyone, including people who are not fully sighted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macdonald Dictionary</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/macdonald-dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/macdonald-dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Macdonald Dictionary View the project here.
Overview George Ranald Macdonald (1891 - 1967) was a farmer and local historian in Canterbury, New Zealand. After retiring he began volunteering at Canterbury Museum. When Museum visitors mentioned there was a need for a biographical dictionary of colonial personalities to help with research, Macdonald volunteered for the project.
Compiled by Macdonald between 1952 and 1964, and comprised of over 12000 index cards with biographical information on over 22000 people, the dictionary took about 12 years to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the ANZACs</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/measuring-anzacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/measuring-anzacs/</guid>
      <description>Measuring the ANZACs View the project here.
Overview The Measuring the ANZACs project brings together an international team of researchers, community connections around New Zealand’s military history from the Auckland War Memorial Museum, and the power of the Zooniverse community to explore, analyze, and digitize original World War I personnel files from Archives New Zealand.
Data gathered from Measuring the ANZACs will be used for three main purposes:
 To create a complete and rich index of persons who served in the New Zealand military in World War I and the South African War (also called the Second Boer War).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Public Library: What&#39;s on the menu?</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/nypl-menu/</guid>
      <description>New York Public Library: What&amp;rsquo;s on the menu? View the project here.
Overview Help The New York Public Library improve a unique collection!
We’re transcribing our historical restaurant menus, dish by dish, so that they can be searched by what people were eating back in the day. It’s a big job so we need your help!
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - Naval Rendezvous</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-naval-rendezvous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-naval-rendezvous/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - Naval Rendezvous View the project here.
Overview This project seeks volunteers to help transcribe sea ice and weather observations from the logbooks of military vessels that sailed Arctic seas in the 19th and 20th century. This information is used to improve climate and sea ice data sets used by scientists every day.
To learn how to participate in this project, visit the Old Weather forum here.
In this project we use customized LibreOffice spreadsheets to guide the collection and organization of information extracted from the logbooks posted online, as in the example below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - Shipping Office</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-shipping-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-shipping-office/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - Shipping Office View the project here.
Overview This project seeks volunteers to help transcribe sea ice and weather observations from the logbooks of whaling ships that sailed Arctic seas from 1849 to 1912. This information is used to improve climate and sea ice data sets used by scientists every day.
To learn how to participate in this project, visit the Old Weather forum here.
In this project we use Microsoft Excel to guide the collection and organization of information extracted from the logbooks posted online, as in the example below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - WW2</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - WW2 View the project here.
Overview Help recover hidden weather data collected by the U.S. Navy during World War II!
The purpose of this project is to recover hidden marine weather data recorded in U.S. Navy ships&#39; logbooks during World War II. Like all Old Weather projects, these data will be used to drive sophisticated computer models that help us understand weather and climate in extraordinary detail. But there is another goal that is just as vital - to uncover the source of a mysterious distortion in the Navy temperature data collected during the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers of the War Department</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/war-department-papers/</guid>
      <description>Papers of the War Department View the project here.
Overview The War Department office was established in 1790. It burned in 1800.
For decades historians believed that its files, and the window they provide into the early federal government, had been lost forever. This collection unites copies of the lost files in a digital archive that reconstitutes this invaluable historical resource. Our community of transcribers are working to create full text transcriptions of every possible document in the collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/newberry-transcribe/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview Unlock the past! Transcribe letters and diaries to help with historical research.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan White Letters</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/ryan-white-letters/</guid>
      <description>Ryan White Letters View the project here.
Overview The Ryan White Letters Collection consists of almost 6000 letters and cards written to Ryan White and his family during the last years of his life. After being diagnosed with HIV/AIDS at the age of 13, Ryan’s legal fight to attend school despite his disease brought him to the forefront of public discussion about AIDS and its victims in the late 1980s. Thousands of letters came to Ryan from all over the world, many of them from children and teens who had seen his story in the media and wanted Ryan to know he was loved and supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scarlets and Blues</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/scarlets-and-blues/</guid>
      <description>Scarlets and Blues View the project here.
Overview Travel back in time and take a behind-the-scenes look at the stories, lives and interactions of WWI-era staff and soldiers at the Royal Hospital Chelsea, one of London’s most iconic and longstanding institutions.
Named for the colours of the coats worn by England’s famous Chelsea Pensioners, the Scarlets and Blues project takes a behind-the-scenes look at the Royal Hospital Chelsea using records from The National Archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smithsonian Institute: Transcribing Audio Collections</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-audio-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-audio-collections/</guid>
      <description>Smithsonian Institute: Transcribing Audio Collections View the project here.
Overview The Smithsonian holds over 150,000 audio recordings - in various formats, and dating from the late 19th century to the present - in its many museums, archives, and libraries. Transcription of these collections will increase accessibility, unlock hidden content, and preserve historical audio assets for future generations.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smithsonian National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/smithsonian-archives/</guid>
      <description>Smithsonian National Archives View the project here.
Overview Become a Smithsonian Digital Volunteer and help us make historical documents and biodiversity data more accessible.
Join 55,775 &amp;ldquo;volunpeers&amp;rdquo; to add more to the total 912,645 pages of field notes, diaries, ledgers, logbooks, currency proof sheets, photo albums, manuscripts, biodiversity specimens labels, and historic audio recordings, that have been collaboratively transcribed and reviewed since June 2013.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford University Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stanford-university-archives/</guid>
      <description>Stanford University Archives View the project here.
Overview The Stanford University Archives is the official repository for records of Stanford University and serves as its institutional memory. The Archives collects, preserves, administers, and promotes access to materials in any format that document the history of Stanford, including its founders, administration, faculty, students, and alumni/ae. Our holdings include more than 30,000 linear feet of material and 20+ TB of electronic records within 2,200+ collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Notes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</guid>
      <description>Star Notes View the project here.
Overview Help us transcribe the groundbreaking work of early women astronomers!
We have digitized the notebooks of the Harvard Computers and early Harvard astronomers including Williamina Fleming, Annie Jump Cannon, Henrietta Swan Leavitt, and many others. The goal of Star Notes is to link these notebooks back to their original source material: 500,000 glass plate photographs representing the first ever picture of the visible universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of St James&#39;s Burial Ground</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/stories-of-st-james/</guid>
      <description>Stories of St James&amp;rsquo;s Burial Ground View the project here.
Overview High-Speed Rail 2 (HS2) is a major infrastructure project connecting cities across the UK with faster train lines and services. In London, contractors Costain Skanska Joint Venture (CSJV) are managing work near Euston Station where construction is taking place on the site of St James’s Burial Ground, a major 18th-19th century cemetery site. Ahead of this work over 100 archaeologists and specialists from MOLA Headland Infrastructure were brought in to excavate and record over 40,000 burials, the largest archaeological excavation of its kind ever undertaken in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/berkeley-historical-plaque/</guid>
      <description>The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project View the project here.
Overview The Berkeley Historical Plaque Project belongs to all of us who live in Berkeley. We invite you to participate by making a contribution, e-mailing us current or historical photos that will add to this website, or writing and sending us your own e-Plaque texts with photos.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/transcribe-virginia/</guid>
      <description>Transcribe View the project here.
Overview Transcribe is the Library of Virginia’s collaborative online workspace where the public can participate in enhancing access to many of our amazing collections documenting over 400 years of Virginia history, people, and culture. This is the perfect opportunity for participants to dig deep into our collections and transcribe historical materials from five to ten active projects at a time. From peace to wartime, court records to letters home, and conspiracies to political statements, there will be something for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States National Archives</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/national-archives/</guid>
      <description>United States National Archives View the project here.
Overview Welcome to our Citizen Archivist program. You can contribute to the National Archives Catalog by tagging, transcribing and adding comments to our records, making them more accessible and searchable. Join us! Every contribution you make helps unlock history.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices Through Time: The Story of Care</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/voices-through-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/voices-through-time/</guid>
      <description>Voices Through Time: The Story of Care View the project here.
Overview Help us transcribe the records of Coram, the UK’s first children’s charity, to tell the story of care from where it began.
Our archive contains thousands of handwritten records, going back to the 1700s, which contain the stories of children who were cared for at the Foundling Hospital.
With your help transcribing these records, we can make them available online for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
