<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zoology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/zoology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zoology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/zoology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ano-nuevo/</guid>
      <description>Año Nuevo Island - Animal Count View the project here.
Overview Every year, thousands of seals and sea lions haul out on Año Nuevo Island to give birth, molt, and rest. The secluded shores of the island make a perfect spot for northern elephant seal and California sea lion mothers to give birth and nurse their pups. Researchers at the University of California, Santa Cruz are interested in tracking the number of animals that haul out onto the island&amp;rsquo;s beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/chesapeake-bay-otter-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance View the project here.
Overview The Chesapeake Bay Otter Alliance is a group of researchers from across the Smithsonian and local universities, with a goal to study and educate the public about North American River Otters in the Chesapeake Bay. We need your help to figure out where these otters are in the Chesapeake Bay!
Very little to no research has been done regarding the numbers, health, and populations of otters in the Chesapeake Bay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimp and See</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/chimp-and-see/</guid>
      <description>Chimp and See View the project here.
Overview Studies of human evolution often focus on the fossils and artifacts left by our early ancestors. However, we can also make inferences about human origins by studying our closest living relatives: chimpanzees, the great apes that live across equatorial Africa. Because humans and chimps are so closely related, patterns in chimpanzee behavior may tell us quite a bit about how the earliest hominids lived and evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eMammal</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/emammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/emammal/</guid>
      <description>eMammal View the project here.
Overview eMammal is a data management system and archive for camera trap research projects. This cyber-tool is designed to not only be useful to scientists, but also to the citizen scientists who aid scientists in photo collection. Camera trappers use our software to look at pictures, identify animals and upload them for review and archive at the Smithsonian. These data then help address important conservation-related questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frog Find</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frog-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frog-find/</guid>
      <description>Frog Find View the project here.
Overview Help us find threatened frogs in NSW National Parks. Understanding where they live helps us improve their chance of survival in the future.
Frogs need your help! Following bushfires, floods and a host of other threats including water pollution and disease, our frogs really have their back against the wall.
Frog Find uses frog sounds recorded from streams, ponds and wetlands to work out who is calling where.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FrogSong</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frogsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/frogsong/</guid>
      <description>FrogSong View the project here.
Overview With your help, researchers at James Cook University and Monash University aim to develop automated techniques to identify frog calls in very long audio recordings. This will allow us to understand the environmental drivers of frog chorusing, detect changes in frog communities through time, determine how species partition the acoustic space, and much more!
This project contains audio recordings collected by the Australian Acoustic Observatory at sites around Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FrogWatch USA</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/frogwatch-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/frogwatch-usa/</guid>
      <description>FrogWatch USA View the project here.
Overview FrogWatch USA™ is a citizen science program of the Association of Zoos and Aquariums that invites individuals and families to learn about the wetlands in their communities and help conserve amphibians by reporting data on the calls of local frogs and toads.
Volunteers are trained to collect information about the calls from frogs and toads during the monitoring season of February through August.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/inaturalist/</guid>
      <description>iNaturalist View the project here.
Overview One of the world’s most popular nature apps, iNaturalist helps you identify the plants and animals around you. Get connected with a community of over a million scientists and naturalists who can help you learn more about nature! What’s more, by recording and sharing your observations, you’ll create research quality data for scientists working to better understand and protect nature. iNaturalist is a joint initiative by the California Academy of Sciences and the National Geographic Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Wild</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/instant-wild/</guid>
      <description>Instant Wild View the project here.
Overview ZSL’s Instant Wild empowers you to take part in vital conservation work, bringing you LIVE images and videos from amazing locations all around the world. By identifying the animals in each image, you are contributing to conservation and making a positive impact on the future for wildlife.
Available both as a smartphone app and online at instantwild.zsl.org, Instant Wild mobilises people power to scale up important animal monitoring work, which helps scientists to protect wildlife and secure a richer biodiversity for all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s Notebook</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/natures-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook View the project here.
Overview Nature&amp;rsquo;s Notebook gathers information on plant and animal phenology across the U.S. to be used for decision-making on local, national and global scales to ensure the continued vitality of our environment.
Scientists alone cannot collect enough data: They need your help. Join more than 15,000 other naturalists across the nation in taking the pulse of our planet. You&amp;rsquo;ll use scientifically-vetted observation guidelines, developed for over 1000 species, to ensure data are useful to researchers and decision-makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offal Wildlife Watching</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/offal-ww/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/offal-ww/</guid>
      <description>Offal Wildlife Watching View the project here.
Overview Who Eats your Guts? Help us better understand scavenging of deer gut piles provided by hunters across Minnesota. IMPORTANT: IMAGES SHOW ANIMALS FEEDING ON THE REMAINS OF DEER
The purpose of this research is to better understand what and when species use deer gut piles provided by hunters across Minnesota. Minnesota offers a unique opportunity to look at this across four different biomes and a major metropolitan area, different hunting methods (rifle, archery, and shotgun), and different scavenger assemblages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project RattleCam</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rattlecam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-rattlecam/</guid>
      <description>Project RattleCam View the project here.
Overview This project was conceived in 2020 when Dr. Scott Boback of Dickinson College and Dr. Emily Taylor of the California Polytechnic State University decided to design a Zooniverse project for help analyzing game camera images they&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting from prairie rattlesnake rookeries in a remote area of Colorado. Rattlesnake rookeries are areas where females come together to give birth and care for their young.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Indy Wildlife Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/indy-wildlife-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/indy-wildlife-watch/</guid>
      <description>The Indy Wildlife Watch: An Initiative of the CUES View the project here.
Overview Join the Center for Urban Ecology and Sustainability (CUES) at Butler University and the Indianapolis Zoo by tagging animals in our photos!
Urbanization describes a human population shift from rural areas to cities, which usually results in the physical growth of urban areas.
As the global population of humans continues to grow, so will the rate of urbanization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wesselman-woods/</guid>
      <description>Wesselman Woods Wildlife Watch View the project here.
Overview Want an exclusive view of the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S? Take a closer look at urban wildlife activity through this camera trap project by joining our citizen science team and helping us tag pictures and contribute to urban ecology theory!
Wesselman Woods is home to the largest urban old-growth forest in the U.S with over 200 acres of land, making this camera trap project like none other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Mont-Blanc</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wild-mont-blanc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wild-mont-blanc/</guid>
      <description>Wild Mont-Blanc View the project here.
Overview Help us explore the secret life of the Mont-Blanc massif! Our cameras track the distribution, behavior and seasonal rhythm of animals year after year.
Forty camera traps installed across France’s Mont-Blanc massif are giving us a powerful new window into the dynamics of alpine wildlife species. The Research Center for Alpine Ecosystems (CREA Mont-Blanc) needs your help to identify all the different animals caught in hundreds of thousands of camera trap images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildlife of Los Angeles</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildlife-of-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildlife-of-la/</guid>
      <description>Wildlife of Los Angeles View the project here.
Overview In the United States greater than 80% of the human population occurs in cities, yet we know very little about the wildlife in these areas. Much work needs to be done to understand how increases in urbanized areas impact wildlife species and their ability to survive around us. Urbanization poses many threats to wildlife such as loss of habitat, fragmentation of habitat, roads and traffic, poisons and toxins, people, and our pets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/wildwatch-burrowing-owl/</guid>
      <description>Wildwatch Burrowing Owl View the project here.
Overview The western burrowing owl needs our help. Unusual among owl species, this pint-sized raptor lives in elaborate underground burrows. These owls cannot dig their own burrows, and instead “reuse” excavated dens dug by ground squirrels and other fossorial (burrowing) animals. With its penchant for open, native grasslands, the burrowing owl has been on a collision course with humans throughout much of Southern California.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
