<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astrophysics on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/astrophysics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astrophysics on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/astrophysics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Asteroids</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/active-asteroids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/active-asteroids/</guid>
      <description>Active Asteroids View the project here.
Overview Active Asteroids &amp;ndash; asteroids with comet-like activity such as tails &amp;ndash; are poorly understood in part because so few of these objects have been found. At the time of this project launch, fewer than 30 active asteroids have been found since 1949. Finding more active asteroids will enable scientists to study these enigmatic objects as a population. The implications for science and engineering are far-reaching, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI4Mars</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ai4mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/ai4mars/</guid>
      <description>AI4Mars View the project here.
Overview We need YOUR help to make future Mars rovers safer!
By participating in this project, you will help improve the rovers’ ability to identify different, sometimes dangerous terrain - an essential skill for autonomous exploration!
You’ll be using your superior cognitive and artistic abilities to label images from the Curiosity Rover, collectively creating the first open-source navigation-classification dataset of the Red Planet. It will be used - like the cityscapes dataset - by teams to train rovers to understand Martian environments, laying the way for future missions to unlock the secrets of our nearest neighbor!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurorasaurus</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/aurorasaurus/</guid>
      <description>Aurorasaurus View the project here.
Overview Aurorasaurus is the first and only citizen science initiative that tracks auroras around the world via reports on our website and social media. All aurora-related tweets and reports are placed on the Aurorasaurus.org map. We then ask people to log in and verify the tweets or reports. Each verified report serves as a valuable data point for scientists to analyze and incorporate into space weather models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backyard Worlds: Planet 9</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/backyard-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/backyard-worlds/</guid>
      <description>Backyard Worlds: Planet 9 View the project here.
Overview Is there a large planet at the fringes of our solar system awaiting discovery, a world astronomers call Planet Nine? We’re looking for this planet and for new brown dwarfs in the backyard of the solar system using data from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer (WISE) mission. But we need your help!
Finding these dim objects requires combing through the images by eye to distinguish moving celestial bodies from ghosts and other artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bursts from Space</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/bursts-from-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/bursts-from-space/</guid>
      <description>Bursts from Space View the project here.
Overview Fast Radio Bursts are massive bursts of energy we see from across half the universe. We call them Fast Radio Bursts because that&amp;rsquo;s what we see - a brief millisecond &amp;lsquo;burst&amp;rsquo; of energy in radio waves.
What are they? We don&amp;rsquo;t know! But every burst we find tells us a little more about what&amp;rsquo;s happening. We need to find these bursts!
Sounds easy right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological jellyfish</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmological-jellyfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/cosmological-jellyfish/</guid>
      <description>Cosmological jellyfish View the project here.
Overview We are a group of researchers at the Max Planck Institute of Astronomy using simulations of the Universe to study the various ways in which galaxies in the Universe evolve, both through their own internal processes, and under the influence of their environment.
Galaxies in the Universe can come in many forms and shapes.
Some of them can show very asymmetric distributions, with long tails of material that depart from their main body made of stars and cosmic gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Energy Explorers</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dark-energy-explorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/dark-energy-explorers/</guid>
      <description>Dark Energy Explorers View the project here.
Overview The Hobby-Eberly Dark Energy Experiment (HETDEX) is designed to find over one million galaxies that are 9 billion to 11 billion light-years away, yielding the largest map of the universe ever produced. The map will allow HETDEX astronomers to measure how fast the universe was expanding at different times in its history. Changes in the expansion rate will reveal the role of dark energy at different epochs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disk Detective</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/disk-detective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/disk-detective/</guid>
      <description>Disk Detective View the project here.
Overview NASA&amp;rsquo;s WISE mission is surveying the whole sky at infrared wavelengths. Here at Disk Detective, you&amp;rsquo;ll examine data from WISE and other surveys to search for dusty debris disks similar to our asteroid belt, and gas-rich primordial disks, the birthplaces of planets.
Location: Online</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einstein@Home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/einstein-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/einstein-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Einstein@Home View the project here.
Overview Einstein@Home is a World Year of Physics 2005 and an International Year of Astronomy 2009 project. It is supported by the American Physical Society (APS), the US National Science Foundation (NSF), the Max Planck Society (MPG), and a number of international organizations.
Einstein@Home uses your computer&amp;rsquo;s idle time to search for weak astrophysical signals from spinning neutron stars (often called pulsars) using data from the LIGO gravitational-wave detectors, the Arecibo radio telescope, and the Fermi gamma-ray satellite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireballs in the Sky</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/fireballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/fireballs/</guid>
      <description>Fireballs in the Sky View the project here.
Overview Fireballs in the Sky is an innovative citizen science program that connects the public with the research of the Desert Fireball Network.
Meteorites have the potential to show us how the Solar System formed and evolved, coming from the very first bodies to be created. They act as a snapshot in time, holding the minerals that came from their parent bodies and are unchanged as they hurtle towards Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globe at Night</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-at-night/</guid>
      <description>Globe at Night View the project here.
Overview Globe at Night is an international citizen-science campaign to raise public awareness of the impact of light pollution by inviting citizen-scientists to measure &amp;amp; submit their night sky brightness observations. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get involved - all you need is computer or smart phone &amp;amp; follow these 6 Simple Steps!
The November 2021 campaign is using the Constellation Perseus. Check out the dates and constellations for our other campaigns during all 12 months of 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MilkyWay@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/milkyway-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/milkyway-at-home/</guid>
      <description>MilkyWay@home View the project here.
Overview Milkyway@Home uses the BOINC platform to harness volunteered computing resources, creating a highly accurate three dimensional model of the Milky Way galaxy using data gathered by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. This project enables research in both astroinformatics and computer science.
In computer science, the project is investigating different optimization methods which are resilient to the fault-prone, heterogeneous and asynchronous nature of Internet computing; such as evolutionary and genetic algorithms, as well as asynchronous newton methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Hunters NGTS</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-ngts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-ngts/</guid>
      <description>Planet Hunters NGTS View the project here.
Overview The Next-Generation Transit Survey have been searching for transiting exoplanets around the brightest stars in the sky. We need your help sifting through the observations flagged by the computers to search for hidden worlds that might have been missed in the NGTS team&amp;rsquo;s review. Most of the planets in the dataset have likely been found already, but you just might be the first to find a new exoplanet not known before!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Hunters TESS</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-tess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-hunters-tess/</guid>
      <description>Planet Hunters TESS View the project here.
Overview The recently launched Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) is providing us with a huge amount of data that lets us look for planets outside of our own Solar System, including planets that could support life. With your help, we are going to find planets that will help us understand how these extrasolar systems form and evolve over time. The results may even bring us closer to answering the question that we all want to answer: Are we alone in the Universe?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Patrol</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-patrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/planet-patrol/</guid>
      <description>Planet Patrol View the project here.
Overview NASA’s Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) mission will take pictures of more than a million stars to search for planets orbiting them, called &amp;ldquo;transiting exoplanets&amp;rdquo;. We expect this mission will see thousands of these transiting exoplanets when they pass in front of nearby stars and periodically block some of the starlight.
But sometimes when a star dims like that, it&amp;rsquo;s not because of a planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Four</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</guid>
      <description>Project Four View the project here.
Overview Welcome to Planet Four, a citizen science project designed to help planetary scientists identify and measure features on the surface of Mars&amp;hellip; the likes of which don’t exist on Earth. All of the images on this site depict the south polar region, where dark seasonal fans and blotches appear during the Spring. By mapping these features in images from the HiRISE camera, the highest resolution camera ever sent to a planet, we can explore the Martian climate and how it changes over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/galaxy-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/galaxy-zoo/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here (for desktop users) and its mobile version (for Android and iPhone) here.
Overview To understand how galaxies formed we need your help to classify them according to their shapes. If you&amp;rsquo;re quick, you may even be the first person to see the galaxies you&amp;rsquo;re asked to classify.
Welcome to Galaxy Zoo&amp;rsquo;s latest incarnation. For more than a decade, we&amp;rsquo;ve asked volunteers to help us explore galaxies near and far, sampling a fraction of the roughly one hundred billion that are scattered throughout the observable Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT NAME</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/junocam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/junocam/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT NAME View the project here.
Overview We’re calling all amateur astronomers to upload their telescopic images and data of Jupiter. These uploads are critical for providing context for new JunoCam images and will help NASA successfully plan the future of the mission.
If you&amp;rsquo;re a veteran astrophotographer or if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting started with your first telescope, we highly recommend you read our Submission Guidelines before submitting data. In the PDF you&amp;rsquo;ll find information about the best capture and process workflows as well as links to free software and tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio Galaxy Zoo: LOFAR</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-galaxy-zoo-lofar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-galaxy-zoo-lofar/</guid>
      <description>Radio Galaxy Zoo: LOFAR View the project here.
Overview Help astronomers locate and identify supermassive black holes and starforming galaxies!
The LOFAR project offers us an unprecedented view of what our skies look like at radio wavelengths. Never before have we been able to map such a large part of the radio sky at such high sensitivity. This allows scientists all over the world to answer many questions on the evolution of galaxies and the supermassive black holes that they harbour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio JOVE</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-jove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/radio-jove/</guid>
      <description>Radio JOVE View the project here.
Overview Radio JOVE students and amateur scientists from around the world observe and analyze natural radio emissions of Jupiter, the Sun, and our galaxy building their own radio telescope from an easy to build kit or using remote radio telescopes through the Internet.
 Build and use your own Decametric Radio Telescope Share your observations with other project members Teachers, See Our Lesson Ideas and other Educational Materials  There is much more to astronomy than what can be learned by peering at the skies through an optical telescope!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Notes</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/star-notes/</guid>
      <description>Star Notes View the project here.
Overview Help us transcribe the groundbreaking work of early women astronomers!
We have digitized the notebooks of the Harvard Computers and early Harvard astronomers including Williamina Fleming, Annie Jump Cannon, Henrietta Swan Leavitt, and many others. The goal of Star Notes is to link these notebooks back to their original source material: 500,000 glass plate photographs representing the first ever picture of the visible universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardust@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/stardust-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/stardust-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Stardust@home View the project here.
Overview On January 15, 2006, the Stardust spacecraft’s sample return capsule parachuted gently onto the Utah desert. Nestled within the capsule were precious particles collected during Stardust’s dramatic encounter with comet Wild 2 in January of 2004; and something else, even rarer and no less precious: tiny particles of interstellar dust that originated in distant stars, light-years away. They are the first such contemporary interstellar dust particles ever collected in space and returned to Earth for study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardust@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/stardust-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/stardust-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Stardust@home View the project here.
Overview The interstellar dust particles returned to Earth by the Stardust mission are the first such pristine dust particles ever collected in space, and scientists are eager to “get their hands” on them. We estimate that Stardust collected less than 100 interstellar dust particles. They are tiny-only about a micron (a millionth of a meter) in size! These miniscule particles were captured in an aerogel collector about 1,000 square centimeters in size, and in about 150 square centimeters of aluminum metal foils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Target NEOs!</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/target-neo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/target-neo/</guid>
      <description>Target NEOs! View the project here.
Overview Target NEOs!* is an exciting opportunity for amateur astronomers to participate in a long-term citizen science project that will contribute to basic scientific understanding of near-Earth objects (NEOs). Observers collect data about asteroids on a selected list and submit images and corresponding reports. These observations support spacecraft missions in progress and aid future mission designers and scientists. Citizen scientists’ astrometry and photometry data will enable scientists to test theoretical models about these objects to refine orbits and taxonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universe@home</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/universe-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/universe-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Universe@home View the project here.
Overview Universe@home project&amp;rsquo;s two main goals are:
 to provide scientist with a necessary computational power and to provide the way of involvement for anyone equipped with a computer and willing to take part in the research  We live in times which are marked by the fastest scientific development in the history. Our knowledge grows faster than ever before. We explore the structures of the Universe, nuclei of stars and evolution of galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zwicky Chemical Factory</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/zwicky-chemical-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/zwicky-chemical-factory/</guid>
      <description>Zwicky Chemical Factory View the project here.
Overview Every year astronomers discover thousands of new supernovae (exploding stars). Once these spectacular events are found, we use spectroscopy to understand the chemical elements in the explosion and what type of star exploded. Help us classify these explosions!
The elements created by an individual supernova (SN) differ depending on the type of SN (for example, oxygen and sodium are primarily created when massive stars explode, whereas iron is primarily created when white dwarf stars explode).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
