<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meteorology on Project Delve</title>
    <link>http://projectdelve.com/tags/meteorology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meteorology on Project Delve</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://projectdelve.com/tags/meteorology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Africa Rainfall Project</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/africa-rainfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/africa-rainfall/</guid>
      <description>Africa Rainfall Project View the project here.
Overview In sub-Saharan Africa, 95 percent of agriculture depends on rainfall, which makes accurate weather forecasts absolutely crucial. However, because rainfall in this area is often localized—sometimes almost at the level of one farm—it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to forecast accurately with satellite data, which show larger weather patterns.
Through the Africa Rainfall Project, researchers at Delft University of Technology will create high-resolution computer simulations of localized rainstorms in sub-Saharan Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>climateprediction.net</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/computational/climateprediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/computational/climateprediction/</guid>
      <description>climateprediction.net View the project here.
Overview Climateprediction.net is a volunteer computing climate modeling project.
We run climate models on people’s home computers to help answer questions about how climate change is affecting our world, now and in the future. Evidence of how our climate is changing is vital to encourage investment in reducing greenhouse gas emissions, as well as coping with inevitable change.
You can help discover how the climate could look by running our free software on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cocorahs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/cocorahs/</guid>
      <description>Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network View the project here.
Overview CoCoRaHS is an acronym for the Community Collaborative Rain, Hail and Snow Network. CoCoRaHS is a unique, non-profit, community-based network of volunteers of all ages and backgrounds working together to measure and map precipitation (rain, hail and snow). By using low-cost measurement tools, stressing training and education, and utilizing an interactive Web-site, our aim is to provide the highest quality data for natural resource, education and research applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Snow Observations</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/community-snow-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/community-snow-observations/</guid>
      <description>Community Snow Observations (CSO) View the project here.
Overview CSO is a citizen science campaign to measure snow. Make your backcountry travels count! We need your help measuring snow depths in mountain places too vast for researchers to monitor.
Your observations help us predict snow conditions and improve safety for mountain travelers.
This project aims to improve our understanding of snow depth variability in mountainous regions. We need community-based observers, including backcountry professionals and recreationists, to help gather snow observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLOBE Observer</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/scienceout/globe-observer/</guid>
      <description>GLOBE Observer View the project here.
Overview When you download the GLOBE Observer app, you join the community of The GLOBE Program - citizen scientists, students, and teachers in 120+ countries around the world contributing to Earth system science research.
Your observations:
 Help monitor the conditions of clouds, water (especially as a habitat for mosquitoes), plants (trees and other land cover), and see change over time. Can be used to help interpret NASA and other satellite data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/m-a-e-terrae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/m-a-e-terrae/</guid>
      <description>Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae View the project here.
Overview Meteororum ad Extremum Terrae (MET - Meteorology of the End of the World) aims to recover weather and oceanic data record in Argentina since at least the beginning of the XIXth Century. The first currently known records date back to 1801. Other than the Oficina Meteorológica Argentina, later Servicio Meteorológico Nacional, many public and private organizations have registered weather data. Argentine Navy ships, lighthouses, railway stations, &amp;ldquo;estancias&amp;rdquo; are among many data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Weather - WW2</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/historical/old-weather-ww2/</guid>
      <description>Old Weather - WW2 View the project here.
Overview Help recover hidden weather data collected by the U.S. Navy during World War II!
The purpose of this project is to recover hidden marine weather data recorded in U.S. Navy ships&#39; logbooks during World War II. Like all Old Weather projects, these data will be used to drive sophisticated computer models that help us understand weather and climate in extraordinary detail. But there is another goal that is just as vital - to uncover the source of a mysterious distortion in the Navy temperature data collected during the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Four</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/project-four/</guid>
      <description>Project Four View the project here.
Overview Welcome to Planet Four, a citizen science project designed to help planetary scientists identify and measure features on the surface of Mars&amp;hellip; the likes of which don’t exist on Earth. All of the images on this site depict the south polar region, where dark seasonal fans and blotches appear during the Spring. By mapping these features in images from the HiRISE camera, the highest resolution camera ever sent to a planet, we can explore the Martian climate and how it changes over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Rescue At Sea</title>
      <link>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/weather-rescue-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://projectdelve.com/sciencein/weather-rescue-at-sea/</guid>
      <description>Weather Rescue At Sea View the project here.
Overview The aim of the Weather Rescue At Sea project is to construct and extended the global surface temperature record back to the 1780s, based on the air temperature observations recorded across the planet.
This will be achieved by crowd-sourcing the recovery (or data rescue) of the weather observations from historical ship logbooks, station records, weather journals and other sources, to produce a longer, and more consistent dataset of global surface temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
